<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>BennuGD</systemName>
    <systemDescription>BennuGD is a high-level, open-source game development suite that focuses on modularity and portability, making it an excellent choice for cross-platform game development.
    
Although officially supported only on Windows, Linux, and GP2X Wiz, BennuGD can run on several other platforms, including *BSD, MacOS X, and other consoles such as the Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X, and the classic Xbox.

This versatility makes coding in BennuGD enjoyable, as the game can be played on both your computer and your console!</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>SplinterGU</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>2007</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-engine}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD هي مجموعة تطوير ألعاب مفتوحة المصدر عالية المستوى تركز على المعيارية والقابلية للنقل، مما يجعلها خيارًا ممتازًا لتطوير الألعاب متعددة المنصات.

على الرغم من أنها مدعومة رسميًا فقط على Windows و Linux و GP2X Wiz، يمكن لـ BennuGD أن تعمل على عدة منصات أخرى، بما في ذلك *BSD و MacOS X وأنظمة أساسية أخرى مثل Wii و Dingoo A320 و GP2X و Xbox الكلاسيكية.

هذا التنوع يجعل البرمجة في BennuGD ممتعة، لأنه يمكن لعب اللعبة على كل من جهاز الكمبيوتر الخاص بك وجهازك الطرفي!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD je visokostupnjev, open-source software za razvoj igara koji se fokusira na modularnost i portabilnost, čineći ga odličnom opcijom za razvoj igara na više platformi.

Iako je službeno podržan samo na Windows, Linux i GP2X Wiz, BennuGD može raditi na nekoliko drugih platformi, uključujući *BSD, MacOS X i druge konzole poput Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X i klasičnog Xbox-a.

Ova svestranost čini programiranje u BennuGD-u uživanjem, jer igra može biti odigrana na vašem računalu i vašoj konzoli!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD és un conjunt de desenvolupament de jocs de codi obert d'alt nivell que se centra en la modularitat i la portabilitat, la qual cosa la fa una opció excel·lent per al desenvolupament de jocs multiplataforma.

Although officially supported only on Windows, Linux, and GP2X Wiz, BennuGD can run on several other platforms, including *BSD, MacOS X, and other consoles such as the Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X, and the classic Xbox.

Aquest gama de suport fa que la programació en BennuGD sigui divertida, ja que el joc es pot jugar tant a l'ordinador com a la consola!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD ist eine Open-Source-Spiele-Entwicklungssuite auf hoher Ebene, die sich auf Modularität und Portabilität konzentriert und eine hervorragende Wahl für die plattformübergreifende Spieleentwicklung darstellt.

Obwohl offiziell nur unter Windows, Linux und GP2X Wiz unterstützt, kann BennuGD auf mehreren anderen Plattformen ausgeführt werden, darunter *BSD, MacOS X und andere Konsolen wie Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X und das klassische Xbox.

Diese Vielseitigkeit macht die Programmierung in BennuGD angenehm, da das Spiel sowohl auf Ihrem Computer als auch auf Ihrer Konsole gespielt werden kann!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD es un conjunto de desarrollo de juegos de código abierto de alto nivel que se enfoca en la modularidad y la portabilidad, lo que la convierte en una opción excelente para el desarrollo de juegos multiplataforma.

Aunque oficialmente solo se admite en Windows, Linux y GP2X Wiz, BennuGD puede ejecutarse en varias otras plataformas, incluidas *BSD, MacOS X y otras consolas como Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X y el Xbox clásico.

¡Esta versatilidad hace que la codificación en BennuGD sea agradable, ya que el juego se puede jugar tanto en su computadora como en su consola!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD est une suite de développement de jeux open-source de haut niveau qui se concentre sur la modularité et la portabilité, ce qui en fait un excellent choix pour le développement de jeux multiplateformes.

Bien qu'officiellement pris en charge uniquement sur Windows, Linux et GP2X Wiz, BennuGD peut s'exécuter sur plusieurs autres plates-formes, notamment *BSD, MacOS X et d'autres consoles telles que la Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X et le Xbox classique.

Cette polyvalence rend la programmation dans BennuGD agréable, car le jeu peut être joué à la fois sur votre ordinateur et sur votre console!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD je visokostupnjev, open-source software za razvoj igara koji se fokusira na modularnost i portabilnost, čineći ga odličnom opcijom za razvoj igara na više platformi.

Iako je službeno podržan samo na Windows, Linux i GP2X Wiz, BennuGD može raditi na nekoliko drugih platformi, uključujući *BSD, MacOS X i druge konzole poput Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X i klasičnog Xbox-a.

Ova svestranost čini programiranje u BennuGD-u uživanjem, jer igra može biti odigrana na vašem računalu i vašoj konzoli!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD è una suite di sviluppo di giochi open-source di alto livello che si concentra sulla modularità e sulla portabilità, rendendola una scelta eccellente per lo sviluppo di giochi multipiattaforma.

Although officially supported only on Windows, Linux, and GP2X Wiz, BennuGD can run on several other platforms, including *BSD, MacOS X, and other consoles such as the Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X, and the classic Xbox.

Questa versatilità rende la programmazione in BennuGD piacevole, poiché il gioco può essere giocato sia sul tuo computer che sulla tua console!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>BennuGDは、モジュール性とポータビリティに焦点を当てた高レベルのオープンソースゲーム開発スイートであり、クロスプラットフォームゲーム開発に最適です。

Windows、Linux、GP2X Wizでのみ公式にサポートされていますが、BennuGDは*BSD、MacOS X、およびWii、Dingoo A320、GP2X、クラシックXboxなどの他のいくつかのプラットフォームで実行できます。

この汎用性により、BennuGDでのコーディングが楽しくなります。ゲームはコンピューターとコンソールの両方でプレイできるからです!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD는 모듈성 및 이식성에 중점을 두는 고수준의 오픈소스 게임 개발 제품군으로, 크로스 플랫폼 게임 개발에 탁월한 선택입니다.

Windows, Linux 및 GP2X Wiz에서만 공식적으로 지원되지만 BennuGD는 *BSD, MacOS X 및 Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X 및 클래식 Xbox와 같은 기타 여러 플랫폼에서 실행할 수 있습니다.

이러한 다양성은 게임을 컴퓨터와 콘솔 모두에서 플레이할 수 있기 때문에 BennuGD에서의 코딩을 즐겁게 만듭니다!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD is een open-source game-development suite op hoog niveau die zich richt op modulariteit en draagbaarheid, waardoor het een uitstekende keuze is voor platformonafhankelijke spelontwikkeling.

Although officially supported only on Windows, Linux, and GP2X Wiz, BennuGD can run on several other platforms, including *BSD, MacOS X, and other consoles such as the Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X, and the classic Xbox.

Deze veelzijdigheid maakt programmeren in BennuGD aangenaam, omdat het spel zowel op uw computer als op uw console kan worden gespeeld!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD to oparta na open-source, wysokopoziomowa pakiet do tworzenia gier, który skupia się na modularności i przenośności, co czyni ją doskonałym wyborem do międzyplatformowego tworzenia gier.

Chociaż oficjalnie obsługiwane jest tylko na Windows, Linux i GP2X Wiz, BennuGD może działać na kilku innych platformach, w tym *BSD, MacOS X i inne konsole, takie jak Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X i klasyczny Xbox.

Ta wszechstronność sprawia, że kodowanie w BennuGD jest przyjemne, ponieważ gra może być grana zarówno na Twoim komputerze, jak i na Twojej konsoli!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD é um pacote de desenvolvimento de jogos de código aberto de alto nível que se concentra na modularidade e portabilidade, tornando-o uma excelente opção para desenvolvimento de jogos multiplataforma.

Embora oficialmente suportado apenas no Windows, Linux e GP2X Wiz, BennuGD pode ser executado em várias outras plataformas, incluindo *BSD, MacOS X e outros consoles, como Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X e o Xbox clássico.

Esta versatilidade torna a codificação no BennuGD agradável, pois o jogo pode ser jogado tanto em seu computador quanto em seu console!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD este o suite de dezvoltare jocuri open-source de nivel înalt care se concentrează pe modularitate și portabilitate, făcând-o o alegere excelentă pentru dezvoltarea jocurilor multiplatformă.

Deși este suportat oficial numai pe Windows, Linux și GP2X Wiz, BennuGD poate rula pe mai multe alte platforme, inclusiv *BSD, MacOS X și alte console cum ar fi Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X și clasicul Xbox.

Această versatilitate face ca programarea în BennuGD să fie plăcută, deoarece jocul poate fi jucat atât pe computerul tău cât și pe consola ta!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD — это высокоуровневый пакет разработки игр с открытым исходным кодом, ориентированный на модульность и портативность, что делает его отличным выбором для кроссплатформенной разработки игр.

Хотя официально поддерживается только в Windows, Linux и GP2X Wiz, BennuGD может работать на нескольких других платформах, включая *BSD, MacOS X и другие консоли, такие как Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X и классический Xbox.

Эта универсальность делает программирование в BennuGD приятным, так как игра может быть запущена как на вашем компьютере, так и на вашей консоли!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD је високостепена софтвериска пакета за развој игара отворене изворе која се фокусира на модуларност и портабилност, чинећи га одличном опцијом за развој игара на више платформи.

Мада је званично подржана само на Windows, Linux и GP2X Wiz, BennuGD може радити на неколико других платформи, укључујући *BSD, MacOS X и другим конзолама као што су Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X и класична Xbox.

Ова свестраност чини програмирање у BennuGD-у уживањем, јер се игра може играти и на вашем рачунару и на вашој конзоли!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD är en open-source-spelsutvekling på högt nivå som fokuserar på modularitet och portabilitet, vilket gör det ett utmärkt val för plattformsoberoende spelutveckling.

Although officially supported only on Windows, Linux, and GP2X Wiz, BennuGD can run on several other platforms, including *BSD, MacOS X, and other consoles such as the Wii, Dingoo A320, GP2X, and the classic Xbox.

Denna mångsidighet gör programmering i BennuGD roligt, eftersom spelet kan spelas på både din dator och din konsol!</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>BennuGD是一个高级的开源游戏开发套件，专注于模块化和可移植性，使其成为跨平台游戏开发的绝佳选择。

虽然官方仅在Windows、Linux和GP2X Wiz上支持，但BennuGD可以在多个其他平台上运行，包括*BSD、MacOS X和其他游戏机，如Wii、Dingoo A320、GP2X和经典Xbox。

这种多功能性使BennuGD中的编码令人愉悦，因为游戏可以在您的计算机和游戏机上玩！</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
