<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Chihiro</systemName>
    <systemDescription>The Chihiro is an arcade system produced by Sega and Microsoft based on the Xbox home video game console. It was the second such partnership, with Sega also siding with Namco and Nintendo with the Nintendo GameCube-powered Triforce system.

The Chihiro is based upon the Xbox, using the same Pentium III CPU and NVIDIA graphics card. Unlike the Xbox, however, it uses GD-ROM media instead of DVDs, has more RAM and an earlier revision chipset which is used in the Xbox debugging unit (MCPX2).
Because of the similar hardware, it is in theory relatively easy to port Chihiro games to the Xbox and PC. The GD-ROM board can be configured to store up to 1GB of data from the GD-ROM like with the Triforce.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Sega</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>2002</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-emulator}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>Chihiro هو نظام أركيد أنتجته شركتا Sega و Microsoft استنادًا إلى وحدة التحكم في ألعاب الفيديو المنزلية Xbox. كانت هذه هي الشراكة الثانية من نوعها، حيث تعاونت Sega أيضًا مع Namco و Nintendo في نظام Triforce الذي يعمل بنظام Nintendo GameCube. يعتمد Chihiro على Xbox، حيث يستخدم نفس وحدة المعالجة المركزية Pentium III وبطاقة الرسومات NVIDIA. ولكن على عكس Xbox، فإنه يستخدم وسائط GD-ROM بدلاً من أقراص DVD، ويحتوي على ذاكرة RAM أكبر وشريحة مراجعة سابقة تُستخدم في وحدة تصحيح أخطاء Xbox (MCPX2). ونظرًا لتشابه الأجهزة، من السهل نسبيًا من الناحية النظرية نقل ألعاب Chihiro إلى Xbox والكمبيوتر الشخصي. يمكن تكوين لوحة GD-ROM لتخزين ما يصل إلى 1 جيجابايت من البيانات من GD-ROM كما هو الحال مع Triforce.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>Chihiro je arkadni sistem koji su proizveli Sega i Microsoft, zasnovan na kućnoj videoigraćoj konzoli Xbox. Bio je to drugi takav partnerski poduhvat, pri čemu se Sega udružila s Namcom i Nintendom na sistemu Triforce pokretanom od strane Nintendo GameCubea. Chihiro je zasnovan na Xboxu, koristeći isti Pentium III procesor i NVIDIA grafičku karticu. Međutim, za razliku od Xboxa, koristi GD-ROM medije umjesto DVD-ova, ima više RAM-a i raniju reviziju čipseta koji se koristi u jedinici za otklanjanje grešaka Xboxa (MCPX2). Zbog sličnog hardvera, u teoriji je relativno lako portirati igre za Chihiro na Xbox i PC. GD-ROM ploča se može konfigurisati da pohrani do 1 GB podataka sa GD-ROM-a, kao i kod Triforcea.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>El Chihiro és un sistema d'arcade produït per Sega i Microsoft basat en la consola de videojocs domèstica Xbox. Va ser la segona col·laboració d'aquest tipus, amb Sega també associant-se amb Namco i Nintendo amb el sistema Triforce, basat en la Nintendo GameCube. El Chihiro es basa en l'Xbox, utilitzant la mateixa CPU Pentium III i la mateixa targeta gràfica NVIDIA. A diferència de l'Xbox, però, utilitza suports GD-ROM en lloc de DVD, té més RAM i un xip de revisió anterior que s'utilitza a la unitat de depuració de l'Xbox (MCPX2). A causa del maquinari similar, teòricament és relativament fàcil portar jocs de Chihiro a l'Xbox i al PC. La placa GD-ROM es pot configurar per emmagatzemar fins a 1 GB de dades del GD-ROM, com amb el Triforce.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Das Chihiro ist ein Arcade-System, das von Sega und Microsoft auf Basis der Xbox-Heimvideospielkonsole entwickelt wurde. Es war die zweite Partnerschaft dieser Art, wobei Sega auch mit Namco und Nintendo beim Nintendo GameCube-basierten Triforce-System zusammenarbeitete. Das Chihiro basiert auf der Xbox und verwendet denselben Pentium III-Prozessor und dieselbe NVIDIA-Grafikkarte. Im Gegensatz zur Xbox verwendet es jedoch GD-ROM-Medien anstelle von DVDs, verfügt über mehr RAM und einen früheren Chipsatz, der in der Xbox-Debugging-Einheit (MCPX2) verwendet wird. Aufgrund der ähnlichen Hardware ist es theoretisch relativ einfach, Chihiro-Spiele auf die Xbox und den PC zu portieren. Die GD-ROM-Karte kann so konfiguriert werden, dass sie wie beim Triforce bis zu 1 GB Daten von der GD-ROM speichert.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>El Chihiro es un sistema arcade producido por Sega y Microsoft basado en la consola de videojuegos doméstica Xbox. Fue la segunda colaboración de este tipo, ya que Sega también se alió con Namco y Nintendo con el sistema Triforce, basado en la Nintendo GameCube. El Chihiro se basa en la Xbox y utiliza la misma CPU Pentium III y la misma tarjeta gráfica NVIDIA. Sin embargo, a diferencia de la Xbox, utiliza soportes GD-ROM en lugar de DVD, tiene más RAM y un chipset de revisión anterior que se utiliza en la unidad de depuración de la Xbox (MCPX2). Debido a la similitud del hardware, en teoría es relativamente fácil portar los juegos de Chihiro a la Xbox y al PC. La placa GD-ROM se puede configurar para almacenar hasta 1 GB de datos del GD-ROM, al igual que con el Triforce.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>Le Chihiro est un système d'arcade produit par Sega et Microsoft basé sur la console de jeux vidéo Xbox. Il s'agissait du deuxième partenariat de ce type, Sega s'étant également associé à Namco et Nintendo pour créer le système Triforce alimenté par la Nintendo GameCube. Le Chihiro est basé sur la Xbox et utilise le même processeur Pentium III et la même carte graphique NVIDIA. Contrairement à la Xbox, cependant, il utilise des supports GD-ROM au lieu de DVD, dispose de plus de RAM et d'un chipset de révision antérieure utilisé dans l'unité de débogage Xbox (MCPX2). En raison de la similitude du matériel, il est en théorie relativement facile de porter les jeux Chihiro sur Xbox et PC. La carte GD-ROM peut être configurée pour stocker jusqu'à 1 Go de données provenant du GD-ROM, comme avec le Triforce.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>Chihiro je arkadni sustav koji su proizveli Sega i Microsoft, temeljen na kućnoj videoigraćoj konzoli Xbox. Bio je to drugi takav pothvat, pri čemu se Sega udružila s Namcom, a Nintendo sa sustavom Triforce pokretanim konzolom Nintendo GameCube. Chihiro je temeljen na Xboxu, koristeći isti procesor Pentium III i NVIDIA grafičku karticu. Međutim, za razliku od Xboksa, koristi GD-ROM medije umjesto DVD-a, ima više RAM-a i raniju reviziju čipseta koji se koristi u jedinici za otklanjanje pogrešaka Xboksa (MCPX2). Zbog sličnog hardvera, u teoriji je relativno jednostavno portirati igre za Chihiro na Xbox i PC. GD-ROM ploča može se konfigurirati za pohranu do 1 GB podataka s GD-ROM-a, kao i kod Triforcea.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Il Chihiro è un sistema arcade prodotto da Sega e Microsoft basato sulla console per videogiochi Xbox. Si trattava della seconda partnership di questo tipo, con Sega che aveva già collaborato con Namco e Nintendo per il sistema Triforce basato su Nintendo GameCube. Il Chihiro è basato su Xbox e utilizza lo stesso processore Pentium III e la stessa scheda grafica NVIDIA. A differenza della Xbox, tuttavia, utilizza supporti GD-ROM invece di DVD, ha più RAM e un chipset di revisione precedente utilizzato nell'unità di debug Xbox (MCPX2). A causa dell'hardware simile, in teoria è relativamente facile trasferire i giochi Chihiro su Xbox e PC. La scheda GD-ROM può essere configurata per memorizzare fino a 1 GB di dati dal GD-ROM come con il Triforce.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>チヒロは、Xbox家庭用ゲーム機をベースにセガとマイクロソフトが共同開発したアーケードシステムである。これは両社の2度目の提携であり、セガは以前にもナムコや任天堂と提携し、ニンテンドーゲームキューブを基盤としたトライフォースシステムを開発している。チヒロはXboxを基盤としており、同じPentium III CPUとNVIDIA製グラフィックカードを採用している。 ただしXboxとは異なり、DVDではなくGD-ROMメディアを採用し、より多くのRAMを搭載。さらにXboxデバッグユニット（MCPX2）で使用される初期リビジョンチップセットを採用している。ハードウェアが類似しているため、理論上チヒロ用ゲームをXboxやPCへ移植するのは比較的容易である。GD-ROMボードはトリフォースと同様、GD-ROMから最大1GBのデータを保存するよう設定可能だ。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>치히로는 세가와 마이크로소프트가 Xbox 가정용 비디오 게임 콘솔을 기반으로 제작한 아케이드 시스템이다. 이는 두 번째 협력 사례로, 세가는 닌텐도 게임큐브 기반 트라이포스 시스템 개발을 위해 남코 및 닌텐도와도 협력한 바 있다. 치히로는 Xbox를 기반으로 동일한 펜티엄 III CPU와 엔비디아 그래픽 카드를 사용한다. 그러나 엑스박스와 달리 DVD 대신 GD-ROM 미디어를 사용하며, 더 많은 RAM과 엑스박스 디버깅 유닛(MCPX2)에 사용된 초기 버전 칩셋을 탑재했습니다. 하드웨어가 유사하기 때문에 이론상 치히로 게임을 엑스박스와 PC로 이식하는 것은 비교적 쉽습니다. GD-ROM 보드는 트라이포스처럼 GD-ROM에서 최대 1GB의 데이터를 저장하도록 구성할 수 있습니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>De Chihiro is een arcadesysteem geproduceerd door Sega en Microsoft, gebaseerd op de Xbox-spelcomputer voor thuisgebruik. Het was de tweede samenwerking van dit type, waarbij Sega ook samenwerkte met Namco en Nintendo met het Triforce-systeem op basis van de Nintendo GameCube. De Chihiro is gebaseerd op de Xbox en maakt gebruik van dezelfde Pentium III-CPU en NVIDIA-grafische kaart. In tegenstelling tot de Xbox maakt het echter gebruik van GD-ROM-media in plaats van dvd's, heeft het meer RAM en een eerdere revisie van de chipset die wordt gebruikt in de Xbox-debugging-unit (MCPX2). Vanwege de vergelijkbare hardware is het in theorie relatief eenvoudig om Chihiro-games naar de Xbox en pc te porten. Het GD-ROM-bord kan worden geconfigureerd om tot 1 GB aan gegevens van de GD-ROM op te slaan, net als bij de Triforce.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Chihiro to system arcade wyprodukowany przez firmy Sega i Microsoft w oparciu o domową konsolę do gier Xbox. Była to druga tego typu współpraca, ponieważ firma Sega współpracowała również z Namco i Nintendo przy tworzeniu systemu Triforce opartego na konsoli Nintendo GameCube. System Chihiro jest oparty na konsoli Xbox i wykorzystuje ten sam procesor Pentium III oraz kartę graficzną NVIDIA. W przeciwieństwie do Xboxa, wykorzystuje jednak nośniki GD-ROM zamiast DVD, ma więcej pamięci RAM i starszą wersję chipsetu, który jest używany w jednostce debugującej Xboxa (MCPX2). Ze względu na podobny sprzęt, teoretycznie stosunkowo łatwo jest przenieść gry Chihiro na Xboxa i PC. Płytę GD-ROM można skonfigurować tak, aby przechowywała do 1 GB danych z GD-ROM, podobnie jak w przypadku Triforce.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>O Chihiro é um sistema arcade produzido pela Sega e pela Microsoft com base na consola de videojogos doméstica Xbox. Foi a segunda parceria deste tipo, com a Sega também a aliar-se à Namco e à Nintendo com o sistema Triforce, alimentado pela Nintendo GameCube. O Chihiro baseia-se na Xbox, utilizando o mesmo CPU Pentium III e placa gráfica NVIDIA. No entanto, ao contrário do Xbox, ele usa mídia GD-ROM em vez de DVDs, tem mais RAM e um chipset de revisão anterior que é usado na unidade de depuração do Xbox (MCPX2). Devido ao hardware semelhante, em teoria é relativamente fácil portar jogos do Chihiro para o Xbox e PC. A placa GD-ROM pode ser configurada para armazenar até 1 GB de dados do GD-ROM, como no Triforce.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Chihiro este un sistem arcade produs de Sega și Microsoft pe baza consolei de jocuri video Xbox. A fost al doilea parteneriat de acest gen, Sega colaborând și cu Namco și Nintendo pentru sistemul Triforce bazat pe Nintendo GameCube. Chihiro se bazează pe Xbox, utilizând același procesor Pentium III și aceeași placă grafică NVIDIA. Spre deosebire de Xbox, însă, utilizează suporturi GD-ROM în loc de DVD-uri, are mai multă memorie RAM și un chipset de revizie mai vechi, care este utilizat în unitatea de depanare Xbox (MCPX2). Datorită hardware-ului similar, în teorie este relativ ușor să se transfere jocurile Chihiro pe Xbox și PC. Placa GD-ROM poate fi configurată pentru a stoca până la 1 GB de date de pe GD-ROM, la fel ca în cazul Triforce.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Chihiro — это аркадная система, произведенная Sega и Microsoft на базе домашней игровой консоли Xbox. Это было второе подобное партнерство: Sega также сотрудничала с Namco и Nintendo в рамках системы Triforce на базе Nintendo GameCube. Chihiro основана на Xbox и использует тот же процессор Pentium III и графическую карту NVIDIA. Однако, в отличие от Xbox, она использует GD-ROM вместо DVD, имеет больше оперативной памяти и более раннюю версию чипсета, который используется в отладочном устройстве Xbox (MCPX2). Благодаря схожему аппаратному обеспечению, теоретически относительно легко перенести игры Chihiro на Xbox и ПК. Плата GD-ROM может быть настроена для хранения до 1 ГБ данных с GD-ROM, как и в Triforce.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>Чихиро је аркадни систем који су произвели Сега и Мајкрософт, заснован на кућној видео-играчкој конзоли Xbox. Било је то друго такво партнерство, при чему се Сега такође удружила са Намком и Нинтендом у оквиру система Triforce покретаног Нинтендо GameCube-ом. Чихиро је заснован на Xbox-у, користећи исти Pentium III процесор и графичку картицу компаније NVIDIA. Међутим, за разлику од Xbox-а, користи GD-ROM медије уместо DVD-ова, има више RAM-а и ранију ревизију чипсета који се користи у јединици за дебагирање Xbox-а (MCPX2). Због сличног хардвера, у теорији је релативно лако портирати игре за Chihiro на Xbox и PC. GD-ROM картица може бити конфигурисана да складишти до 1 GB података са GD-ROM-а, као и код Triforce-а.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>Chihiro är ett arkadsystem som tillverkas av Sega och Microsoft och baseras på Xbox-spelkonsolen. Det var det andra samarbetet av detta slag, där Sega också samarbetade med Namco och Nintendo med Triforce-systemet som baserades på Nintendo GameCube. Chihiro baseras på Xbox och använder samma Pentium III-processor och NVIDIA-grafikkort. Till skillnad från Xbox använder den dock GD-ROM-media istället för DVD-skivor, har mer RAM-minne och en tidigare version av chipset som används i Xbox-felsökningsenheten (MCPX2). På grund av den liknande hårdvaran är det i teorin relativt enkelt att porta Chihiro-spel till Xbox och PC. GD-ROM-kortet kan konfigureras för att lagra upp till 1 GB data från GD-ROM, precis som med Triforce.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>千寻是世嘉与微软基于Xbox家用游戏主机联合开发的街机系统。这是双方第二次合作——此前世嘉还曾与南梦宫及任天堂联手推出基于任天堂GameCube的Triforce系统。千寻主机以Xbox为基础，采用相同的奔腾III处理器和NVIDIA显卡。 但与Xbox不同的是，它采用GD-ROM介质而非DVD，拥有更大内存容量，并搭载早期版本芯片组（即Xbox调试单元使用的MCPX2芯片组）。由于硬件架构相似，理论上将千寻平台游戏移植至Xbox和PC相对容易。其GD-ROM主板可配置为存储高达1GB的GD-ROM数据，与Triforce系统功能一致。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
