<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>EDuke32</systemName>
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 is an awesome, free homebrew game engine and source port of the classic PC first person shooter Duke Nukem 3D— Duke3D for short—to Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, several handhelds, your family toaster, and to your girlfriend's vibrator. Thousands of cool and useful features and upgrades for regular players and additional editing capabilities and scripting extensions for homebrew developers and mod creators have beem added. EDuke32 is open source software that is completely free to use for all non-commercial purposes.

Created by Duke4.net community leader Richard "TerminX" Gobeille and a team of elite ninja programmers including Pierre-Loup "Plagman" Griffais, Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin, and Evan "Hendricks266" Ramos (based on work by Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler), EDuke32 is the undeniable king of Duke Nukem 3D ports.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Richard Gobeille</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>2015</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-port}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 هو محرك ألعاب رائع ومجاني ومصدر مفتوح المصدر للعبة التصويب من منظور الشخص الأول الكلاسيكية Duke Nukem 3D — Duke3D باختصار — لنظامي التشغيل Windows و Linux و Mac OS X و FreeBSD والعديد من الأجهزة المحمولة ومحمصة الخبز العائلية وهزاز صديقتك. تمت إضافة آلاف الميزات والتحسينات الرائعة والمفيدة للاعبين العاديين، بالإضافة إلى إمكانيات تحرير إضافية وامتدادات برمجية لمطوري الألعاب المنزلية ومبدعي التعديلات. EDuke32 هو برنامج مفتوح المصدر يمكن استخدامه مجانًا تمامًا لجميع الأغراض غير التجارية. تم إنشاؤه بواسطة قائد مجتمع Duke4.net ريتشارد "TerminX" جوبييل وفريق من مبرمجي النينجا النخبة، بما في ذلك بيير-لوب "Plagman" Griffais، Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin، و Evan "Hendricks266" Ramos (استنادًا إلى عمل Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler)، EDuke32 هو الملك بلا منازع لمنافذ Duke Nukem 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 je sjajan, besplatan homebrew game engine i source port klasične PC pucačine iz prvog lica Duke Nukem 3D — skraćeno Duke3D — za Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, nekoliko ručnih uređaja, vaš porodični toster i vibrator vaše djevojke. Dodano je hiljade sjajnih i korisnih funkcija i nadogradnji za redovne igrače, kao i dodatne mogućnosti uređivanja i skriptiranja za homebrew developere i kreatore modova. EDuke32 je softver otvorenog koda koji je potpuno besplatan za korištenje u sve nekomercijalne svrhe. Kreirali su ga vođa zajednice Duke4.net Richard "TerminX" Gobeille i tim elitnih ninja programera, uključujući Pierrea-Loupa "Plagman" Griffais, Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin i Evan "Hendricks266" Ramos (na osnovu rada Todda Reploglea/Kena Silvermana/Jonathana Fowlera/Matta Saettlera), EDuke32 je neosporni kralj Duke Nukem 3D portova.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 és un motor de joc homebrew fantàstic i gratuït i un port de codi font del clàssic joc de trets en primera persona per a PC Duke Nukem 3D — abreujat Duke3D — per a Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, diverses consoles portàtils, la torradora de la teva família i el vibrador de la teva xicota. S'hi han afegit milers de funcions i millores genials i útils per als jugadors habituals, així com capacitats d'edició addicionals i extensions d'escriptura per als desenvolupadors de homebrew i els creadors de mods. EDuke32 és programari de codi obert que és completament gratuït per a ús no comercial. Creat pel líder de la comunitat de Duke4.net, Richard "TerminX" Gobeille, i un equip d'elit de programadors ninja que inclou Pierre-Loup "Plagman" Creat per Richard "TerminX" Gobeille, líder de la comunitat de Duke4.net, i un equip d'elit de programadors ninja que inclou Pierre-Loup "Plagman" Griffais, Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin i Evan "Hendricks266" Ramos (basat en el treball de Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler), EDuke32 és el rei indiscutible dels ports de Duke Nukem 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 ist eine großartige, kostenlose Homebrew-Spiel-Engine und Source-Port des klassischen PC-Ego-Shooters Duke Nukem 3D – kurz Duke3D – für Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, verschiedene Handhelds, Ihren Familientoaster und den Vibrator Ihrer Freundin. Es wurden Tausende cooler und nützlicher Funktionen und Upgrades für normale Spieler sowie zusätzliche Bearbeitungsmöglichkeiten und Skript-Erweiterungen für Homebrew-Entwickler und Mod-Ersteller hinzugefügt. EDuke32 ist eine Open-Source-Software, die für alle nicht-kommerziellen Zwecke völlig kostenlos genutzt werden kann. Erstellt wurde sie vom Duke4.net-Community-Leiter Richard „TerminX” Gobeille und einem Team von Elite-Ninja-Programmierern, darunter Pierre-Loup „Plagman” Griffais, Philipp „Helixhorned“ Kutin und Evan „Hendricks266“ Ramos (basierend auf der Arbeit von Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler), ist EDuke32 der unbestrittene König der Duke Nukem 3D-Ports.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 es un increíble motor de juegos casero gratuito y un puerto fuente del clásico juego de disparos en primera persona para PC Duke Nukem 3D —Duke3D para abreviar— para Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, varios dispositivos portátiles, la tostadora de tu familia y el vibrador de tu novia. Se han añadido miles de funciones y mejoras interesantes y útiles para los jugadores habituales, así como capacidades de edición adicionales y extensiones de scripting para desarrolladores caseros y creadores de mods. EDuke32 es un software de código abierto totalmente gratuito para todos los fines no comerciales. Creado por el líder de la comunidad Duke4.net, Richard «TerminX» Gobeille, y un equipo de programadores ninja de élite, entre los que se encuentran Pierre-Loup «Plagman» Griffais, Philipp «Helixhorned» Kutin y Evan «Hendricks266» Ramos (basado en el trabajo de Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler), EDuke32 es el indiscutible rey de las versiones de Duke Nukem 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 est un moteur de jeu maison génial et gratuit, ainsi qu'un portage source du jeu de tir à la première personne classique Duke Nukem 3D (Duke3D en abrégé) vers Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, plusieurs appareils portables, votre grille-pain familial et le vibromasseur de votre petite amie. Des milliers de fonctionnalités et de mises à jour sympas et utiles pour les joueurs réguliers, ainsi que des capacités d'édition supplémentaires et des extensions de script pour les développeurs amateurs et les créateurs de mods ont été ajoutées. EDuke32 est un logiciel open source entièrement gratuit pour toute utilisation non commerciale. Créé par Richard « TerminX » Gobeille, leader de la communauté Duke4.net, et une équipe de programmeurs ninjas d'élite comprenant Pierre-Loup « Plagman » Griffais, Philipp « Helixhorned » Kutin et Evan « Hendricks266 » Ramos (basé sur les travaux de Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler), EDuke32 est le roi incontesté des ports Duke Nukem 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 je sjajan, besplatan homebrew game engine i source port klasične PC pucačine iz prvog lica Duke Nukem 3D — skraćeno Duke3D — za Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, nekoliko prijenosnih uređaja, vaš obiteljski toster i vibrator vaše djevojke. Dodano je tisuće sjajnih i korisnih značajki i nadogradnji za redovite igrače, kao i dodatne mogućnosti uređivanja i skriptiranja za homebrew programere i kreatore modova. EDuke32 je softver otvorenog koda koji je potpuno besplatan za korištenje u svim nekomercijalnim svrhama. Stvorili su ga vođa zajednice Duke4.net Richard "TerminX" Gobeille i tim elitnih ninja programera, uključujući Pierrea-Loupa "Plagman" Griffais, Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin i Evan "Hendricks266" Ramos (temeljen na radu Todda Reploglea/Kena Silvermana/Jonathana Fowlera/Mattta Saettlera), EDuke32 je neosporni kralj Duke Nukem 3D portova.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 è un fantastico motore di gioco gratuito e un porting sorgente del classico sparatutto in prima persona per PC Duke Nukem 3D, abbreviato in Duke3D, per Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, diversi dispositivi portatili, il tostapane di famiglia e il vibratore della tua ragazza. Sono state aggiunte migliaia di funzioni e aggiornamenti interessanti e utili per i giocatori abituali, oltre a capacità di editing aggiuntive ed estensioni di scripting per sviluppatori homebrew e creatori di mod. EDuke32 è un software open source completamente gratuito per tutti gli usi non commerciali. Creato dal leader della comunità Duke4.net Richard "TerminX" Gobeille e da un team di programmatori ninja d'élite tra cui Pierre-Loup "Plagman" Griffais, Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin ed Evan "Hendricks266" Ramos (basato sul lavoro di Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler), EDuke32 è l'indiscusso re dei porting di Duke Nukem 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32は、古典的なPCファーストパーソン・シューティングゲーム『Duke Nukem 3D』（略称Duke3D）の素晴らしい無料自作ゲームエンジンかつソースポートであり、Windows、Linux、Mac OS X、FreeBSD、複数の携帯端末、ご家族のトースター、そして彼女さんのバイブレーターまで対応しています。 通常のプレイヤー向けの何千ものクールで便利な機能やアップグレード、そして自作ゲーム開発者やMODクリエイター向けの追加の編集機能やスクリプト拡張機能が追加されています。EDuke32 は、非営利目的であれば完全に無料で使用できるオープンソースソフトウェアです。Duke4.net コミュニティのリーダーである Richard "TerminX" Gobeille 氏、そして Pierre-Loup "Plagman" Griffais、Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin、Evan "Hendricks266" Ramos といったエリート忍者プログラマーチーム（Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler の作品に基づく）によって作成された EDuke32 は、Duke Nukem 3D ポートの紛れもない王様です。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32는 클래식 PC 1인칭 슈팅 게임 'Duke Nukem 3D'(줄여서 Duke3D)의 훌륭한 무료 홈브루 게임 엔진이자 소스 포트로, Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, 여러 핸드헬드 기기, 가족용 토스터, 심지어 여자친구의 진동기까지 지원합니다. 일반 플레이어를 위한 수천 가지의 멋지고 유용한 기능과 업그레이드, 그리고 홈브루 개발자와 모드 제작자를 위한 추가 편집 기능 및 스크립팅 확장 기능이 추가되었습니다. EDuke32는 모든 비상업적 목적으로 완전히 무료로 사용할 수 있는 오픈 소스 소프트웨어입니다. Duke4.net 커뮤니티 리더인 Richard "TerminX" Gobeille과 Pierre-Loup "Plagman" Griffais, Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin, Evan "Hendricks266" Ramos 등이 참여한 엘리트 닌자 프로그래머 팀이 Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler의 작업을 기반으로 개발한 EDuke32는 Duke Nukem 3D 포팅의 확실한 왕좌를 차지하고 있습니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 is een geweldige, gratis homebrew-game-engine en source port van de klassieke pc-first person shooter Duke Nukem 3D — kortweg Duke3D — voor Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, verschillende handhelds, je broodrooster en de vibrator van je vriendin. Er zijn duizenden coole en handige functies en upgrades voor gewone spelers en extra bewerkingsmogelijkheden en scriptuitbreidingen voor homebrew-ontwikkelaars en mod-makers toegevoegd. EDuke32 is open source software die volledig gratis te gebruiken is voor alle niet-commerciële doeleinden. Gemaakt door Duke4.net-communityleider Richard "TerminX" Gobeille en een team van elite ninja-programmeurs, waaronder Pierre-Loup "Plagman" Griffais, Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin en Evan "Hendricks266" Ramos (gebaseerd op werk van Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler). EDuke32 is de onbetwiste koning van de Duke Nukem 3D-ports.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 to niesamowity, darmowy silnik gier typu homebrew i port źródłowy klasycznej strzelanki FPS Duke Nukem 3D — w skrócie Duke3D — na systemy Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, kilka urządzeń przenośnych, toster Twojej rodziny i wibrator Twojej dziewczyny. Dodano tysiące fajnych i przydatnych funkcji oraz ulepszeń dla zwykłych graczy, a także dodatkowe możliwości edycji i rozszerzenia skryptowe dla twórców domowych i modów. EDuke32 to oprogramowanie open source, które jest całkowicie bezpłatne do użytku w celach niekomercyjnych. Stworzone przez lidera społeczności Duke4.net, Richarda „TerminX” Gobeille'a, oraz zespół elitarnych programistów ninja, w tym Pierre-Loup „Plagman” Griffais, Philipp „Helixhorned” Kutin i Evan „Hendricks266” Ramos (na podstawie prac Todda Replogle'a/Kena Silvermana/Jonathana Fowlera/Matta Saettlera), EDuke32 jest niekwestionowanym królem portów Duke Nukem 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 é um incrível motor de jogo gratuito e porta de código-fonte do clássico jogo de tiro em primeira pessoa para PC Duke Nukem 3D — Duke3D, para abreviar — para Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, vários dispositivos portáteis, a torradeira da sua família e o vibrador da sua namorada. Milhares de recursos e atualizações legais e úteis para jogadores regulares e recursos adicionais de edição e extensões de script para desenvolvedores caseiros e criadores de mods foram adicionados. O EDuke32 é um software de código aberto totalmente gratuito para todos os fins não comerciais. Criado pelo líder da comunidade Duke4.net, Richard "TerminX" Gobeille, e uma equipe de programadores ninjas de elite, incluindo Pierre-Loup "Plagman" Griffais, Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin e Evan "Hendricks266" Ramos (baseado no trabalho de Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler), o EDuke32 é o rei indiscutível das versões do Duke Nukem 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 este un motor de jocuri homebrew gratuit și un port sursă al clasicului joc first person shooter pentru PC Duke Nukem 3D — pe scurt Duke3D — pentru Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, mai multe dispozitive portabile, prăjitorul de pâine al familiei tale și vibratorul prietenei tale. Au fost adăugate mii de funcții și upgrade-uri interesante și utile pentru jucătorii obișnuiți, precum și capacități suplimentare de editare și extensii de scripting pentru dezvoltatorii homebrew și creatorii de moduri. EDuke32 este un software open source care poate fi utilizat complet gratuit în toate scopurile necomerciale. Creat de liderul comunității Duke4.net, Richard „TerminX” Gobeille, și de o echipă de programatori ninja de elită, printre care Pierre-Loup „Plagman” Griffais, Philipp „Helixhorned” Kutin și Evan „Hendricks266” Ramos (bazat pe munca lui Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler), EDuke32 este regele incontestabil al porturilor Duke Nukem 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 — это потрясающий бесплатный игровой движок и порт классической компьютерной игры-шутера от первого лица Duke Nukem 3D (сокращенно Duke3D) для Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, нескольких карманных устройств, вашего семейного тостера и вибратора вашей девушки. Добавлены тысячи классных и полезных функций и обновлений для обычных игроков, а также дополнительные возможности редактирования и расширения скриптов для разработчиков самодельных игр и создателей модификаций. EDuke32 — это программное обеспечение с открытым исходным кодом, которое можно совершенно бесплатно использовать в некоммерческих целях. Создано лидером сообщества Duke4.net Ричардом «TerminX» Гобелем и командой элитных программистов-ниндзя, в которую входят Пьер-Лу «Plagman» Гриффе, Филиппа «Helixhorned» Кутина и Эвана «Hendricks266» Рамоса (на основе работы Тодда Реплогла/Кена Сильвермана/Джонатона Фаулера/Мэтта Сэттлера), EDuke32 является бесспорным королем портов Duke Nukem 3D.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 је сјајан, бесплатан хоумбрев гејм енджин и соурс порт класичне ПЦ пуцачине из првог лица Duke Nukem 3D — скраћено Duke3D — за Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, неколико преносивих уређаја, породични тостер и вибратор твоје девојке. Додате су хиљаде кул и корисних функција и надоградњи за редовне играче, као и додатне могућности за уређивање и скриптирање за хоумбрев програмере и креаторе модова. EDuke32 је софтвер отвореног кода који је потпуно бесплатан за све некомерцијалне сврхе. Креирали су га вођа заједнице Duke4.net Ричард "TerminX" Гобејл и тим елитних нинџа програмера, укључујући Пјер-Луп "Plagman" EDuke32, који су креирали вођа заједнице Duke4.net Ричард "TerminX" Гобеј и тим елитних нинџа програмера, укључујући Пјер-Лупа "Plagman" Грифеа, Филипа "Helixhorned" Кутина и Евана "Hendricks266" Рамоса (на основу рада Тода Реплогла/Кена Силвермана/Џонатана Фаулера/Мэта Саетлера), неспорни је краљ Duke Nukem 3D портoва.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32 är en fantastisk, gratis hemgjord spelmotor och källkodsport av det klassiska PC-förstapersonsskjutaren Duke Nukem 3D – kort sagt Duke3D – till Windows, Linux, Mac OS X, FreeBSD, flera handhållna enheter, din familjs brödrost och din flickväns vibrator. Tusentals coola och användbara funktioner och uppgraderingar för vanliga spelare samt ytterligare redigeringsfunktioner och skriptförlängningar för hembryggda utvecklare och modskapare har lagts till. EDuke32 är en öppen källkodsprogramvara som är helt gratis att använda för alla icke-kommersiella ändamål. Skapad av Duke4.net-communityledaren Richard "TerminX" Gobeille och ett team av elitninja-programmerare, inklusive Pierre-Loup "Plagman" Griffais, Philipp "Helixhorned" Kutin och Evan "Hendricks266" Ramos (baserat på arbete av Todd Replogle/Ken Silverman/Jonathon Fowler/Matt Saettler). EDuke32 är den obestridliga kungen av Duke Nukem 3D-portar.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>EDuke32是一款超棒的免费自制游戏引擎，它将经典PC第一人称射击游戏《毁灭公爵3D》（简称Duke3D）移植到Windows、Linux、Mac OS X、FreeBSD、多种掌机、你家的烤面包机，甚至你女友的按摩棒上。 该引擎为普通玩家新增了数千项实用酷炫功能与升级，同时为自制游戏开发者和模组创作者提供了额外的编辑能力及脚本扩展。EDuke32作为开源软件，完全免费供所有非商业用途使用。由Duke4.net社区领袖Richard "TerminX" Gobeille与精英忍者程序员团队共同打造，成员包括Pierre-Loup "Plagman" 格里菲、菲利普·"螺旋角"·库廷、埃文·"亨德里克斯266"·拉莫斯（基于托德·雷普洛格/肯·西尔弗曼/乔纳森·福勒/马特·塞特勒的成果）组成的精英忍者程序员团队，EDuke32堪称《毁灭公爵3D》移植版的无可争议之王。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
