<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Game Pocket Computer</systemName>
    <systemDescription>The Epoch Game Pocket Computer (Japanese: ゲームポケコン, Hepburn: Gēmupokekon) is a second-generation handheld game console released by Epoch Co. in Japan in 1984 for 12,000 Japanese yen. It is also known as Pokekon and was one of the very few truly handheld systems to be released in the early 1980s, preceding the Game Boy by 5 years.

The system was a bust in Japan, and as a result, only 5 games were made for it. A puzzle game and a paint program were built into the system. It was powered by 4 AA batteries, and screen's contrast could be adjusted by the user. Input and output controls included four buttons, an 8-way joypad, a contrast dial, and a sound on-off switch.

The Game Pocket Computer failed in Japan, and was never released internationally. The device is extremely rare, and units on eBay can go for hundreds of US dollars.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Epoch</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1984</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-portable}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>جهاز Epoch Game Pocket Computer (باليابانية: ゲームポケコン، هيبورن: Gēmupokekon) هو جهاز ألعاب محمول من الجيل الثاني أطلقته شركة Epoch Co. في اليابان عام 1984 بسعر 12000 ين ياباني. يُعرف أيضًا باسم Pokekon وكان أحد الأجهزة المحمولة القليلة جدًا التي تم إطلاقها في أوائل الثمانينيات، قبل جهاز Game Boy بخمس سنوات.

فشل الجهاز في اليابان، ونتيجة لذلك، لم يتم إنتاج سوى 5 ألعاب له. تم تضمين لعبة ألغاز وبرنامج رسم في الجهاز. كان الجهاز يعمل بـ 4 بطاريات AA، ويمكن للمستخدم ضبط تباين الشاشة. تضمنت أدوات التحكم في الإدخال والإخراج أربعة أزرار، ولوحة تحكم ذات 8 اتجاهات، ومفتاح ضبط التباين، ومفتاح تشغيل وإيقاف الصوت.

فشل جهاز Game Pocket Computer في اليابان، ولم يتم طرحه دوليًا أبدًا. هذا الجهاز نادر للغاية، ويمكن أن تصل أسعار الوحدات المعروضة على موقع eBay إلى مئات الدولارات الأمريكية.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>Epoch Game Pocket Computer (japanski: ゲームポケコン, Hepburn: Gēmupokekon) je džepna igraća konzola druge generacije koju je kompanija Epoch Co. izdala u Japanu 1984. godine za 12.000 japanskih jena. Poznata je i kao Pokekon i bila je jedan od rijetkih zaista džepnih sistema objavljenih početkom 1980-ih, pet godina prije Game Boya.

Sistem je bio neuspjeh u Japanu, te je stoga napravljeno samo 5 igara za njega. U sistemu su bile ugrađene igra slagalica i program za slikanje. Napajao se sa 4 AA baterije, a korisnik je mogao podešavati kontrast ekrana. Kontrole za unos i izlaz uključivale su četiri tipke, džojpad sa osam smjerova, kotačić za kontrast i prekidač za uključivanje/isključivanje zvuka.

Game Pocket Computer je propao u Japanu i nikada nije objavljen na međunarodnom tržištu. Uređaj je izuzetno rijedak, a primjerci na eBayu mogu koštati stotine američkih dolara.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>L'Epoch Game Pocket Computer (en japonès: ゲームポケコン, Hepburn: Gēmupokekon) és una consola de jocs portàtil de segona generació llançada per Epoch Co. al Japó el 1984 per 12.000 iens japonesos. També és coneguda com a Pokekon i va ser un dels pocs sistemes realment portàtils llançats a principis dels anys vuitanta, precedint la Game Boy en 5 anys.

El sistema va ser un fracàs al Japó i, com a resultat, només es van crear 5 jocs per a ell. Un joc de trencaclosques i un programa de pintura estaven integrats al sistema. Funcionava amb 4 piles AA, i el contrast de la pantalla es podia ajustar per l'usuari. Els controls d'entrada i sortida incloïen quatre botons, un joystick de 8 direccions, un selector de contrast i un interruptor d'encesa/apagada del so.

El Game Pocket Computer va ser un fracàs al Japó i mai no es va llançar internacionalment. El dispositiu és extremadament rar, i les unitats a eBay poden arribar a costar centenars de dòlars americans.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Der Epoch Game Pocket Computer (japanisch: ゲームポケコン, Hepburn: Gēmupokekon) ist eine Handheld-Spielkonsole der zweiten Generation, die 1984 von Epoch Co. in Japan für 12.000 japanische Yen auf den Markt gebracht wurde. Er ist auch unter dem Namen Pokekon bekannt und war eines der wenigen echten Handheld-Systeme, die in den frühen 1980er Jahren auf den Markt kamen, fünf Jahre vor dem Game Boy.

Das System war in Japan ein Flop, sodass nur fünf Spiele dafür entwickelt wurden. Ein Puzzlespiel und ein Malprogramm waren in das System integriert. Es wurde mit vier AA-Batterien betrieben, und der Kontrast des Bildschirms konnte vom Benutzer eingestellt werden. Zu den Ein- und Ausgabesteuerungen gehörten vier Tasten, ein 8-Wege-Joypad, ein Kontrastregler und ein Ein-/Aus-Schalter für den Ton.

Der Game Pocket Computer scheiterte in Japan und wurde nie international veröffentlicht. Das Gerät ist äußerst selten und kann auf eBay für mehrere hundert US-Dollar verkauft werden.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>La Epoch Game Pocket Computer (en japonés: ゲームポケコン, Hepburn: Gēmupokekon) es una consola portátil de segunda generación lanzada por Epoch Co. en Japón en 1984 por 12 000 yenes japoneses. También se la conoce como Pokekon y fue uno de los pocos sistemas verdaderamente portátiles que se lanzaron a principios de la década de 1980, cinco años antes que la Game Boy.

La consola fue un fracaso en Japón y, como resultado, solo se crearon cinco juegos para ella. El sistema incorporaba un juego de puzles y un programa de pintura. Funcionaba con cuatro pilas AA y el usuario podía ajustar el contraste de la pantalla. Los controles de entrada y salida incluían cuatro botones, un joypad de ocho direcciones, un dial de contraste y un interruptor de encendido y apagado del sonido.

La Game Pocket Computer fracasó en Japón y nunca se comercializó a nivel internacional. El dispositivo es extremadamente raro y las unidades que se venden en eBay pueden alcanzar cientos de dólares estadounidenses.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>La console de jeu portable Epoch Game Pocket Computer (en japonais : ゲームポケコン, Hepburn : Gēmupokekon) est une console de jeu portable de deuxième génération commercialisée par Epoch Co. au Japon en 1984 au prix de 12 000 yens japonais. Également connue sous le nom de Pokekon, elle était l'une des rares consoles véritablement portables commercialisées au début des années 1980, précédant la Game Boy de 5 ans.

La console a été un échec commercial au Japon, et seuls cinq jeux ont été développés pour elle. Un jeu de puzzle et un programme de peinture étaient intégrés à la console. Elle fonctionnait avec quatre piles AA et le contraste de l'écran pouvait être réglé par l'utilisateur. Les commandes d'entrée et de sortie comprenaient quatre boutons, un joypad à 8 directions, un bouton de réglage du contraste et un interrupteur marche/arrêt du son.

Le Game Pocket Computer a échoué au Japon et n'a jamais été commercialisé à l'international. Cet appareil est extrêmement rare et les exemplaires vendus sur eBay peuvent atteindre plusieurs centaines de dollars américains.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>Epoch Game Pocket Computer (japanski: ゲームポケコン, Hepburn: Gēmupokekon) je ručna igraća konzola druge generacije koju je tvrtka Epoch Co. izdala u Japanu 1984. godine za 12.000 japanskih jena. Također je poznata kao Pokekon i bio je jedan od rijetkih istinski ručnih sustava objavljenih početkom 1980-ih, 5 godina prije Game Boya.

Sustav je bio neuspjeh u Japanu i kao rezultat toga napravljeno je samo 5 igara za njega. U sustav su bile ugrađene igra slagalica i program za crtanje. Napajao se s 4 AA baterije, a korisnik je mogao podesiti kontrast ekrana. Kontrole za unos i izlaz uključivale su četiri tipke, joypad s osam smjerova, kotačić za kontrast i prekidač za uključivanje/isključivanje zvuka.

Game Pocket Computer nije uspio u Japanu i nikada nije pušten u međunaradnu prodaju. Uređaj je izuzetno rijedak, a na eBayu se primjerci mogu prodavati za stotine američkih dolara.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>L'Epoch Game Pocket Computer (in giapponese: ゲームポケコン, Hepburn: Gēmupokekon) è una console di gioco portatile di seconda generazione lanciata dalla Epoch Co. in Giappone nel 1984 al prezzo di 12.000 yen giapponesi. Conosciuto anche come Pokekon, è stato uno dei pochissimi sistemi veramente portatili lanciati nei primi anni '80, precedendo il Game Boy di 5 anni.

La console fu un fallimento in Giappone e, di conseguenza, furono realizzati solo 5 giochi. Un puzzle game e un programma di disegno erano integrati nella console. Era alimentata da 4 batterie AA e il contrasto dello schermo poteva essere regolato dall'utente. I controlli di input e output includevano quattro pulsanti, un joypad a 8 direzioni, una manopola per il contrasto e un interruttore per l'accensione e lo spegnimento dell'audio.

Il Game Pocket Computer fallì in Giappone e non fu mai commercializzato a livello internazionale. Il dispositivo è estremamente raro e le unità su eBay possono raggiungere centinaia di dollari americani.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>エポックゲームポケットコンピュータ（ゲームポケコン）は、1984年にエポック社が日本で発売した第2世代の携帯型ゲーム機である。価格は12,000円。通称「ポケコン」とも呼ばれ、1980年代初頭に発売された数少ない真の携帯型ゲーム機の一つであり、ゲームボーイより5年先行していた。

本機は日本で失敗作となり、結果として対応ソフトは5本のみとなった。本体にはパズルゲームとペイントプログラムが内蔵されていた。電源は単三形乾電池4本で、画面のコントラストはユーザーが調整可能だった。入力・出力操作には4つのボタン、8方向ジョイパッド、コントラストダイヤル、音量オンオフスイッチが備わっていた。

ゲームポケットコンピュータは日本市場で失敗に終わり、海外では発売されなかった。このデバイスは極めて希少で、eBayでは数百ドルで取引されることもある。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>에포크 게임 포켓 컴퓨터(일본어: ゲームポケコン, 헤프번: Gēmupokekon)는 1984년 일본에서 에포크 주식회사가 12,000엔에 출시한 2세대 휴대용 게임 콘솔이다. 포케콘으로도 알려져 있으며, 1980년대 초반에 출시된 진정한 의미의 휴대용 시스템 중 극소수에 속하며 게임보이보다 5년 앞서 출시되었다.

이 시스템은 일본에서 실패작이었으며, 그 결과 단 5종의 게임만 제작되었다. 퍼즐 게임과 페인트 프로그램이 기기에 내장되어 있었다. 4개의 AA 배터리로 작동했으며, 사용자가 화면의 명암을 조절할 수 있었다. 입력 및 출력 제어 장치로는 4개의 버튼, 8방향 조이패드, 명암 조절 다이얼, 음향 켜기/끄기 스위치가 포함되었다.

게임 포켓 컴퓨터는 일본에서 실패했으며, 해외에는 출시되지 않았다. 이 기기는 극히 희귀하여 이베이에서 수백 달러에 거래되기도 한다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>De Epoch Game Pocket Computer (Japans: ゲームポケコン, Hepburn: Gēmupokekon) is een tweede generatie draagbare spelcomputer die in 1984 door Epoch Co. in Japan werd uitgebracht voor 12.000 Japanse yen. Hij staat ook bekend als Pokekon en was een van de weinige echt draagbare systemen die in het begin van de jaren tachtig op de markt kwamen, vijf jaar voor de Game Boy.

Het systeem was een flop in Japan en als gevolg daarvan werden er slechts vijf spellen voor gemaakt. Een puzzelspel en een tekenprogramma waren in het systeem ingebouwd. Het werkte op vier AA-batterijen en het contrast van het scherm kon door de gebruiker worden aangepast. De invoer- en uitvoerbediening bestond uit vier knoppen, een 8-weg joypad, een contrastknop en een aan/uit-schakelaar voor het geluid.

De Game Pocket Computer mislukte in Japan en werd nooit internationaal uitgebracht. Het apparaat is uiterst zeldzaam en exemplaren op eBay kunnen honderden Amerikaanse dollars opbrengen.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Epoch Game Pocket Computer (jap. ゲームポケコン, Hepburn: Gēmupokekon) to przenośna konsola do gier drugiej generacji, wydana przez firmę Epoch Co. w Japonii w 1984 roku w cenie 12 000 jenów japońskich. Znana również pod nazwą Pokekon, była jedną z nielicznych prawdziwie przenośnych konsol wydanych na początku lat 80., wyprzedzając Game Boya o 5 lat.

System okazał się porażką w Japonii, w wyniku czego powstało dla niego tylko 5 gier. W systemie wbudowano grę logiczną i program do malowania. Był zasilany 4 bateriami AA, a kontrast ekranu mógł być regulowany przez użytkownika. Elementy sterujące wejściem i wyjściem obejmowały cztery przyciski, 8-kierunkowy joypad, pokrętło kontrastu i przełącznik włączania/wyłączania dźwięku.

Game Pocket Computer nie odniósł sukcesu w Japonii i nigdy nie został wprowadzony na rynek międzynarodowy. Urządzenie to jest niezwykle rzadkie, a egzemplarze wystawiane na eBayu osiągają ceny rzędu setek dolarów amerykańskich.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>O Epoch Game Pocket Computer (em japonês: ゲームポケコン, Hepburn: Gēmupokekon) é uma consola portátil de segunda geração lançada pela Epoch Co. no Japão em 1984 por 12 000 ienes japoneses. Também é conhecida como Pokekon e foi um dos poucos sistemas verdadeiramente portáteis lançados no início da década de 1980, precedendo a Game Boy em 5 anos.

O sistema foi um fracasso no Japão e, como resultado, apenas cinco jogos foram criados para ele. Um jogo de quebra-cabeça e um programa de pintura foram incorporados ao sistema. Ele era alimentado por quatro pilhas AA e o contraste da tela podia ser ajustado pelo usuário. Os controles de entrada e saída incluíam quatro botões, um joypad de oito direções, um botão de contraste e um botão liga/desliga de som.

O Game Pocket Computer fracassou no Japão e nunca foi lançado internacionalmente. O dispositivo é extremamente raro, e as unidades no eBay podem chegar a centenas de dólares americanos.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Epoch Game Pocket Computer (în japoneză: ゲームポケコン, Hepburn: Gēmupokekon) este o consolă de jocuri portabilă de a doua generație lansată de Epoch Co. în Japonia în 1984, la prețul de 12.000 de yeni japonezi. Este cunoscută și sub numele de Pokekon și a fost unul dintre puținele sisteme cu adevărat portabile lansate la începutul anilor 1980, precedând Game Boy cu 5 ani.

Sistemul a fost un eșec în Japonia și, ca urmare, au fost create doar 5 jocuri pentru acesta. Un joc de puzzle și un program de pictură erau încorporate în sistem. Era alimentat de 4 baterii AA, iar contrastul ecranului putea fi reglat de utilizator. Comenzile de intrare și ieșire includeau patru butoane, un joypad cu 8 direcții, un cadran de contrast și un comutator de pornire-oprire a sunetului.

Game Pocket Computer a eșuat în Japonia și nu a fost lansat niciodată la nivel internațional. Dispozitivul este extrem de rar, iar unitățile de pe eBay pot ajunge la sute de dolari americani.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Epoch Game Pocket Computer (яп. ゲームポケコン, Хепберн: Gēmupokekon) — портативная игровая консоль второго поколения, выпущенная компанией Epoch Co. в Японии в 1984 году по цене 12 000 иен. Она также известна под названием Pokekon и была одной из немногих по-настоящему портативных систем, выпущенных в начале 1980-х годов, на 5 лет опередив Game Boy.

Система провалилась в Японии, в результате чего для нее было выпущено только 5 игр. В систему были встроены головоломка и программа для рисования. Она питалась от 4 батареек AA, а контрастность экрана пользователь мог регулировать самостоятельно. Управление вводом и выводом включало четыре кнопки, 8-позиционный джойпад, регулятор контрастности и переключатель включения/выключения звука.

Game Pocket Computer провалился в Японии и так и не был выпущен на международном рынке. Устройство является чрезвычайно редким, и на eBay его можно купить за сотни долларов США.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>Epoch Game Pocket Computer (јапански: ゲームポケコン, Хепберн: Gēmupokekon) је ручна играћа конзола друге генерације коју је компанија Epoch Co. објавила у Јапану 1984. године по цени од 12.000 јапанских јена. Такође је позната као Pokekon и била је један од ретких заиста ручних система објављених почетком 1980-их, пет година пре Game Boy-а.

Систем је био неуспех у Јапану, и као резултат, направљене су само 5 игара за њега. Уграђена су загонетка и програм за цртање. Покретан је са 4 АА батерије, а контраст екрана могао је да подеси корисник. Контроле улаза и излаза укључивале су четири дугмета, 8-смерни џојпад, точак за контраст и прекидач за укључивање/искључивање звука.

Game Pocket Computer је пропао у Јапану и никада није био пуштен у међународну продају. Уређај је изузетно редак, а примерак на eBay-у може коштати стотине америчких долара.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>Epoch Game Pocket Computer (japanska: ゲームポケコン, Hepburn: Gēmupokekon) är en andra generationens handhållen spelkonsol som släpptes av Epoch Co. i Japan 1984 för 12 000 japanska yen. Den är även känd som Pokekon och var en av de få riktigt handhållna systemen som släpptes i början av 1980-talet, fem år före Game Boy.

Systemet blev en flopp i Japan, och som ett resultat tillverkades endast fem spel för det. Ett pusselspel och ett målarprogram var inbyggda i systemet. Det drevs av fyra AA-batterier, och skärmens kontrast kunde justeras av användaren. In- och utgångskontrollerna inkluderade fyra knappar, en 8-vägs joypad, en kontrastratt och en ljudpå/av-knapp.

Game Pocket Computer misslyckades i Japan och släpptes aldrig internationellt. Enheten är extremt sällsynt och exemplar på eBay kan kosta hundratals amerikanska dollar.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>Epoch游戏掌上电脑（日文：ゲームポケコン，音译：Gēmupokekon）是Epoch公司于1984年在日本发售的第二代掌上游戏机，售价12,000日元。该设备亦称Pokekon，是1980年代初期为数不多的真正掌上游戏系统之一，比Game Boy早问世五年。

该系统在日本市场惨遭滑铁卢，仅推出5款游戏。系统内置益智游戏与绘图程序，采用4节AA电池供电，用户可调节屏幕对比度。输入输出控制装置包含四个按键、八向摇杆、对比度旋钮及声音开关。

Game Pocket Computer在日本市场失败后，从未在国际上发售。该设备极为罕见，在eBay上的售价可达数百美元。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
