<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>GZDoom</systemName>
    <systemDescription>GZDoom is a fork of the ZDoom source port created by Christoph Oelckers (Graf Zahl), who still oversees its development. First released in 2005, it has versions for Windows, Linux, and MacOS.

GZDoom remains a popular port due to both its unprecedented modding capability and graphical optimizations for modern hardware. In particular, the ZScript language unique to GZDoom, combined with ACS and DECORATE inherited from ZDoom, enables a high level of gameplay modding and special mapping features.

Many maps and mods, plus some total conversions and stand-alone games, have been exclusive to GZDoom. This includes over a dozen Cacoward winners.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Christoph Oelckers</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>2005</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-port}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom هو نسخة معدلة من منفذ ZDoom المصدري الذي أنشأه كريستوف أولكيرز (Graf Zahl)، الذي لا يزال يشرف على تطويره. تم إصداره لأول مرة في عام 2005، وله إصدارات لنظامي التشغيل Windows و Linux و MacOS. لا يزال GZDoom منفذًا شائعًا بسبب قدرته غير المسبوقة على التعديل وتحسينات الرسومات للأجهزة الحديثة. على وجه الخصوص، تتيح لغة ZScript الفريدة لـ GZDoom، جنبًا إلى جنب مع ACS و DECORATE الموروثتين من ZDoom، مستوى عالٍ من تعديل طريقة اللعب وميزات خرائط خاصة. العديد من الخرائط والتعديلات، بالإضافة إلى بعض التحويلات الكاملة والألعاب المستقلة، كانت حصرية لـ GZDoom. وهذا يشمل أكثر من عشرة فائزين بجائزة Cacoward.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom je fork ZDoom source porta koji je kreirao Christoph Oelckers (Graf Zahl), koji i dalje nadgleda njegov razvoj. Prvi put objavljen 2005. godine, ima verzije za Windows, Linux i MacOS. GZDoom ostaje popularan port zbog svoje neviđene mogućnosti modifikacije i grafičkih optimizacija za moderan hardver. Posebno, ZScript, programski jezik jedinstven za GZDoom, u kombinaciji sa ACS-om i DECORATE-om naslijeđenim od ZDooma, omogućava visok nivo modifikacije igrivosti i posebne mapeerske mogućnosti. Mnoge mape i modovi, kao i neke totalne konverzije i samostalne igre, bile su ekskluzivne za GZDoom. To uključuje i preko deset pobjednika Cacoward nagrade.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom és un fork del port de codi font de ZDoom creat per Christoph Oelckers (Graf Zahl), que encara supervisa el seu desenvolupament. Publicat per primer cop el 2005, té versions per a Windows, Linux i MacOS. GZDoom continua sent un port popular gràcies tant a la seva capacitat de modding sense precedents com a les optimitzacions gràfiques per a maquinari modern. En particular, el llenguatge ZScript, exclusiu de GZDoom, combinat amb l'ACS i el DECORATE heretats de ZDoom, permet un alt nivell de personalització de la jugabilitat i funcions especials de mapatge. Molts mapes i mods, a més d'algunes conversions totals i jocs independents, han estat exclusius de GZDoom. Això inclou més d'una dotzena de guanyadors del Cacoward.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom ist ein Fork des ZDoom-Source-Ports, der von Christoph Oelckers (Graf Zahl) erstellt wurde, der auch weiterhin die Entwicklung überwacht. Es wurde erstmals 2005 veröffentlicht und ist in Versionen für Windows, Linux und MacOS erhältlich. GZDoom ist aufgrund seiner beispiellosen Modding-Fähigkeiten und grafischen Optimierungen für moderne Hardware nach wie vor ein beliebter Port. Insbesondere die für GZDoom einzigartige Sprache ZScript ermöglicht in Kombination mit den von ZDoom übernommenen ACS- und DECORATE-Funktionen ein hohes Maß an Gameplay-Modding und spezielle Mapping-Funktionen. Viele Maps und Mods sowie einige Total Conversions und eigenständige Spiele sind exklusiv für GZDoom verfügbar. Dazu gehören auch über ein Dutzend Cacoward-Gewinner.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom es una bifurcación del puerto fuente ZDoom creado por Christoph Oelckers (Graf Zahl), quien aún supervisa su desarrollo. Lanzado por primera vez en 2005, tiene versiones para Windows, Linux y MacOS. GZDoom sigue siendo un puerto popular debido a su capacidad de modificación sin precedentes y a las optimizaciones gráficas para el hardware moderno. En particular, el lenguaje ZScript exclusivo de GZDoom, combinado con ACS y DECORATE heredados de ZDoom, permite un alto nivel de modificación del juego y funciones especiales de mapeo. Muchos mapas y mods, además de algunas conversiones totales y juegos independientes, han sido exclusivos de GZDoom. Esto incluye más de una docena de ganadores del Cacoward.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom est un fork du portage source ZDoom créé par Christoph Oelckers (Graf Zahl), qui supervise toujours son développement. Sorti pour la première fois en 2005, il existe en versions Windows, Linux et MacOS. GZDoom reste un portage populaire en raison de ses capacités de modding sans précédent et de ses optimisations graphiques pour le matériel moderne. En particulier, le langage ZScript propre à GZDoom, combiné à ACS et DECORATE hérités de ZDoom, permet un haut niveau de modding du gameplay et des fonctionnalités de mappage spéciales. De nombreuses cartes et mods, ainsi que certaines conversions totales et certains jeux autonomes, ont été exclusifs à GZDoom. Cela inclut plus d'une douzaine de lauréats du Cacoward.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom je fork izvornog portiranja ZDooma koji je stvorio Christoph Oelckers (Graf Zahl), koji i dalje nadgleda njegov razvoj. Prvi put objavljen 2005. godine, ima verzije za Windows, Linux i MacOS. GZDoom ostaje popularan port zbog svoje neviđene mogućnosti modiranja i grafičkih optimizacija za suvremeni hardver. Posebno, programski jezik ZScript, jedinstven za GZDoom, u kombinaciji s ACS-om i DECORATE-om naslijeđenima od ZDooma, omogućuje visoku razinu modifikacije igrivosti i posebne značajke mapiranja. Mnoge mape i modovi, kao i neke totalne konverzije i samostalne igre, bile su ekskluzivne za GZDoom. To uključuje više od desetak dobitnika Cacoward nagrade.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom è un fork del porting sorgente ZDoom creato da Christoph Oelckers (Graf Zahl), che ne supervisiona ancora lo sviluppo. Rilasciato per la prima volta nel 2005, è disponibile in versioni per Windows, Linux e MacOS. GZDoom rimane un porting popolare grazie sia alla sua capacità di modding senza precedenti che alle ottimizzazioni grafiche per l'hardware moderno. In particolare, il linguaggio ZScript, esclusivo di GZDoom, combinato con ACS e DECORATE ereditati da ZDoom, consente un alto livello di modding del gameplay e speciali funzionalità di mappatura. Molte mappe e mod, oltre ad alcune conversioni totali e giochi stand-alone, sono stati esclusivi di GZDoom. Tra questi figurano oltre una dozzina di vincitori del Cacoward.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>GZDoomはChristoph Oelckers（Graf Zahl）が開発したZDoomソースポートのフォークであり、現在も彼が開発を統括している。2005年に初リリースされ、Windows、Linux、MacOS版が存在する。GZDoomは、前例のない改造機能と現代ハードウェア向けのグラフィック最適化の両面から、今なお人気の高いポートである。 特にGZDoom固有のZScript言語は、ZDoomから継承したACSとDECORATEと組み合わせることで、高度なゲームプレイ改造や特殊なマップ機能を実現します。数多くのマップや改造、さらには完全な変換作品やスタンドアロンゲームがGZDoom専用として開発されており、これには10を超えるカコウワード受賞作も含まれます。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom은 크리스토프 올커스(Graf Zahl)가 개발한 ZDoom 소스 포트의 포크 버전으로, 현재도 그가 개발을 총괄하고 있습니다. 2005년 처음 출시된 이후 Windows, Linux, MacOS용 버전이 존재합니다. GZDoom은 전례 없는 모딩 기능과 현대 하드웨어를 위한 그래픽 최적화로 여전히 인기 있는 포트로 자리매김하고 있습니다. 특히 GZDoom 고유의 ZScript 언어는 ZDoom에서 계승한 ACS 및 DECORATE와 결합되어 높은 수준의 게임플레이 모딩과 특수 매핑 기능을 가능케 합니다. 수많은 맵과 모드, 일부 토탈 컨버전 및 독립 실행형 게임이 GZDoom 전용으로 제작되었으며, 여기에는 10여 개가 넘는 Cacoward 수상작도 포함됩니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom is een afsplitsing van de ZDoom-bronport, gemaakt door Christoph Oelckers (Graf Zahl), die nog steeds toezicht houdt op de ontwikkeling ervan. Het werd voor het eerst uitgebracht in 2005 en er zijn versies voor Windows, Linux en MacOS. GZDoom blijft een populaire port vanwege zowel zijn ongekende moddingmogelijkheden als grafische optimalisaties voor moderne hardware. Met name de ZScript-taal, die uniek is voor GZDoom, in combinatie met ACS en DECORATE, overgenomen van ZDoom, maakt een hoog niveau van gameplay-modding en speciale mapping-functies mogelijk. Veel maps en mods, plus enkele totale conversies en stand-alone games, zijn exclusief voor GZDoom. Hieronder vallen meer dan een dozijn Cacoward-winnaars.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom jest rozwidleniem portu źródłowego ZDoom stworzonego przez Christopha Oelckersa (Graf Zahl), który nadal nadzoruje jego rozwój. Po raz pierwszy wydany w 2005 roku, posiada wersje dla systemów Windows, Linux i MacOS. GZDoom pozostaje popularnym portem zarówno ze względu na swoje bezprecedensowe możliwości modyfikacji, jak i optymalizacje graficzne dla nowoczesnego sprzętu. W szczególności język ZScript, unikalny dla GZDoom, w połączeniu z ACS i DECORATE odziedziczonymi po ZDoom, umożliwia modyfikację rozgrywki na wysokim poziomie oraz specjalne funkcje mapowania. Wiele map i modów, a także niektóre całkowite konwersje i samodzielne gry, są dostępne wyłącznie w GZDoom. Obejmuje to kilkunastu zwycięzców Cacoward.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom é um fork do port ZDoom criado por Christoph Oelckers (Graf Zahl), que ainda supervisiona seu desenvolvimento. Lançado pela primeira vez em 2005, ele tem versões para Windows, Linux e MacOS. O GZDoom continua sendo um port popular devido à sua capacidade de modding sem precedentes e otimizações gráficas para hardware moderno. Em particular, a linguagem ZScript exclusiva do GZDoom, combinada com ACS e DECORATE herdadas do ZDoom, permite um alto nível de modificação da jogabilidade e recursos especiais de mapeamento. Muitos mapas e mods, além de algumas conversões totais e jogos independentes, são exclusivos do GZDoom. Isso inclui mais de uma dúzia de vencedores do Cacoward.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom este o ramificație a portului sursă ZDoom creat de Christoph Oelckers (Graf Zahl), care încă supraveghează dezvoltarea acestuia. Lansat pentru prima dată în 2005, are versiuni pentru Windows, Linux și MacOS. GZDoom rămâne un port popular datorită capacității sale de modding fără precedent și optimizărilor grafice pentru hardware-ul modern. În special, limbajul ZScript unic pentru GZDoom, combinat cu ACS și DECORATE moștenite de la ZDoom, permite un nivel ridicat de modding al jocului și funcții speciale de mapare. Multe hărți și moduri, plus unele conversii totale și jocuri independente, au fost exclusive pentru GZDoom. Acestea includ peste o duzină de câștigători Cacoward.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom — это форк исходного порта ZDoom, созданный Кристофом Оэлкерсом (Graf Zahl), который по-прежнему курирует его разработку. Впервые выпущенный в 2005 году, он имеет версии для Windows, Linux и MacOS. GZDoom остается популярным портом благодаря как беспрецедентным возможностям модификации, так и графической оптимизации для современного оборудования. В частности, язык ZScript, уникальный для GZDoom, в сочетании с ACS и DECORATE, унаследованными от ZDoom, обеспечивает высокий уровень модификации игрового процесса и специальные функции картографирования. Многие карты и моды, а также некоторые полные конверсии и автономные игры были эксклюзивными для GZDoom. Сюда входит более дюжины победителей Cacoward.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom је форк ZDoom портa изворног кода који је креирао Кристоф Оелкерс (Graf Zahl), који и даље надгледа његов развој. Први пут објављен 2005. године, има верзије за Windows, Linux и MacOS. GZDoom остаје популаран порт због својих невиђених могућности модирања и графичких оптимизација за савремени хардвер. Посебно, језик ZScript, јединствен за GZDoom, у комбинацији са ACS и DECORATE наслеђеним од ZDoom-а, омогућава висок ниво модификације гејмплеја и посебне функције мапирања. Многе мапе и модови, као и неке тотал конверзије и самосталне игре, биле су ексклузивне за GZDoom. То укључује преко десетак добитника Cacoward награде.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom är en fork av ZDoom-källporten som skapats av Christoph Oelckers (Graf Zahl), som fortfarande övervakar dess utveckling. Den släpptes första gången 2005 och finns i versioner för Windows, Linux och MacOS. GZDoom är fortfarande en populär port tack vare både dess oöverträffade moddingmöjligheter och grafiska optimeringar för modern hårdvara. I synnerhet möjliggör det GZDoom-unika språket ZScript, i kombination med ACS och DECORATE som ärvts från ZDoom, en hög nivå av modding av spelupplevelsen och speciella kartläggningsfunktioner. Många kartor och mods, plus några totalomvandlingar och fristående spel, har varit exklusiva för GZDoom. Detta inkluderar över ett dussin Cacoward-vinnare.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>GZDoom是由Christoph Oelckers（Graf Zahl）创建的ZDoom源端口分支，他至今仍负责其开发工作。该项目于2005年首次发布，提供Windows、Linux和MacOS版本。凭借其前所未有的模组支持能力以及针对现代硬件的图形优化，GZDoom始终保持着广泛的流行度。 尤其值得一提的是，GZDoom独有的ZScript语言结合自ZDoom继承的ACS与DECORATE系统，实现了高度的游戏玩法修改与特殊地图功能。众多地图模组、部分全转换模组及独立游戏均专为GZDoom开发，其中包含十余部Cacoward获奖作品。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
