<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Hydra Castle Labyrinth</systemName>
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, originally Meikyuujou Hydra, is a freeware Indie platformer developed by E. Hashimoto, a.k.a. Buster, and released on his website. The original game was entirely in Japanese, but saw a translation patch months after its original creation.

The game hearkens back to early "Metroidvania" games like Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious and Legacy of the Wizard: the player explores an immense maze-like dungeon, collecting tools and keys that allow them to proceed deeper. Certain areas are cordoned off from the main dungeon area, and each presents a more linear zone with a boss at the end. The player can find new equipment to make themselves stronger as well.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>E. Hashimoto</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>2011</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-port}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth، المعروف في الأصل باسم Meikyuujou Hydra، هو لعبة منصات مستقلة مجانية طورها E. Hashimoto، المعروف باسم Buster، وتم إصدارها على موقعه الإلكتروني. كانت اللعبة الأصلية باللغة اليابانية بالكامل، ولكن تم إصدار تصحيح ترجمة لها بعد أشهر من إنشائها الأصلي.

تستحضر اللعبة ألعاب "Metroidvania" القديمة مثل Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious و Legacy of the Wizard: حيث يستكشف اللاعب زنزانة ضخمة تشبه المتاهة، ويجمع الأدوات والمفاتيح التي تسمح له بالتقدم إلى أعماقها. بعض المناطق معزولة عن منطقة الزنزانة الرئيسية، وتقدم كل منها منطقة أكثر خطية مع وجود زعيم في نهايتها. يمكن للاعب العثور على معدات جديدة لتقوية نفسه.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, izvorno Meikyuujou Hydra, je besplatni indie platformer koji je razvio E. Hashimoto, poznat i kao Buster, i objavljen na njegovoj web stranici. Originalna igra je bila u potpunosti na japanskom, ali je nekoliko mjeseci nakon izvorne kreacije dobila prevodilački patch.

Igra podsjeća na rane "Metroidvania" igre poput Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious i Legacy of the Wizard: igrač istražuje ogroman labirint, prikupljajući alate i ključeve koji mu omogućavaju da prodre dublje. Određena područja su odvojena od glavnog labirinta, a svako od njih predstavlja linearniju zonu s bossom na kraju. Igrač također može pronaći novu opremu kako bi postao jači.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, originalment Meikyuujou Hydra, és un joc de plataformes indie gratuït desenvolupat per E. Hashimoto, també conegut com a Buster, i publicat al seu lloc web. El joc original era íntegrament en japonès, però mesos després de la seva creació es va publicar un pedaç de traducció.

El joc evoca els primers jocs "Metroidvania" com Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious i Legacy of the Wizard: el jugador explora una immensa masmorra de tipus laberint, recollint eines i claus que li permeten avançar més endins. Certes àrees estan tancades de la masmorra principal i cadascuna presenta una zona més lineal amb un cap al final. El jugador també pot trobar nou equipament per fer-se més fort.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, ursprünglich Meikyuujou Hydra, ist ein Freeware-Indie-Plattformspiel, das von E. Hashimoto, alias Buster, entwickelt und auf seiner Website veröffentlicht wurde. Das Originalspiel war vollständig auf Japanisch, wurde jedoch einige Monate nach seiner Veröffentlichung mit einem Übersetzungspatch versehen.

Das Spiel erinnert an frühe „Metroidvania”-Spiele wie Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious und Legacy of the Wizard: Der Spieler erkundet einen riesigen, labyrinthartigen Dungeon und sammelt Werkzeuge und Schlüssel, mit denen er tiefer vordringen kann. Bestimmte Bereiche sind vom Hauptbereich des Dungeons abgetrennt und stellen jeweils eine linearere Zone dar, an deren Ende ein Boss wartet. Der Spieler kann auch neue Ausrüstung finden, um sich selbst zu stärken.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, originalmente Meikyuujou Hydra, es un juego indie gratuito de plataformas desarrollado por E. Hashimoto, también conocido como Buster, y publicado en su sitio web. El juego original estaba completamente en japonés, pero meses después de su creación se publicó un parche de traducción.

El juego se remonta a los primeros juegos «Metroidvania», como Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious y Legacy of the Wizard: el jugador explora una inmensa mazmorra laberíntica, recogiendo herramientas y llaves que le permiten avanzar más profundamente. Ciertas áreas están acordonadas del área principal de la mazmorra, y cada una presenta una zona más lineal con un jefe al final. El jugador también puede encontrar nuevo equipo para hacerse más fuerte.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, à l'origine Meikyuujou Hydra, est un jeu de plateforme indépendant gratuit développé par E. Hashimoto, alias Buster, et publié sur son site web. Le jeu original était entièrement en japonais, mais un patch de traduction a été publié quelques mois après sa création.

Le jeu rappelle les premiers jeux « Metroidvania » tels que Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious et Legacy of the Wizard : le joueur explore un immense donjon en forme de labyrinthe, collectant des outils et des clés qui lui permettent d'avancer plus profondément. Certaines zones sont isolées du donjon principal et chacune présente une zone plus linéaire avec un boss à la fin. Le joueur peut également trouver de nouveaux équipements pour se rendre plus fort.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, izvorno Meikyuujou Hydra, besplatni je indie platformer koji je razvio E. Hashimoto, poznat i kao Buster, i objavljen na njegovoj web stranici. Izvorna igra bila je u potpunosti na japanskom, ali je nekoliko mjeseci nakon izvorne izrade dobila prijevod.

Igra podsjeća na rane "Metroidvania" igre poput Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious i Legacy of the Wizard: igrač istražuje golemu tamnicu nalik labirintu, prikupljajući alate i ključeve koji mu omogućuju da prodre dublje. Određena područja odvojena su od glavne tamnice, a svako predstavlja linearniju zonu s bossom na kraju. Igrač također može pronaći novu opremu kako bi postao jači.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, originariamente Meikyuujou Hydra, è un platform indie freeware sviluppato da E. Hashimoto, alias Buster, e pubblicato sul suo sito web. Il gioco originale era interamente in giapponese, ma alcuni mesi dopo la sua creazione è stata rilasciata una patch di traduzione.

Il gioco richiama i primi giochi "Metroidvania" come Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious e Legacy of the Wizard: il giocatore esplora un immenso dungeon simile a un labirinto, raccogliendo strumenti e chiavi che gli consentono di procedere più in profondità. Alcune aree sono isolate dall'area principale del dungeon e ciascuna presenta una zona più lineare con un boss alla fine. Il giocatore può anche trovare nuove attrezzature per diventare più forte.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>ヒドラ城の迷宮（原題：迷宮城ヒドラ）は、E.ハシモト（別名：バスター）が開発し、自身のウェブサイトで公開したフリーウェアのインディー・プラットフォーマーである。オリジナル版は完全に日本語で制作されたが、数か月後に翻訳パッチが公開された。

本作は『ナイトメアII ガリウスの迷宮』や『レガシー・オブ・ザ・ウィザード』といった初期の「メトロイドヴァニア」作品を彷彿とさせる。プレイヤーは巨大な迷宮のようなダンジョンを探索し、道具や鍵を集めて奥深くへ進む。特定のエリアはメインダンジョンから隔離されており、それぞれがより直線的な構造で、最後にボスが待ち受ける。新たな装備を見つけて自身を強化することも可能だ。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>하이드라 성 미궁(原題: 迷宮城ハイドラ)은 E. 하시모토(일명 버스터)가 개발하여 자신의 웹사이트에 공개한 프리웨어 인디 플랫포머 게임이다. 원작은 전편 일본어로 제작되었으나, 출시 수개월 후 번역 패치가 적용되었다.

이 게임은 '나이트메어 II: 갈리우스의 미궁'이나 '마법사의 유산'과 같은 초기 '메트로배니아' 게임들을 연상케 합니다. 플레이어는 거대한 미로 같은 던전을 탐험하며, 더 깊숙이 진행할 수 있게 해주는 도구와 열쇠를 수집합니다. 특정 구역들은 메인 던전 구역에서 차단되어 있으며, 각각은 끝에 보스가 있는 보다 직선적인 구역을 제공합니다. 플레이어는 자신을 더 강하게 만들어줄 새로운 장비도 찾을 수 있습니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, oorspronkelijk Meikyuujou Hydra, is een freeware indie-platformgame ontwikkeld door E. Hashimoto, alias Buster, en uitgebracht op zijn website. De originele game was volledig in het Japans, maar enkele maanden na de oorspronkelijke creatie verscheen er een vertaalpatch.

De game doet denken aan vroege "Metroidvania"-games zoals Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious en Legacy of the Wizard: de speler verkent een immense doolhofachtige kerker en verzamelt gereedschappen en sleutels waarmee hij dieper kan doordringen. Bepaalde gebieden zijn afgesloten van het hoofdgedeelte van de kerker en elk gebied is een meer lineaire zone met een eindbaas aan het einde. De speler kan ook nieuwe uitrusting vinden om zichzelf sterker te maken.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, pierwotnie Meikyuujou Hydra, to darmowa niezależna platformówka stworzona przez E. Hashimoto, znanego również jako Buster, i wydana na jego stronie internetowej. Oryginalna gra była w całości w języku japońskim, ale kilka miesięcy po jej stworzeniu pojawiła się łatka z tłumaczeniem.

Gra nawiązuje do wczesnych gier typu „Metroidvania”, takich jak Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious i Legacy of the Wizard: gracz eksploruje ogromny labirynt przypominający lochy, zbierając narzędzia i klucze, które pozwalają mu zapuścić się głębiej. Niektóre obszary są odgrodzone od głównej części lochów i każdy z nich stanowi bardziej liniową strefę, na końcu której znajduje się boss. Gracz może również znaleźć nowe wyposażenie, które pozwoli mu stać się silniejszym.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, originalmente Meikyuujou Hydra, é um jogo indie gratuito de plataforma desenvolvido por E. Hashimoto, também conhecido como Buster, e lançado em seu site. O jogo original era inteiramente em japonês, mas recebeu um patch de tradução meses após sua criação original.

O jogo remete aos primeiros jogos "Metroidvania", como Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious e Legacy of the Wizard: o jogador explora uma imensa masmorra em forma de labirinto, coletando ferramentas e chaves que lhe permitem avançar mais profundamente. Certas áreas são isoladas da área principal da masmorra, e cada uma apresenta uma zona mais linear com um chefe no final. O jogador também pode encontrar novos equipamentos para se tornar mais forte.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, inițial Meikyuujou Hydra, este un joc indie gratuit de tip platformer dezvoltat de E. Hashimoto, alias Buster, și lansat pe site-ul său web. Jocul original era în întregime în limba japoneză, dar a beneficiat de un patch de traducere la câteva luni după crearea sa inițială.

Jocul amintește de primele jocuri „Metroidvania”, precum Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious și Legacy of the Wizard: jucătorul explorează un imens labirint, colectând unelte și chei care îi permit să avanseze mai adânc. Anumite zone sunt izolate de zona principală a labirintului și fiecare prezintă o zonă mai liniară, cu un șef la final. Jucătorul poate găsi echipamente noi pentru a deveni mai puternic.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, первоначально Meikyuujou Hydra, — это бесплатная инди-игра в жанре платформер, разработанная E. Hashimoto, также известным как Buster, и выпущенная на его веб-сайте. Первоначально игра была полностью на японском языке, но через несколько месяцев после ее создания появился патч с переводом.

Игра напоминает ранние игры серии «Metroidvania», такие как Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious и Legacy of the Wizard: игрок исследует огромное лабиринтообразное подземелье, собирая инструменты и ключи, которые позволяют ему продвигаться все глубже. Некоторые области отгорожены от основной части подземелья и представляют собой более линейные зоны с боссом в конце. Игрок также может найти новое снаряжение, чтобы стать сильнее.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>Лавиринт замка Хидра, првобитно Meikyuujou Hydra, је бесплатни инди платформер који је развио Е. Хашимото, познат и као Бастер, и објављен на његовом веб-сајту. Оригинална игра је била у потпуности на јапанском, али је неколико месеци након њеног стварања добила закрпу за превод.

Игра подсећа на ране "Metroidvania" игре попут Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious и Legacy of the Wizard: играч истражује огроман лавиринтски тамница, прикупљајући алате и кључеве који му омогућавају да продре дубље. Одређена подручја су одвојена од главне тамнице, а свако представља линијску зону са босом на крају. Играч такође може пронаћи нову опрему да би постао јачи.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>Hydra Castle Labyrinth, ursprungligen Meikyuujou Hydra, är ett freeware-indieplattformsspel utvecklat av E. Hashimoto, alias Buster, och släppt på hans webbplats. Det ursprungliga spelet var helt på japanska, men fick en översättningspatch några månader efter att det skapades.

Spelet påminner om tidiga "Metroidvania"-spel som Knightmare II: The Maze of Galious och Legacy of the Wizard: spelaren utforskar en enorm labyrintliknande fängelsehåla och samlar verktyg och nycklar som gör det möjligt att ta sig längre in. Vissa områden är avskärmade från huvudfängelsehålan och varje område är mer linjärt med en boss i slutet. Spelaren kan också hitta ny utrustning för att bli starkare.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>《九头蛇城迷宫》（原名：迷宫城九头蛇）是由E. Hashimoto（又名Buster）开发并发布于其个人网站的免费独立平台游戏。原版游戏全程采用日语界面，但数月后推出了翻译补丁。

本作承袭了《骑士噩梦II：加里乌斯的迷宫》与《巫师的遗产》等早期"银河战士恶魔城"类游戏的精髓：玩家需探索庞大的迷宫式地下城，收集工具与钥匙以深入探索。部分区域与主迷宫隔绝，形成线性关卡结构，末端设有头目战。玩家还可获取新装备提升自身实力。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
