<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Hurrican</systemName>
    <systemDescription>Inspired by the epic Turrican game series, Hurrican stays by all means true to the original game while still being highly innovative.
Blast your way through myriads of enemies, explore the secrets of nine massive worlds and collect tons of powerups to increase your firepower in this highly explosive Run and Gun arcade game.

Hurrican is THE ultimate “Turrican Mega-Mix”, taking ideas from several installements of the original franchise while at the same time expanding on it’s universe.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Poke53280</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1990</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-port}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>مستوحاة من سلسلة ألعاب Turrican الملحمية، تظل Hurrican وفية تمامًا للعبة الأصلية مع الحفاظ على طابعها المبتكر للغاية.
شق طريقك عبر أعداد لا حصر لها من الأعداء، واستكشف أسرار تسعة عوالم ضخمة، واجمع الكثير من التعزيزات لزيادة قوتك النارية في هذه اللعبة المثيرة للغاية من نوع Run and Gun. Hurrican هي "Turrican Mega-Mix" النهائية، حيث تستمد أفكارها من عدة أجزاء من السلسلة الأصلية، بينما توسع في الوقت نفسه عالمها.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>Inspirisan epskom serijom igara Turrican, Hurrican ostaje u svakom pogledu vjeran originalnoj igri, a istovremeno je izuzetno inovativan.
Probij se kroz mnoštvo neprijatelja, istraži tajne devet masivnih svjetova i sakupi tone pojačanja da povećaš vatrenu moć u ovoj izuzetno eksplozivnoj Run and Gun arkadnoj igri. Hurrican je ultimativni "Turrican Mega-Mix", koji crpi ideje iz nekoliko nastavaka originalne franšize, a istovremeno proširuje njen univerzum.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>Inspirat en l'èpica sèrie de jocs Turrican, Hurrican es manté fidel al joc original en tots els sentits, tot i ser altament innovador.
Fes-te camí disparant a través de miriades d'enemics, explora els secrets de nou mons massius i recull tones de potenciadors per augmentar la teva potència de foc en aquest joc d'arcade Run and Gun altament explosiu. Hurrican és LA definitiva "Turrican Mega-Mix", prenent idees de diverses entregues de la franquícia original mentre alhora en amplia l'univers.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Inspiriert von der epischen Turrican-Spieleserie bleibt Hurrican dem Originalspiel in jeder Hinsicht treu und ist dennoch äußerst innovativ.
Bahnen Sie sich Ihren Weg durch unzählige Feinde, erkunden Sie die Geheimnisse von neun riesigen Welten und sammeln Sie jede Menge Power-ups, um Ihre Feuerkraft in diesem hoch explosiven Run-and-Gun-Arcade-Spiel zu erhöhen. Hurrican ist DER ultimative „Turrican Mega-Mix“, der Ideen aus mehreren Teilen der Originalreihe aufgreift und gleichzeitig deren Universum erweitert.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>Inspirado en la épica serie de juegos Turrican, Hurrican se mantiene fiel al juego original sin dejar de ser muy innovador.
Ábrete paso a través de innumerables enemigos, explora los secretos de nueve mundos gigantescos y recoge montones de potenciadores para aumentar tu potencia de fuego en este juego arcade de correr y disparar altamente explosivo. Hurrican es EL «Turrican Mega-Mix» definitivo, que toma ideas de varias entregas de la franquicia original y, al mismo tiempo, amplía su universo.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>Inspiré de la série épique Turrican, Hurrican reste fidèle au jeu original tout en étant très innovant.
Frayez-vous un chemin à travers une myriade d'ennemis, explorez les secrets de neuf mondes gigantesques et collectez des tonnes de bonus pour augmenter votre puissance de feu dans ce jeu d'arcade Run and Gun hautement explosif. Hurrican est LE « Turrican Mega-Mix » ultime, s'inspirant de plusieurs opus de la franchise originale tout en élargissant son univers.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>Inspiriran epskom serijom igara Turrican, Hurrican ostaje u svakom pogledu vjeran originalnoj igri, a istovremeno je iznimno inovativan.
Probij se kroz mnoštvo neprijatelja, istraži tajne devet golemih svjetova i sakupi tone pojačanja kako bi povećao vatrenu moć u ovoj izrazito eksplozivnoj arkadnoj igri tipa Run and Gun. Hurrican je ultimativni "Turrican Mega-Mix", koji crpi ideje iz nekoliko nastavaka originalne franšize, a istovremeno proširuje njezin svemir.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Ispirato all'epica serie di giochi Turrican, Hurrican rimane fedele al gioco originale pur essendo altamente innovativo.
Fatti strada tra miriadi di nemici, esplora i segreti di nove mondi enormi e raccogli tantissimi potenziamenti per aumentare la tua potenza di fuoco in questo gioco arcade Run and Gun altamente esplosivo. Hurrican è IL "Turrican Mega-Mix" definitivo, che prende spunto da diversi capitoli della serie originale e allo stesso tempo ne amplia l'universo.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>伝説のTurricanシリーズに着想を得たHurricanは、あらゆる面で原作に忠実でありながら、革新性を兼ね備えています。
無数の敵を撃ち抜け、9つの広大な世界の秘密を探索し、大量のパワーアップアイテムを集めて火力を強化せよ。この爆発的なラン＆ガン・アーケードゲームで。Hurricanは究極の「Turricanメガミックス」であり、オリジナルシリーズの複数作品からアイデアを取り入れつつ、その世界をさらに拡大している。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>에픽한 터리칸 게임 시리즈에서 영감을 받은 허리케인은 원작 게임에 충실하면서도 혁신적인 면모를 보여줍니다.
수많은 적을 뚫고 나아가며, 아홉 개의 거대한 세계에 숨겨진 비밀을 탐험하고, 화력을 강화할 수 있는 수많은 파워업을 수집하세요. 이 폭발적인 런 앤 건 아케이드 게임에서! 허리케인은 오리지널 프랜차이즈의 여러 작품에서 아이디어를 차용하면서도 동시에 그 세계관을 확장한, 궁극의 "터리칸 메가 믹스"입니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>Hurrican is geïnspireerd op de epische Turrican-gameserie en blijft in alle opzichten trouw aan het originele spel, maar is tegelijkertijd zeer innovatief.
Baan je een weg door talloze vijanden, ontdek de geheimen van negen enorme werelden en verzamel talloze power-ups om je vuurkracht te vergroten in dit explosieve Run and Gun-arcadespel. Hurrican is DE ultieme "Turrican Mega-Mix", die ideeën uit verschillende delen van de originele franchise overneemt en tegelijkertijd het universum ervan uitbreidt.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Zainspirowana epicką serią gier Turrican, gra Hurrican pozostaje wierna oryginałowi, a jednocześnie jest bardzo innowacyjna.
Przebij się przez rzesze wrogów, odkrywaj sekrety dziewięciu ogromnych światów i zbieraj mnóstwo ulepszeń, aby zwiększyć swoją siłę ognia w tej wybuchowej grze zręcznościowej typu „run and gun”. Hurrican to najlepszy „Turrican Mega-Mix”, czerpiący pomysły z kilku części oryginalnej serii, a jednocześnie rozszerzający jej świat.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>Inspirado na épica série de jogos Turrican, Hurrican mantém-se fiel ao jogo original, mas continua a ser altamente inovador.
Abra caminho através de miríades de inimigos, explore os segredos de nove mundos enormes e recolha toneladas de powerups para aumentar o seu poder de fogo neste jogo arcade Run and Gun altamente explosivo. Hurrican é O "Turrican Mega-Mix" definitivo, tirando ideias de várias instalações da franquia original, ao mesmo tempo que expande o seu universo.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Inspirat de seria epică de jocuri Turrican, Hurrican rămâne fidel jocului original, fiind în același timp extrem de inovator.
Croiește-ți drum prin miile de inamici, explorează secretele a nouă lumi uriașe și adună tone de bonusuri pentru a-ți crește puterea de foc în acest joc arcade extrem de exploziv de tip Run and Gun. Hurrican este „Turrican Mega-Mix” suprem, preluând idei din mai multe versiuni ale francizei originale și extinzând în același timp universul acesteia.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Вдохновленная эпической серией игр Turrican, Hurrican остается верной оригинальной игре, но при этом является весьма инновационной.
Проложите себе путь через мириады врагов, исследуйте секреты девяти огромных миров и соберите тонны бонусов, чтобы увеличить свою огневую мощь в этой взрывной аркадной игре в жанре «беги и стреляй». Hurrican — это THE ultimate «Turrican Mega-Mix», в котором использованы идеи из нескольких частей оригинальной франшизы и одновременно расширена ее вселенная.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>Инспирисан епском серијом игара Turrican, Hurrican на сваки начин остаје веран оригиналној игри, а истовремено је изузетно иновативан.
Пробијте се кроз мноштво непријатеља, истражите тајне девет масивних светова и сакупите тоне појачања да повећате вашу ватрену моћ у овој изузетно експлозивној аркадној игри трчања и пуцања. Hurrican је ВРХУНСКИ "Turrican Mega-Mix", који узима идеје из неколико наставaka оригиналне франшизе, а истовремено проширује њен универзум.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>Hurrican är inspirerat av den episka spelserien Turrican och är helt troget originalet samtidigt som det är mycket innovativt.
Kämpa dig igenom myriader av fiender, utforska hemligheterna i nio enorma världar och samla massor av powerups för att öka din eldkraft i detta explosiva Run and Gun-arkadspel. Hurrican är DEN ultimata "Turrican Mega-Mix", som hämtar idéer från flera delar av den ursprungliga serien samtidigt som den utvidgar dess universum.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>受史诗级Turrican游戏系列启发，《Hurrican》在忠于原作精髓的同时，仍展现出高度创新性。
在这款高爆性的跑酷射击街机游戏中，你将轰炸无数敌人，探索九个广阔世界的秘密，收集海量强化道具提升火力。Hurrican堪称终极"Turrican超级混搭版"，既汲取了原系列多部作品的精髓，又拓展了其宇宙疆域。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
