<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Laser 310</systemName>
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (also known as VZ-310). It is an all-in-one computer with a Z80, 3.54 MHz microprocessor. VTech (short for Video Technology Ltd.) was a Hong Kong electronics company that also sold the Laser in other countries through various retail chains. The Laser 310 was sold by Dick Smith Electronics , for example, so instead of VTech the Laser 310 was then called the Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 or VZ-310 for short (sold from 1983 to 1989). The Laser 310 is comparable to the previous model Laser200 (VZ-200), except for a modified keyboard and a rather unusual memory size of 18 KiB (2 KiB of which is video RAM) and is fully compatible with it. The machine ran basic games on the cartridge, such as Hoppy (Frogger's version), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) and Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>VTech</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1983</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-computer}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (المعروف أيضًا باسم VZ-310). وهو جهاز كمبيوتر متكامل مزود بمعالج Z80 بسرعة 3.54 ميجاهرتز. VTech (اختصار لـ Video Technology Ltd.) كانت شركة إلكترونيات في هونغ كونغ قامت أيضًا ببيع جهاز Laser في بلدان أخرى من خلال سلاسل متاجر التجزئة المختلفة. تم بيع Laser 310 بواسطة Dick Smith Electronics ، على سبيل المثال، لذا بدلاً من VTech، أُطلق على Laser 310 اسم Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 أو VZ-310 باختصار (تم بيعه من 1983 إلى 1989). يمكن مقارنة Laser 310 بالطراز السابق Laser200 (VZ-200)، باستثناء لوحة مفاتيح معدلة وحجم ذاكرة غير عادي يبلغ 18 كيلوبايت (2 كيلوبايت منها ذاكرة وصول عشوائي للفيديو) وهو متوافق تمامًا معها. كان الجهاز يشغل الألعاب الأساسية على الكارتريدج، مثل Hoppy (نسخة Frogger) و Cosmic Rescue (Scramble) و VZ Invaders (Space Invaders) و Dawn Patrol (Chopper) و Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (poznat i kao VZ-310). To je sve-u-jednom računar sa Z80 mikroprocesorom od 3,54 MHz. VTech (skraćeno od Video Technology Ltd.) bila je hongkonška elektronička kompanija koja je Laser prodavala i u drugim zemljama putem različitih maloprodajnih lanaca. Laser 310 je, na primjer, prodavao Dick Smith Electronics, pa se umjesto VTech nazivao Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 ili skraćeno VZ-310 (prodavan od 1983. do 1989.). Laser 310 je uporediv s prethodnim modelom Laser200 (VZ-200), osim po modificiranoj tastaturi i prilično neobičnoj veličini memorije od 18 KiB (od čega je 2 KiB video RAM), i s njim je u potpunosti kompatibilan. Uređaj je pokretao osnovne igre na kartridžu, kao što su Hoppy (verzija igre Frogger), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) i Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (també conegut com a VZ-310). És un ordinador tot en un amb un microprocessador Z80 de 3,54 MHz. VTech (acrònim de Video Technology Ltd.) era una empresa d'electrònica de Hong Kong que també venia el Laser en altres països a través de diverses cadenes de venda al detall. El Laser 310 es va vendre, per exemple, a través de Dick Smith Electronics; així, en lloc de VTech, el Laser 310 es va anomenar Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 o, abreujat, VZ-310 (venut entre 1983 i 1989). El Laser 310 és comparable al model anterior, el Laser200 (VZ-200), excepte per un teclat modificat i una mida de memòria força inusual de 18 KiB (dels quals 2 KiB són de RAM de vídeo), i és totalment compatible amb ell. La màquina executava jocs bàsics en cartutx, com ara Hoppy (la versió de Frogger), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) i Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (auch bekannt als VZ-310). Es handelt sich um einen All-in-One-Computer mit einem Z80-Mikroprozessor mit 3,54 MHz. VTech (kurz für Video Technology Ltd.) war ein Elektronikunternehmen aus Hongkong, das den Laser auch in anderen Ländern über verschiedene Einzelhandelsketten verkaufte. Der Laser 310 wurde beispielsweise von Dick Smith Electronics verkauft, sodass der Laser 310 statt VTech dann Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 oder kurz VZ-310 hieß (verkauft von 1983 bis 1989). Der Laser 310 ist mit dem Vorgängermodell Laser200 (VZ-200) vergleichbar, abgesehen von einer modifizierten Tastatur und einer eher ungewöhnlichen Speichergröße von 18 KiB (davon 2 KiB Video-RAM) und ist vollständig kompatibel mit diesem. Das Gerät führte einfache Spiele auf der Kassette aus, wie z. B. Hoppy (Frogger-Version), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) und Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (también conocido como VZ-310). Es un ordenador todo en uno con un microprocesador Z80 de 3,54 MHz. VTech (abreviatura de Video Technology Ltd.) era una empresa de electrónica de Hong Kong que también vendía el Laser en otros países a través de diversas cadenas minoristas. El Laser 310 fue vendido por Dick Smith Electronics, por ejemplo, por lo que en lugar de VTech, el Laser 310 pasó a llamarse Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 o VZ-310 para abreviar (vendido entre 1983 y 1989). El Laser 310 es comparable al modelo anterior Laser200 (VZ-200), excepto por un teclado modificado y un tamaño de memoria bastante inusual de 18 KiB (2 KiB de los cuales son RAM de vídeo), y es totalmente compatible con él. La máquina ejecutaba juegos básicos en el cartucho, como Hoppy (versión de Frogger), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) y Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (également connu sous le nom de VZ-310). Il s'agit d'un ordinateur tout-en-un équipé d'un microprocesseur Z80 cadencé à 3,54 MHz. VTech (abréviation de Video Technology Ltd.) était une entreprise d'électronique hongkongaise qui commercialisait également le Laser dans d'autres pays par l'intermédiaire de diverses chaînes de magasins. Le Laser 310 était vendu par Dick Smith Electronics, par exemple, et au lieu de VTech, le Laser 310 était alors appelé Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 ou VZ-310 en abrégé (vendu de 1983 à 1989). Le Laser 310 est comparable au modèle précédent, le Laser200 (VZ-200), à l'exception d'un clavier modifié et d'une taille de mémoire plutôt inhabituelle de 18 Ko (dont 2 Ko de RAM vidéo), et il est entièrement compatible avec celui-ci. La machine exécutait des jeux basiques sur cartouche, tels que Hoppy (version de Frogger), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) et Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (poznat i kao VZ-310). To je sve-u-jednom računalo s mikroračunalom Z80 od 3,54 MHz. VTech (skraćeno od Video Technology Ltd.) bila je hongkonška elektronička tvrtka koja je Laser prodavala i u drugim zemljama putem raznih maloprodajnih lanaca. Laser 310 prodavao je, na primjer, Dick Smith Electronics, pa se umjesto VTecha nazivao Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 ili skraćeno VZ-310 (prodavao se od 1983. do 1989.). Laser 310 usporediv je s prethodnim modelom Laser200 (VZ-200), osim po modificiranoj tipkovnici i prilično neobičnoj veličini memorije od 18 KiB (od čega je 2 KiB video RAM), te je s njim u potpunosti kompatibilan. Uređaj je pokretao osnovne igre na kaseti, kao što su Hoppy (verzija igre Frogger), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) i Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (noto anche come VZ-310). Si tratta di un computer all-in-one con microprocessore Z80 da 3,54 MHz. VTech (abbreviazione di Video Technology Ltd.) era un'azienda elettronica di Hong Kong che vendeva il Laser anche in altri paesi attraverso varie catene di negozi al dettaglio. Il Laser 310 era venduto da Dick Smith Electronics, ad esempio, quindi invece di VTech il Laser 310 era chiamato Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 o VZ-310 in breve (venduto dal 1983 al 1989). Il Laser 310 è paragonabile al modello precedente Laser200 (VZ-200), tranne che per una tastiera modificata e una dimensione di memoria piuttosto insolita di 18 KiB (di cui 2 KiB di RAM video) ed è completamente compatibile con esso. La macchina eseguiva giochi di base su cartuccia, come Hoppy (versione di Frogger), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) e Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310（別名VZ-310）。Z80、3.54MHzマイクロプロセッサを搭載したオールインワンコンピュータである。VTech（Video Technology Ltd.の略称）は香港の電子機器メーカーであり、様々な小売チェーンを通じて他国でもLaserを販売していた。 例えばディック・スミス・エレクトロニクスでは、VTechではなく「ディック・スミス・レーザー VZ-310」または略称「VZ-310」として販売されました（1983年から1989年まで）。 レーザー310は、キーボードの改良と18KiB（うち2KiBはビデオRAM）というやや特殊なメモリ容量を除けば、前モデルであるレーザー200（VZ-200）と同等であり、完全互換性を有しています。 このマシンはカートリッジでベーシックゲーム（ホッピー（フロッガー版）、コズミック・レスキュー（スクランブル）、VZインベーダー（スペースインベーダー）、ドーン・パトロール（チョッパー）、ムーン・パトロールなど）を実行した。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (VZ-310으로도 알려짐). Z80, 3.54 MHz 마이크로프로세서를 탑재한 올인원 컴퓨터입니다. VTech(Video Technology Ltd.의 약칭)는 홍콩의 전자제품 회사로, 다양한 유통망을 통해 다른 국가에서도 Laser를 판매했습니다. 예를 들어, 디크 스미스 일렉트로닉스(Dick Smith Electronics)는 레이저 310을 판매했으며, 따라서 VTech 대신 레이저 310은 디크 스미스 레이저 VZ-310 또는 줄여서 VZ-310으로 불렸습니다(1983년부터 1989년까지 판매됨). 레이저 310은 키보드 변경과 다소 특이한 18KiB 메모리 용량(이 중 2KiB는 비디오 RAM)을 제외하면 이전 모델 레이저200(VZ-200)과 비교 가능하며, 완전히 호환됩니다. 이 기기는 카트리지 기반의 베이직 게임을 실행했으며, 대표적으로 호피(프로거 버전), 코스믹 레스큐(스크램블), VZ 인베이더스(스페이스 인베이더), 던 패트롤(쵸퍼), 문 패트롤 등이 있습니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (ook bekend als VZ-310). Het is een alles-in-één computer met een Z80, 3,54 MHz microprocessor. VTech (afkorting van Video Technology Ltd.) was een elektronicafabrikant uit Hongkong die de Laser ook in andere landen verkocht via verschillende winkelketens. De Laser 310 werd bijvoorbeeld verkocht door Dick Smith Electronics, dus in plaats van VTech werd de Laser 310 toen de Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 of kortweg VZ-310 genoemd (verkocht van 1983 tot 1989). De Laser 310 is vergelijkbaar met het vorige model Laser200 (VZ-200), behalve dat het toetsenbord is aangepast en het geheugen met 18 KiB (waarvan 2 KiB videogeheugen) vrij ongebruikelijk is, en is volledig compatibel met dat model. De machine draaide eenvoudige spellen op de cartridge, zoals Hoppy (Frogger's versie), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) en Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (znany również jako VZ-310). Jest to komputer typu „wszystko w jednym” z mikroprocesorem Z80 o częstotliwości 3,54 MHz. VTech (skrót od Video Technology Ltd.) była hongkońską firmą elektroniczną, która sprzedawała komputer Laser również w innych krajach za pośrednictwem różnych sieci detalicznych. Laser 310 był sprzedawany na przykład przez Dick Smith Electronics, więc zamiast VTech, Laser 310 był wówczas nazywany Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 lub w skrócie VZ-310 (sprzedawany w latach 1983–1989). Laser 310 jest porównywalny z poprzednim modelem Laser200 (VZ-200), z wyjątkiem zmodyfikowanej klawiatury i dość nietypowej pojemności pamięci wynoszącej 18 KiB (z czego 2 KiB to pamięć RAM wideo) i jest z nim w pełni kompatybilny. Urządzenie obsługiwało podstawowe gry na kartridżach, takie jak Hoppy (wersja Frogger), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) i Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (também conhecido como VZ-310). É um computador multifuncional com um microprocessador Z80 de 3,54 MHz. A VTech (abreviação de Video Technology Ltd.) era uma empresa de eletrônicos de Hong Kong que também vendia o Laser em outros países por meio de várias redes de varejo. O Laser 310 era vendido pela Dick Smith Electronics, por exemplo, então, em vez de VTech, o Laser 310 era chamado de Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 ou VZ-310 para abreviar (vendido de 1983 a 1989). O Laser 310 é comparável ao modelo anterior Laser200 (VZ-200), exceto por um teclado modificado e um tamanho de memória bastante incomum de 18 KiB (2 KiB dos quais são RAM de vídeo) e é totalmente compatível com ele. A máquina rodava jogos básicos no cartucho, como Hoppy (versão do Frogger), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) e Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (cunoscut și sub numele de VZ-310). Este un computer all-in-one cu un microprocesor Z80, 3,54 MHz. VTech (prescurtarea de la Video Technology Ltd.) era o companie de electronice din Hong Kong care vindea Laser și în alte țări prin diverse lanțuri de magazine. Laser 310 a fost vândut de Dick Smith Electronics, de exemplu, astfel încât, în loc de VTech, Laser 310 a fost numit Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 sau VZ-310 pe scurt (vândut între 1983 și 1989). Laser 310 este comparabil cu modelul anterior Laser200 (VZ-200), cu excepția unei tastaturi modificate și a unei dimensiuni de memorie destul de neobișnuite de 18 KiB (din care 2 KiB sunt RAM video) și este pe deplin compatibil cu acesta. Aparatul rula jocuri de bază pe cartuș, precum Hoppy (versiunea Frogger), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) și Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (также известный как VZ-310). Это универсальный компьютер с микропроцессором Z80, 3,54 МГц. VTech (сокращение от Video Technology Ltd.) была гонконгской электронной компанией, которая также продавала Laser в других странах через различные розничные сети. Laser 310 продавался, например, компанией Dick Smith Electronics, поэтому вместо VTech Laser 310 тогда назывался Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 или сокращенно VZ-310 (продавался с 1983 по 1989 год). Laser 310 сравним с предыдущей моделью Laser200 (VZ-200), за исключением модифицированной клавиатуры и довольно необычного объема памяти в 18 КиБ (из которых 2 КиБ — видеопамять), и полностью совместим с ней. На компьютере можно было запускать простые игры с картриджа, такие как Hoppy (версия Frogger), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) и Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (познат и као VZ-310). То је све-у-једном рачунар са Z80 микропроцесором од 3,54 MHz. VTech (скраћено од Video Technology Ltd.) била је хонгконшка компанија за електронику која је такође продавала Laser у другим земљама преко различитих малопродајних ланца. Ласер 310 је, на пример, продавао Дик Смит Електроникс, па је уместо VTech називан Дик Смит Ласер VZ-310 или скраћено VZ-310 (продавао се од 1983. до 1989. године). Ласер 310 је упоредив са претходним моделом Ласер200 (VZ-200), осим по модификованој тастатури и прилично необичној величини меморије од 18 KiB (од којих је 2 KiB видео RAM), и у потпуности је компатибилан са њим. Машина је изводила основне игре на касети, као што су Hoppy (верзија игре Frogger), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) и Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>VTech Laser 310 (även känd som VZ-310). Det är en allt-i-ett-dator med en Z80-mikroprocessor på 3,54 MHz. VTech (förkortning för Video Technology Ltd.) var ett elektronikföretag i Hongkong som även sålde Laser i andra länder genom olika detaljhandelskedjor. Laser 310 såldes till exempel av Dick Smith Electronics, så istället för VTech kallades Laser 310 då Dick Smith Laser VZ-310 eller kort och gott VZ-310 (såldes från 1983 till 1989). Laser 310 är jämförbar med den tidigare modellen Laser200 (VZ-200), förutom ett modifierat tangentbord och en ganska ovanlig minnesstorlek på 18 KiB (varav 2 KiB är videominne) och är helt kompatibel med den. Maskinen körde enkla spel på kassetten, såsom Hoppy (Frogger-versionen), Cosmic Rescue (Scramble), VZ Invaders (Space Invaders), Dawn Patrol (Chopper) och Moon Patrol.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>伟易达Laser 310（亦称VZ-310）是一款搭载Z80架构、3.54MHz微处理器的一体机电脑。伟易达（Video Technology Ltd.简称）是香港电子公司，通过多家零售连锁店在其他国家销售该产品。 例如，该机型由迪克·史密斯电子公司销售时，产品名称从伟易达改为迪克·史密斯激光VZ-310（或简称VZ-310），销售周期为1983至1989年。 Laser 310与前代机型Laser200（VZ-200）基本兼容，仅键盘经过改良，且配备18千字节（其中2千字节为视频内存）的特殊内存规格。 该机型可运行卡带版基础游戏，包括《Hoppy》（《青蛙过河》版本）、《Cosmic Rescue》（《太空战机》）、《VZ Invaders》（《太空侵略者》）、《Dawn Patrol》（《直升机》）及《Moon Patrol》。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
