<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>PDP-1</systemName>
    <systemDescription>The PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) is the first computer in Digital Equipment Corporation's PDP series and was first produced in 1959. It is famous for being the computer most important in the creation of hacker culture at Massachusetts Institute of Technology, BBN and elsewhere.
The PDP-1 is the original hardware for playing history's first game on a minicomputer, Steve Russell's Spacewar!

The PDP-1 uses an 18-bit word size and has 4096 words as standard main memory, upgradable to 65,536 words.
It is built mostly of DEC 1000-series System Building Blocks, using micro-alloy and micro-alloy diffused transistors with a rated switching speed of 5 MHz. The System Building Blocks are packaged into several 19-inch racks. The racks are themselves packaged into a single large mainframe case, with a hexagonal control panel containing switches and lights mounted to lie at table-top height at one end of the mainframe. Above the control panel is the system's standard input/output solution, a punched tape reader and writer.

The PDP-1 weighed about 730 kg (1,600 lb).</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Digital Equipment Corporation</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1961</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-computer}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) هو أول كمبيوتر في سلسلة PDP من شركة Digital Equipment Corporation، وقد تم إنتاجه لأول مرة في عام 1959. وهو مشهور بكونه الكمبيوتر الأكثر أهمية في تكوين ثقافة القراصنة في معهد ماساتشوستس للتكنولوجيا و BBN وأماكن أخرى. PDP-1 هو الجهاز الأصلي لتشغيل أول لعبة في التاريخ على كمبيوتر صغير، وهي لعبة Spacewar! التي ابتكرها ستيف راسل.

يستخدم PDP-1 حجم كلمة 18 بت ويحتوي على 4096 كلمة كذاكرة رئيسية قياسية، قابلة للترقية إلى 65536 كلمة. وهو مصنوع في الغالب من مكونات نظام DEC 1000-series System Building Blocks، باستخدام ترانزستورات من السبائك الدقيقة والسبائك الدقيقة المنتشرة بسرعة تبديل مقدرة تبلغ 5 ميجاهرتز. يتم تجميع مكونات نظام System Building Blocks في عدة حوامل مقاس 19 بوصة. يتم تجميع الحوامل نفسها في علبة واحدة كبيرة للحاسوب المركزي، مع لوحة تحكم سداسية تحتوي على مفاتيح ومصابيح مثبتة على ارتفاع سطح الطاولة في أحد طرفي الحاسوب المركزي. يوجد فوق لوحة التحكم حل الإدخال/الإخراج القياسي للنظام، وهو قارئ وكاتب شريط مثقوب. يزن PDP-1 حوالي 730 كجم (1600 رطل).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) je prvi računar iz PDP serije kompanije Digital Equipment Corporation i prvi put je proizveden 1959. godine. Poznat je kao računar od najveće važnosti za stvaranje hakerske kulture na Massachusetts Institute of Technology, u BBN-u i drugdje. PDP-1 je originalni hardver za igranje prve igre u historiji na miniračunaru, Spacewar! Stevea Russella.

PDP-1 koristi veličinu riječi od 18 bita i ima 4096 riječi standardne glavne memorije, proširive na 65.536 riječi. Izgrađen je uglavnom od blokova za izgradnju sistema (System Building Blocks) serije DEC 1000, koristeći transistore od mikrolegure i mikrolegure s difuzijom s nazivnom brzinom prebacivanja od 5 MHz. Blokovi za izgradnju sistema pakovani su u nekoliko 19-inčnih rackova. Rasplamsaji su pakovani u jednom velikom kućištu mainframea, sa šesterokutnom kontrolnom pločom koja sadrži prekidače i svjetla, montiranom na visini stola na jednom kraju mainframea. Iznad kontrolne ploče nalazi se standardno sistemsko rješenje za ulaz/izlaz, čitač i pisac perforirane trake. PDP-1 je težio oko 730 kg (1.600 lb).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>El PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) és el primer ordinador de la sèrie PDP de Digital Equipment Corporation i es va produir per primer cop el 1959. És famós per ser l'ordinador més important en la creació de la cultura hacker al Massachusetts Institute of Technology, a BBN i en altres llocs. El PDP-1 és el maquinari original per jugar al primer joc de la història en un miniesordinador, el Spacewar! de Steve Russell.

El PDP-1 utilitza una mida de paraula de 18 bits i té 4096 paraules de memòria principal estàndard, ampliables a 65.536 paraules. Està construït principalment amb blocs de construcció de sistema de la sèrie 1000 de DEC, utilitzant transistors de microaliatge i de microaliatge difós amb una velocitat de commutació nominal de 5 MHz. Els blocs de construcció de sistema estan empaquetats en diverses bastides de 19 polzades. Els bastidors estan empaquetats dins d'una única carcassa gran de mainframe, amb un panell de control hexagonal que conté commutadors i llums muntat a l'alçada del taulell a un extrem del mainframe. A sobre del panell de control hi ha la solució d'entrada/sortida estàndard del sistema, un lector i gravador de cinta perforada. El PDP-1 pesava uns 730 kg (1.600 lliures).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Der PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) ist der erste Computer der PDP-Serie von Digital Equipment Corporation und wurde erstmals 1959 hergestellt. Er ist bekannt als der Computer, der für die Entstehung der Hacker-Kultur am Massachusetts Institute of Technology, bei BBN und anderswo am wichtigsten war. Der PDP-1 ist die Original-Hardware, auf der das erste Spiel der Geschichte auf einem Minicomputer gespielt wurde: Steve Russells Spacewar!

Der PDP-1 verwendet eine Wortgröße von 18 Bit und verfügt über einen Standard-Hauptspeicher von 4096 Wörtern, der auf 65.536 Wörter erweitert werden kann. Er besteht größtenteils aus System Building Blocks der DEC 1000-Serie und verwendet Mikrolegierungs- und Mikrolegierungs-Diffusionstransistoren mit einer Nennschaltgeschwindigkeit von 5 MHz. Die System Building Blocks sind in mehreren 19-Zoll-Racks untergebracht. Die Racks sind wiederum in einem einzigen großen Mainframe-Gehäuse untergebracht, mit einem sechseckigen Bedienfeld mit Schaltern und Leuchten, das an einem Ende des Mainframes in Tischhöhe angebracht ist. Über dem Bedienfeld befindet sich die Standard-Ein-/Ausgabelösung des Systems, ein Lochstreifenleser und -schreiber. Der PDP-1 wog etwa 730 kg (1.600 lb).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>El PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) es el primer ordenador de la serie PDP de Digital Equipment Corporation y se fabricó por primera vez en 1959. Es famoso por ser el ordenador más importante en la creación de la cultura hacker en el Instituto Tecnológico de Massachusetts, BBN y otros lugares. El PDP-1 es el hardware original para jugar al primer juego de la historia en un minordenador, ¡Spacewar! de Steve Russell.

El PDP-1 utiliza un tamaño de palabra de 18 bits y tiene 4096 palabras como memoria principal estándar, ampliable a 65 536 palabras. Está construido principalmente con bloques de construcción del sistema de la serie DEC 1000, utilizando transistores de microaleación y microaleación difusa con una velocidad de conmutación nominal de 5 MHz. Los bloques de construcción del sistema se empaquetan en varios racks de 19 pulgadas. Los racks están a su vez empaquetados en una única carcasa de mainframe grande, con un panel de control hexagonal que contiene interruptores y luces montados a la altura de la mesa en un extremo del mainframe. Por encima del panel de control se encuentra la solución de entrada/salida estándar del sistema, un lector y escritor de cinta perforada. El PDP-1 pesaba unos 730 kg (1600 lb).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>Le PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) est le premier ordinateur de la série PDP de Digital Equipment Corporation. Il a été produit pour la première fois en 1959. Il est célèbre pour avoir été l'ordinateur le plus important dans la création de la culture hacker au Massachusetts Institute of Technology, chez BBN et ailleurs. Le PDP-1 est le matériel d'origine qui a permis de jouer au premier jeu de l'histoire sur un mini-ordinateur, Spacewar! de Steve Russell.

Le PDP-1 utilise une taille de mot de 18 bits et dispose d'une mémoire principale standard de 4096 mots, extensible à 65 536 mots. Il est principalement composé de blocs de construction système DEC série 1000, utilisant des transistors en micro-alliage et en micro-alliage diffusé avec une vitesse de commutation nominale de 5 MHz. Les blocs de construction système sont regroupés dans plusieurs racks de 19 pouces. Les racks sont eux-mêmes regroupés dans un seul grand boîtier central, avec un panneau de commande hexagonal contenant des commutateurs et des voyants lumineux montés à hauteur de table à une extrémité du boîtier central. Au-dessus du panneau de commande se trouve la solution d'entrée/sortie standard du système, un lecteur et un enregistreur de bande perforée. Le PDP-1 pesait environ 730 kg (1 600 lb).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) je prvi računalo u PDP seriji tvrtke Digital Equipment Corporation i prvi put je proizveden 1959. godine. Poznat je kao računalo najvažnije za stvaranje hakerske kulture na Massachusetts Institute of Technology, u BBN-u i drugdje. PDP-1 je originalni hardver za igranje prve igre u povijesti na miniračunalu, Spacewar! Stevea Russella.

PDP-1 koristi veličinu riječi od 18 bita i ima 4096 riječi standardne glavne memorije, proširive na 65.536 riječi. Izgrađen je uglavnom od gradivnih blokova sustava serije DEC 1000, koristeći transistore od mikrolegure i difuzije u mikroleguri s nazivnom brzinom prebacivanja od 5 MHz. Gradivni blokovi sustava pakirani su u nekoliko 19-inčnih rackova. Rackovi su smješteni u jednom velikom kućištu mainframea, s šesterokutnom kontrolnom pločom koja sadrži prekidače i svjetla montirana na visini stola na jednom kraju mainframea. Iznad kontrolne ploče nalazi se standardno ulazno/izlazno rješenje sustava, čitač i pisač programskih traka. PDP-1 je težio oko 730 kg (1.600 lb).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Il PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) è il primo computer della serie PDP della Digital Equipment Corporation ed è stato prodotto per la prima volta nel 1959. È famoso per essere il computer più importante nella creazione della cultura hacker al Massachusetts Institute of Technology, alla BBN e altrove. Il PDP-1 è l'hardware originale per giocare al primo gioco della storia su un minicomputer, Spacewar! di Steve Russell.

Il PDP-1 utilizza una dimensione di parola a 18 bit e ha 4096 parole come memoria principale standard, aggiornabile a 65.536 parole. È costruito principalmente con blocchi di sistema della serie DEC 1000, utilizzando transistor in microlega e microlega diffusa con una velocità di commutazione nominale di 5 MHz. I blocchi di sistema sono racchiusi in diversi rack da 19 pollici. I rack sono a loro volta racchiusi in un unico grande case mainframe, con un pannello di controllo esagonale contenente interruttori e spie luminose montati ad altezza tavolo su un'estremità del mainframe. Sopra il pannello di controllo si trova la soluzione di input/output standard del sistema, un lettore e scrittore di nastri perforati. Il PDP-1 pesava circa 730 kg (1.600 libbre).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>PDP-1（Programmed Data Processor-1）は、デジタル・イクイップメント・コーポレーション（DEC）のPDPシリーズの最初のコンピュータであり、1959年に初めて製造された。マサチューセッツ工科大学（MIT）、BBN（ボストン・ブレイン・ネットワーク）などにおけるハッカー文化の形成において最も重要なコンピュータとして有名である。PDP-1は、ミニコンピュータ上で史上初のゲームであるスティーブ・ラッセルの『スペースウォー！』をプレイするためのオリジナルのハードウェアである。

PDP-1は18ビットのワード長を採用し、標準メインメモリは4096ワード（最大65,536ワードまで拡張可能）である。主にDEC 1000シリーズ・システムビルディングブロックで構成され、定格スイッチング速度5MHzのマイクロアロイおよびマイクロアロイ拡散トランジスタを使用している。システムビルディングブロックは複数の19インチラックにパッケージ化されている。 ラック自体は単一の大型メインフレーム筐体に収められており、メインフレームの一端にはテーブルトップの高さに設置された六角形の制御パネルが取り付けられ、スイッチや表示灯を備えています。制御パネルの上部には、パンチテープリーダー／ライターというシステム標準の入出力装置が配置されています。PDP-1の重量は約730kg（1,600ポンド）でした。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>PDP-1(Programmed Data Processor-1)은 디지털 장비(Digital Equipment Corporation)의 PDP 시리즈 최초의 컴퓨터로 1959년에 처음 생산되었습니다. 매사추세츠 공과대학(MIT), BBN 등지에서 해커 문화 형성에 가장 중요한 컴퓨터로 유명합니다. PDP-1은 미니컴퓨터에서 역사상 최초의 게임인 스티브 러셀의 '스페이스워!(Spacewar!)'를 실행한 원본 하드웨어입니다.

PDP-1은 18비트 단어 크기를 사용하며, 표준 메인 메모리는 4096단어이며 65,536단어까지 확장 가능합니다. 주로 DEC 1000 시리즈 시스템 빌딩 블록(System Building Blocks)으로 구성되었으며, 정격 스위칭 속도 5MHz의 미세합금 및 미세합금 확산 트랜지스터를 사용합니다. 시스템 빌딩 블록은 여러 개의 19인치 랙에 패키징됩니다. 이 랙들은 하나의 대형 메인프레임 케이스에 통합되어 있으며, 메인프레임 한쪽 끝에는 스위치와 표시등이 장착된 육각형 제어판이 탁상 높이 수준으로 설치됩니다. 제어판 위에는 시스템의 표준 입출력 장치인 천공 테이프 리더/라이터가 위치합니다. PDP-1의 무게는 약 730kg(1,600파운드)입니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>De PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) is de eerste computer in de PDP-serie van Digital Equipment Corporation en werd voor het eerst geproduceerd in 1959. Hij staat bekend als de computer die het belangrijkst was voor het ontstaan van de hackercultuur aan het Massachusetts Institute of Technology, BBN en elders. De PDP-1 is de originele hardware waarop het eerste spel op een minicomputer ooit werd gespeeld, Steve Russells Spacewar!

De PDP-1 gebruikt een woordgrootte van 18 bits en heeft 4096 woorden als standaard hoofdgeheugen, uitbreidbaar tot 65.536 woorden. Hij is grotendeels gebouwd met DEC 1000-serie System Building Blocks, waarbij gebruik wordt gemaakt van micro-legering en micro-legering diffuus transistors met een nominale schakelsnelheid van 5 MHz. De System Building Blocks zijn verpakt in verschillende 19-inch racks. De rekken zijn zelf verpakt in een enkele grote mainframekast, met een zeshoekig bedieningspaneel met schakelaars en lampjes dat op tafelhoogte aan één uiteinde van de mainframe is gemonteerd. Boven het bedieningspaneel bevindt zich de standaard invoer-/uitvoeroplossing van het systeem, een ponsbandlezer en -schrijver. De PDP-1 woog ongeveer 730 kg (1600 lb).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) to pierwszy komputer z serii PDP firmy Digital Equipment Corporation, wyprodukowany po raz pierwszy w 1959 roku. Jest znany jako komputer, który odegrał najważniejszą rolę w tworzeniu kultury hakerów w Massachusetts Institute of Technology, BBN i innych miejscach. PDP-1 to oryginalny sprzęt, na którym zagrano pierwszą w historii grę na minikomputerze, Spacewar! autorstwa Steve'a Russella.

PDP-1 wykorzystuje 18-bitową długość słowa i ma 4096 słów jako standardową pamięć główną, z możliwością rozszerzenia do 65 536 słów. Jest zbudowany głównie z bloków systemowych DEC serii 1000, wykorzystujących tranzystory mikrostopowe i mikrostopowe dyfuzyjne o znamionowej prędkości przełączania 5 MHz. Bloki systemowe są umieszczone w kilku 19-calowych szafach. Raki są z kolei umieszczone w jednej dużej obudowie mainframe, z sześciokątnym panelem sterowania zawierającym przełączniki i lampki zamontowane na wysokości blatu stołu na jednym końcu mainframe. Nad panelem sterowania znajduje się standardowe rozwiązanie wejścia/wyjścia systemu, czytnik i zapisywarka taśmy perforowanej. PDP-1 ważył około 730 kg (1600 funtów).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>O PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) é o primeiro computador da série PDP da Digital Equipment Corporation e foi produzido pela primeira vez em 1959. É famoso por ser o computador mais importante na criação da cultura hacker no Massachusetts Institute of Technology, na BBN e em outros lugares. O PDP-1 é o hardware original para jogar o primeiro jogo da história em um minicomputador, o Spacewar! de Steve Russell.

O PDP-1 usa um tamanho de palavra de 18 bits e tem 4096 palavras como memória principal padrão, atualizável para 65.536 palavras. Ele é construído principalmente com blocos de construção do sistema da série DEC 1000, usando transistores de microliga e microliga difusa com uma velocidade de comutação nominal de 5 MHz. Os blocos de construção do sistema são embalados em vários racks de 19 polegadas. Os racks são, por sua vez, embalados em um único gabinete de mainframe grande, com um painel de controle hexagonal contendo interruptores e luzes montados na altura da mesa em uma extremidade do mainframe. Acima do painel de controle está a solução padrão de entrada/saída do sistema, um leitor e gravador de fita perfurada. O PDP-1 pesava cerca de 730 kg (1.600 lb).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) este primul computer din seria PDP a Digital Equipment Corporation și a fost produs pentru prima dată în 1959. Este renumit pentru faptul că este cel mai important computer în crearea culturii hackerilor la Massachusetts Institute of Technology, BBN și în alte locuri. PDP-1 este hardware-ul original pentru jucarea primului joc din istorie pe un minicomputer, Spacewar! al lui Steve Russell.

PDP-1 utilizează o dimensiune de cuvânt de 18 biți și are 4096 de cuvinte ca memorie principală standard, care poate fi extinsă la 65.536 de cuvinte. Este construit în mare parte din blocuri de sistem din seria DEC 1000, utilizând micro-aliaje și tranzistoare difuzate din micro-aliaje cu o viteză nominală de comutare de 5 MHz. Blocurile de sistem sunt ambalate în mai multe rack-uri de 19 inci. Rack-urile sunt la rândul lor ambalate într-o singură carcasă mare de mainframe, cu un panou de control hexagonal care conține comutatoare și lumini montate la înălțimea blatului de masă la un capăt al mainframe-ului. Deasupra panoului de control se află soluția standard de intrare/ieșire a sistemului, un cititor și scriitor de bandă perforată. PDP-1 cântărea aproximativ 730 kg (1.600 lb).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) — первый компьютер серии PDP компании Digital Equipment Corporation, выпущенный в 1959 году. Он известен как компьютер, сыгравший важнейшую роль в становлении хакерской культуры в Массачусетском технологическом институте, BBN и других местах. PDP-1 — это оригинальное оборудование, на котором была запущена первая в истории игра на мини-компьютере, Spacewar!

PDP-1 использует 18-битный размер слова и имеет 4096 слов в качестве стандартной основной памяти, которую можно расширить до 65 536 слов. Он построен в основном из системных блоков DEC серии 1000 с использованием микросплавов и диффузионных транзисторов с номинальной скоростью переключения 5 МГц. Системные блоки упакованы в несколько 19-дюймовых стоек. Стойки, в свою очередь, упакованы в один большой корпус мэйнфрейма с шестиугольной панелью управления, содержащей переключатели и индикаторы, установленной на уровне столешницы на одном конце мэйнфрейма. Над панелью управления находится стандартное устройство ввода-вывода системы — устройство чтения и записи перфоленты. Вес PDP-1 составлял около 730 кг (1600 фунтов).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>ПДП-1 (Програмовани процесор података-1) је први рачунар у PDP серији компаније Digital Equipment Corporation и први пут је произведен 1959. године. Познат је као рачунар најважнији за настанак хакерске културе на Масачусетском институту технологије, у BBN и на другим местима. PDP-1 је оригинални хардвер за прву игру у историји на минирачунару, Spacewar! Стива Расела.

ПДП-1 користи величину речи од 18 бита и има 4096 речи као стандардну главниу меморију, проширујућу до 65.536 речи. Изграђен је углавном од блокова за изградњу система серије DEC 1000, користећи микролегиране и микролегиране дифузне транзисторе са номиналном брзином прекидања од 5 MHz. Блокови за изградњу система су упаковани у неколико 19-инчних ормана. Сами рамови су смештени у једно велико кућиште главног рачунара, са шестоугаоном командном таблом која садржи прекидаче и светла, постављеном на висини стола на једном крају кућишта. Изнад командне табле налази се стандардно системско решење за улаз/излаз, читач и писач перфориране траке. PDP-1 је тежио око 730 кг (1.600 lb).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>PDP-1 (Programmed Data Processor-1) är den första datorn i Digital Equipment Corporations PDP-serie och tillverkades första gången 1959. Den är känd för att vara den dator som var viktigast för skapandet av hackerkulturen vid Massachusetts Institute of Technology, BBN och på andra håll. PDP-1 är den ursprungliga hårdvaran för att spela historiens första spel på en minidator, Steve Russells Spacewar!

PDP-1 använder en ordstorlek på 18 bitar och har 4096 ord som standardhuvudminne, vilket kan uppgraderas till 65 536 ord. Den är till största delen byggd av DEC 1000-seriens System Building Blocks, med mikrolegerade och mikrolegerade diffusa transistorer med en nominell omkopplingshastighet på 5 MHz. System Building Blocks är förpackade i flera 19-tums rack. Racken är i sin tur förpackade i ett enda stort stordatorchassi, med en sexkantig kontrollpanel med omkopplare och lampor monterade i bordshöjd i ena änden av stordatorn. Ovanför kontrollpanelen finns systemets standardlösning för in- och utdata, en hålbandsläsare och -skrivare. PDP-1 vägde cirka 730 kg (1 600 lb).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>PDP-1（程序化数据处理器-1）是数字设备公司PDP系列的首款计算机，于1959年首次投产。它因在麻省理工学院、BBN及其他机构催生黑客文化过程中扮演至关重要角色而闻名。PDP-1正是运行史上首款小型计算机游戏——史蒂夫·罗素开发的《太空战争！》的原始硬件平台。

PDP-1采用18位字长架构，标准主存容量为4096字，可扩展至65536字。其主体由DEC 1000系列系统构建模块构成，采用微合金及微合金扩散晶体管，额定开关频率达5MHz。这些系统构建模块被集成于多个19英寸机架中。 机架整体封装于单一大型主机箱内，主机箱一端设有六边形控制面板，其开关与指示灯安装于桌面高度。控制面板上方配置系统标准输入输出设备——穿孔带读写器。PDP-1主机重量约730千克（1,600磅）。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
