<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Plug &amp; Play TV Games</systemName>
    <systemDescription>TV game (TV game for short) or plug and play game (plug-'n'-play game for short) is an interactive entertainment device designed for use on a television set that integrates the video game console with the game controller.

The term "TV game" can be used to refer to any number of self-contained, portable game systems operating on either batteries or an electronic power supply which plugs directly into a TV or VCR. The game software is built directly into the unit, which is typically designed to look like a toy or classic game console/controller with the addition of two AV ports. These systems usually contain either highly specialized games or activities, or a collection of classic games. Thus, it could be viewed as a video game console without interchangeable game software. As the game software is integrated into the game unit and almost never designed to be changed by the user, these game systems are typically sold by retailers as electronic toys or collectibles rather than game consoles.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Various</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1998</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-console}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>لعبة التلفزيون (اختصاراً TV game) أو لعبة التوصيل والتشغيل (اختصاراً plug-'n'-play game) هي جهاز ترفيهي تفاعلي مصمم للاستخدام على جهاز التلفزيون يدمج وحدة التحكم في ألعاب الفيديو مع وحدة التحكم في اللعبة.

يمكن استخدام مصطلح "لعبة تلفزيونية" للإشارة إلى أي عدد من أنظمة الألعاب المحمولة المستقلة التي تعمل إما بالبطاريات أو بمصدر طاقة إلكتروني يتم توصيله مباشرة بالتلفزيون أو جهاز الفيديو. يتم تضمين برنامج اللعبة مباشرة في الوحدة، التي عادة ما تكون مصممة لتبدو مثل لعبة أو وحدة تحكم/جهاز تحكم كلاسيكي مع إضافة منفذي AV. عادة ما تحتوي هذه الأنظمة إما على ألعاب أو أنشطة متخصصة للغاية، أو مجموعة من الألعاب الكلاسيكية. وبالتالي، يمكن اعتبارها وحدة تحكم ألعاب فيديو بدون برامج ألعاب قابلة للتبديل. نظرًا لأن برامج الألعاب مدمجة في وحدة الألعاب ولا يتم تصميمها أبدًا بحيث يمكن للمستخدم تغييرها، عادةً ما يتم بيع أنظمة الألعاب هذه من قبل تجار التجزئة كألعاب إلكترونية أو قطع تذكارية بدلاً من وحدات تحكم الألعاب.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>TV igra (skraćeno TV igra) ili plug and play igra (skraćeno plug-'n'-play igra) je interaktivni zabavni uređaj dizajniran za upotrebu na televizoru koji integriše konzolu za video igre sa kontrolerom.

Termin "TV igra" se može koristiti za označavanje bilo kojeg broja samostalnih, prenosivih sistema za igranje koji rade na baterije ili na elektronsko napajanje koje se direktno priključuje na TV ili video-rekorder. Softver za igru je ugrađen direktno u uređaj, koji je obično dizajniran da izgleda kao igračka ili klasična konzola/kontrolna jedinica za igranje, s dodatkom dva AV priključka. Ovi sistemi obično sadrže ili visoko specijalizovane igre ili aktivnosti, ili kolekciju klasičnih igara. Stoga se može smatrati konzolom za videoigre bez zamjenskog softvera za igre. Budući da je softver za igru integriran u samu jedinicu i gotovo nikada nije dizajniran da ga korisnik mijenja, ovi se sistemi za igre obično prodaju u maloprodaji kao elektronske igračke ili kolekcionarski predmeti, a ne kao konzole za igre.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>Joc de TV (abreviat com a TV game) o joc plug and play (abreviat com a plug-'n'-play game) és un dispositiu d'entreteniment interactiu dissenyat per a ús en un televisor que integra la consola de videojocs amb el comandament.

El terme «joc de TV» es pot fer servir per referir-se a qualsevol nombre de sistemes de joc autònoms i portàtils que funcionen amb piles o amb una font d'alimentació electrònica que s'endolla directament a un televisor o a un vídeo. El programari del joc està integrat directament a la unitat, que normalment està dissenyada per semblar un joguet o una consola/maneta de joc clàssica, amb l'addició de dos ports d'àudio i vídeo. Aquests sistemes solen contenir jocs o activitats altament especialitzats, o bé una col·lecció de jocs clàssics. Així doncs, es podria considerar una consola de videojocs sense programari de jocs intercanviable. Com que el programari de joc està integrat a la unitat de joc i gairebé mai no està dissenyat perquè l'usuari el canviï, aquests sistemes de joc solen ser venuts pels minoristes com a joguines electròniques o articles de col·lecció en lloc de consoles de jocs.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Ein TV-Spiel (kurz TV-Spiel) oder Plug-and-Play-Spiel (kurz Plug-'n'-Play-Spiel) ist ein interaktives Unterhaltungsgerät, das für die Verwendung auf einem Fernseher konzipiert ist und die Videospielkonsole mit dem Spielcontroller integriert.

Der Begriff „TV-Spiel” kann für eine beliebige Anzahl eigenständiger, tragbarer Spielsysteme verwendet werden, die entweder mit Batterien oder einem elektronischen Netzteil betrieben werden und direkt an einen Fernseher oder Videorekorder angeschlossen werden. Die Spielesoftware ist direkt in das Gerät integriert, das in der Regel wie ein Spielzeug oder eine klassische Spielkonsole/ein klassischer Spielcontroller mit zwei zusätzlichen AV-Anschlüssen gestaltet ist. Diese Systeme enthalten in der Regel entweder hochspezialisierte Spiele oder Aktivitäten oder eine Sammlung klassischer Spiele. Somit könnte man sie als Videospielkonsole ohne austauschbare Spielesoftware betrachten. Da die Spielesoftware in das Gerät integriert ist und fast nie so konzipiert ist, dass sie vom Benutzer geändert werden kann, werden diese Spielsysteme in der Regel von Einzelhändlern eher als elektronisches Spielzeug oder Sammlerstücke denn als Spielkonsolen verkauft.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>Los videojuegos para televisión (o «TV game», por sus siglas en inglés) o los juegos «plug and play» (o «plug-'n'-play game», por sus siglas en inglés) son dispositivos de entretenimiento interactivo diseñados para su uso en un televisor que integran la consola de videojuegos con el mando.

El término «juego de televisión» puede utilizarse para referirse a cualquier número de sistemas de juego autónomos y portátiles que funcionan con pilas o con una fuente de alimentación electrónica que se conecta directamente a un televisor o a un reproductor de vídeo. El software del juego está integrado directamente en la unidad, que suele tener el aspecto de un juguete o de una consola/mando clásico, con la adición de dos puertos AV. Estos sistemas suelen contener juegos o actividades muy especializados, o una colección de juegos clásicos. Por lo tanto, podría considerarse una consola de videojuegos sin software de juego intercambiable. Dado que el software de juego está integrado en la unidad y casi nunca está diseñado para que el usuario lo cambie, estos sistemas de juego suelen venderse en tiendas como juguetes electrónicos o artículos de colección, en lugar de consolas de videojuegos.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>Le jeu vidéo (ou jeu TV) ou jeu plug-and-play (ou jeu plug-'n'-play) est un dispositif de divertissement interactif conçu pour être utilisé sur un téléviseur et qui intègre la console de jeu vidéo et la manette de jeu.

Le terme « jeu vidéo » peut être utilisé pour désigner n'importe quel système de jeu autonome et portable fonctionnant sur piles ou sur une alimentation électrique qui se branche directement sur un téléviseur ou un magnétoscope. Le logiciel de jeu est intégré directement dans l'appareil, qui est généralement conçu pour ressembler à un jouet ou à une console/manette de jeu classique, avec deux ports AV supplémentaires. Ces systèmes contiennent généralement des jeux ou des activités hautement spécialisés, ou une collection de jeux classiques. On peut donc les considérer comme des consoles de jeux vidéo sans logiciel de jeu interchangeable. Comme le logiciel de jeu est intégré à l'unité de jeu et n'est pratiquement jamais conçu pour être modifié par l'utilisateur, ces systèmes de jeu sont généralement vendus par les détaillants comme des jouets électroniques ou des objets de collection plutôt que comme des consoles de jeu.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>TV igra (skraćeno TV igra) ili plug-and-play igra (skraćeno plug-'n'-play igra) je interaktivni zabavni uređaj namijenjen za upotrebu na televizoru koji integrira konzolu za videoigre s kontrolerom.

Izraz "TV igra" može se koristiti za opis raznih samostalnih, prijenosnih igraćih sustava koji rade na baterije ili na elektroničko napajanje koje se izravno priključuje na televizor ili videorekorder. Softver za igru ugrađen je izravno u uređaj, koji je obično dizajniran da izgleda kao igračka ili klasična igraća konzola/uređaj za upravljanje s dodatkom dva AV priključka. Ovi sustavi obično sadrže ili visoko specijalizirane igre ili aktivnosti, ili zbirku klasičnih igara. Stoga se može smatrati videoigračom konzolom bez izmjenjivog softvera za igre. Budući da je softver za igre integriran u samu jedinicu za igru i gotovo nikada nije dizajniran da ga korisnik mijenja, ovi se sustavi za igre obično prodaju u maloprodaji kao elektroničke igračke ili kolekcionarski predmeti, a ne kao igraće konzole.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Il videogioco per TV (abbreviato in TV game) o plug and play (abbreviato in plug-'n'-play game) è un dispositivo di intrattenimento interattivo progettato per l'uso su un televisore che integra la console per videogiochi con il controller di gioco.

Il termine "gioco per TV" può essere utilizzato per riferirsi a qualsiasi numero di sistemi di gioco autonomi e portatili che funzionano a batterie o con un alimentatore elettronico che si collega direttamente a un televisore o a un videoregistratore. Il software di gioco è integrato direttamente nell'unità, che in genere è progettata per assomigliare a un giocattolo o a una console/controller di gioco classico con l'aggiunta di due porte AV. Questi sistemi di solito contengono giochi o attività altamente specializzati, oppure una raccolta di giochi classici. Pertanto, potrebbero essere considerati come console per videogiochi senza software di gioco intercambiabile. Poiché il software di gioco è integrato nell'unità di gioco e quasi mai progettato per essere modificato dall'utente, questi sistemi di gioco sono in genere venduti dai rivenditori come giocattoli elettronici o oggetti da collezione piuttosto che come console di gioco.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>テレビゲーム（略してTVゲーム）またはプラグアンドプレイゲーム（略してプラグンプレイゲーム）とは、テレビセット上で使用するために設計されたインタラクティブな娯楽機器であり、ビデオゲームコンソールとゲームコントローラーを一体化させたものである。

「TVゲーム」という用語は、電池またはテレビやVCRに直接接続する電源で動作する、あらゆる種類の独立型・携帯型ゲームシステムを指す場合がある。ゲームソフトウェアは本体に直接組み込まれており、通常はおもちゃやクラシックなゲーム機／コントローラーのような外観に、2つのAVポートが追加されたデザインとなっている。これらのシステムには、高度に専門化されたゲームやアクティビティ、あるいはクラシックゲームのコレクションが収録されていることが多い。 したがって、交換可能なゲームソフトを持たないビデオゲーム機と見なすこともできる。ゲームソフトが本体に統合されており、ユーザーによる変更がほぼ不可能であるため、これらのゲームシステムは小売店ではゲーム機ではなく電子玩具やコレクターズアイテムとして販売されるのが一般的である。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>TV 게임(약칭 TV 게임) 또는 플러그 앤 플레이 게임(약칭 플러그 앤 플레이 게임)은 텔레비전 세트에서 사용하도록 설계된 상호작용형 엔터테인먼트 장치로, 비디오 게임 콘솔과 게임 컨트롤러를 통합한 형태입니다.

"TV 게임"이라는 용어는 배터리 또는 TV나 VCR에 직접 연결되는 전자 전원 공급 장치로 작동하는 다양한 독립형 휴대용 게임 시스템을 지칭하는 데 사용될 수 있습니다. 게임 소프트웨어는 장치에 직접 내장되어 있으며, 일반적으로 장난감이나 클래식 게임 콘솔/컨트롤러처럼 보이도록 설계되고 두 개의 AV 포트가 추가됩니다. 이러한 시스템은 일반적으로 고도로 특화된 게임이나 활동, 또는 클래식 게임 모음을 포함합니다. 따라서 이는 교체 가능한 게임 소프트웨어가 없는 비디오 게임 콘솔로 볼 수 있습니다. 게임 소프트웨어가 기기에 통합되어 있으며 사용자가 변경하도록 설계된 경우가 거의 없기 때문에, 이러한 게임 시스템은 일반적으로 소매점에서 게임 콘솔이 아닌 전자 장난감이나 수집품으로 판매됩니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>Een tv-spel (afgekort tv-game) of plug-and-play-spel (afgekort plug-'n'-play-game) is een interactief entertainmentapparaat dat is ontworpen voor gebruik op een televisietoestel en dat de videogameconsole met de gamecontroller integreert.

De term "tv-spel" kan worden gebruikt om te verwijzen naar een willekeurig aantal zelfstandige, draagbare spelsystemen die werken op batterijen of een elektronische voeding die rechtstreeks op een tv of videorecorder kan worden aangesloten. De spelsoftware is rechtstreeks in het apparaat ingebouwd, dat er doorgaans uitziet als speelgoed of een klassieke spelconsole/controller met twee extra AV-poorten. Deze systemen bevatten meestal zeer gespecialiseerde spellen of activiteiten, of een verzameling klassieke spellen. Het kan dus worden gezien als een videogameconsole zonder verwisselbare spelsoftware. Aangezien de spelsoftware in het spelapparaat is geïntegreerd en bijna nooit door de gebruiker kan worden gewijzigd, worden deze spelsystemen door winkeliers meestal verkocht als elektronisch speelgoed of verzamelobjecten in plaats van als spelconsoles.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Gra telewizyjna (w skrócie gra TV) lub gra typu plug and play (w skrócie gra plug-'n'-play) to interaktywne urządzenie rozrywkowe przeznaczone do użytku z telewizorem, które łączy konsolę do gier wideo z kontrolerem do gier.

Termin „gra telewizyjna” może odnosić się do dowolnej liczby samodzielnych, przenośnych systemów do gier, zasilanych bateriami lub elektronicznym zasilaczem, które podłącza się bezpośrednio do telewizora lub magnetowidu. Oprogramowanie do gier jest wbudowane bezpośrednio w urządzenie, które zazwyczaj wygląda jak zabawka lub klasyczna konsola/kontroler do gier z dodatkiem dwóch portów AV. Systemy te zazwyczaj zawierają albo wysoce specjalistyczne gry lub aktywności, albo zbiór klasycznych gier. Można je zatem postrzegać jako konsole do gier wideo bez wymiennego oprogramowania. Ponieważ oprogramowanie jest zintegrowane z urządzeniem i prawie nigdy nie jest przeznaczone do zmiany przez użytkownika, systemy te są zazwyczaj sprzedawane przez detalistów jako zabawki elektroniczne lub przedmioty kolekcjonerskie, a nie konsole do gier.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>Jogo de TV (abreviado como jogo de TV) ou jogo plug and play (abreviado como jogo plug-'n'-play) é um dispositivo de entretenimento interativo projetado para uso em um aparelho de televisão que integra o console de videogame com o controle do jogo.

O termo "jogo de TV" pode ser usado para se referir a qualquer número de sistemas de jogos portáteis e independentes que funcionam com baterias ou uma fonte de alimentação eletrônica que se conecta diretamente a uma TV ou videocassete. O software do jogo é incorporado diretamente na unidade, que normalmente é projetada para se parecer com um brinquedo ou console/controlador de jogo clássico, com a adição de duas portas AV. Esses sistemas geralmente contêm jogos ou atividades altamente especializados ou uma coleção de jogos clássicos. Assim, pode ser visto como um console de videogame sem software de jogo intercambiável. Como o software do jogo está integrado à unidade de jogo e quase nunca é projetado para ser alterado pelo usuário, esses sistemas de jogo são normalmente vendidos por varejistas como brinquedos eletrônicos ou itens colecionáveis, em vez de consoles de jogo.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Jocul TV (pe scurt, joc TV) sau jocul plug and play (pe scurt, joc plug-'n'-play) este un dispozitiv de divertisment interactiv conceput pentru a fi utilizat pe un televizor, care integrează consola de jocuri video cu controlerul de joc.

Termenul „joc TV” poate fi utilizat pentru a se referi la orice număr de sisteme de jocuri autonome, portabile, care funcționează fie cu baterii, fie cu o sursă de alimentare electronică care se conectează direct la un televizor sau la un videorecorder. Software-ul de joc este încorporat direct în unitate, care este de obicei proiectată să arate ca o jucărie sau o consolă/un controler de joc clasic, cu adăugarea a două porturi AV. Aceste sisteme conțin de obicei fie jocuri sau activități foarte specializate, fie o colecție de jocuri clasice. Astfel, ar putea fi considerată o consolă de jocuri video fără software de jocuri interschimbabil. Deoarece software-ul de jocuri este integrat în unitatea de joc și aproape niciodată conceput pentru a fi schimbat de utilizator, aceste sisteme de jocuri sunt de obicei vândute de comercianții cu amănuntul ca jucării electronice sau obiecte de colecție, mai degrabă decât console de jocuri.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Телевизионная игра (сокращенно «ТВ-игра») или игра «plug and play» (сокращенно «plug-'n'-play») — это интерактивное развлекательное устройство, предназначенное для использования на телевизоре, которое объединяет в себе игровую консоль и игровой контроллер.

Термин «телевизионная игра» может использоваться для обозначения любого количества автономных портативных игровых систем, работающих от батарей или электронного источника питания, который подключается непосредственно к телевизору или видеомагнитофону. Игровое программное обеспечение встроено непосредственно в устройство, которое обычно имеет вид игрушки или классической игровой консоли/контроллера с добавлением двух AV-портов. Эти системы обычно содержат либо высокоспециализированные игры или задания, либо коллекцию классических игр. Таким образом, их можно рассматривать как игровые консоли без сменного игрового программного обеспечения. Поскольку игровое программное обеспечение встроено в игровой блок и практически никогда не предназначено для изменения пользователем, эти игровые системы обычно продаются розничными продавцами как электронные игрушки или предметы коллекционирования, а не как игровые консоли.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>ТВ игра (скраћено TV game) или plug and play игра (скраћено plug-'n'-play game) је интерактивни забавни уређај дизајниран за употребу на телевизору који интегрише конзолу за видео игре са контролером за игре.

Термин "ТВ игра" може се користити за означавање било ког броја самосталних, преносивих гејминг система који раде на батеријама или на електронском напајању које се директно прикључује на телевизор или видео-рекордер. Софтвер за игру је директно уграђен у уређај, који је обично дизајниран да изгледа као играчка или класична конзола/контролер са додатком два АВ порта. Ови системи обично садрже или високо специјализоване игре или активности, или збирку класичних игара. Стога се може сматрати видео-играчком конзолом без заменљивог софтвера за игре. Пошто је софтвер за игре интегрисан у сам уређај и готово никада није дизајниран да га корисник мења, ови системи за игре се обично продају у продавницама као електронске играчке или колекционарски предмети, а не као конзоле за игре.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>TV-spel (förkortat TV-spel) eller plug-and-play-spel (förkortat plug-'n'-play-spel) är en interaktiv underhållningsenhet avsedd för användning på en TV-apparat som integrerar spelkonsolen med spelkontrollen.

Termen "TV-spel" kan användas för att hänvisa till ett obegränsat antal fristående, bärbara spelsystem som drivs med batterier eller en elektronisk strömkälla som ansluts direkt till en TV eller videobandspelare. Spelprogramvaran är inbyggd direkt i enheten, som vanligtvis är utformad för att se ut som en leksak eller en klassisk spelkonsol/kontroll med två AV-portar. Dessa system innehåller vanligtvis antingen högspecialiserade spel eller aktiviteter, eller en samling klassiska spel. Det kan alltså ses som en spelkonsol utan utbytbar spelprogramvara. Eftersom spelprogramvaran är integrerad i spelenheten och nästan aldrig är utformad för att kunna bytas ut av användaren, säljs dessa spelsystem vanligtvis av återförsäljare som elektroniska leksaker eller samlarobjekt snarare än spelkonsoler.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>电视游戏（简称TV游戏）或即插即用游戏（简称即插即用游戏）是一种专为电视机设计的交互式娱乐设备，它将视频游戏主机与游戏控制器整合为一体。

"电视游戏"一词可泛指各类自成一体的便携式游戏系统，这类设备通过电池或电子电源供电，可直接连接电视或录像机使用。游戏软件直接内置于主机中，其外观通常设计成玩具或经典游戏主机/手柄的样式，并附加两个音视频接口。这类系统通常包含高度专属的游戏或活动，或是经典游戏合集。 因此，这类设备可视为无法更换游戏软件的视频游戏主机。由于游戏软件与主机不可分离且基本不支持用户更换，零售商通常将其作为电子玩具或收藏品而非游戏主机进行销售。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
