<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Socrates</systemName>
    <systemDescription>The VTech Socrates is an 8-bit educational home video game console manufactured and released in 1988 by VTech. The console features a robot character Socrates, named after the philosopher. The character is visually similar to Johnny Five from the Short Circuit movies. It was discontinued in the early 1990s.

The system features standard wireless controllers that communicated via infrared reception.

Yeno distributed the system in Europe. In Germany, under the name Prof. Weiss-Alles, which translates to "Professor Knows-Everything". And in France, as the Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, where "Saitout" comes from the french phrase "Sais Tout", meaning "Knows All".
VTech also distributed the system in Canada, being sold as the Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>VTech</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1988</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-console}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>VTech Socrates هي وحدة تحكم ألعاب فيديو تعليمية منزلية ذات 8 بت تم تصنيعها وإصدارها في عام 1988 بواسطة VTech. تتميز وحدة التحكم بشخصية روبوتية تدعى Socrates، سميت على اسم الفيلسوف. تشبه الشخصية بصريًا شخصية Johnny Five من أفلام Short Circuit. تم إيقاف إنتاجها في أوائل التسعينيات. يتميز النظام بوحدات تحكم لاسلكية قياسية تتصل عبر استقبال الأشعة تحت الحمراء. قامت Yeno بتوزيع النظام في أوروبا. في ألمانيا، تحت اسم Prof. Weiss-Alles، والذي يترجم إلى "الأستاذ يعرف كل شيء". وفي فرنسا، باسم Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video، حيث يأتي اسم "Saitout" من العبارة الفرنسية "Sais Tout"، والتي تعني "يعرف كل شيء". قامت VTech أيضًا بتوزيع النظام في كندا، حيث تم بيعه باسم Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>VTech Socrates je 8-bitna edukativna kućna videoigračka konzola koju je proizveo i objavio VTech 1988. godine. Konzola ima robota po imenu Socrates, nazvanog po filozofu. Lik je vizuelno sličan Johnnyju Fiveu iz filmova Short Circuit. Proizvodnja je prekinuta početkom 1990-ih. Sistem ima standardne bežične kontrolere koji su komunicirali putem infracrvenog prijema. Yeno je distribuirao sistem u Evropi. U Njemačkoj je distribuiran pod imenom Prof. Weiss-Alles, što se prevodi kao "Profesor Sve-Zna". A u Francuskoj, kao Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, gdje "Saitout" potiče od francuske fraze "Sais Tout", što znači "Sve zna". VTech je također distribuirao sistem u Kanadi, gdje se prodavao kao Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>La VTech Socrates és una consola de videojocs educativa domèstica de 8 bits fabricada i llançada el 1988 per VTech. La consola inclou un personatge robot anomenat Socrates, en honor al filòsof. El personatge és visualment similar a Johnny Five de les pel·lícules Short Circuit. Es va deixar de fabricar a principis dels anys 90. El sistema inclou comandaments estàndard sense fils que es comunicaven per recepció d'infrarojos. Yeno va distribuir el sistema a Europa. A Alemanya, sota el nom de Prof. Weiss-Alles, que es tradueix com a «Professor Sabeho-Tot». I a França, com a Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, on «Saitout» prové de l'expressió francesa «Sais Tout», que significa «Sabeho Tot». VTech també va distribuir el sistema al Canadà, on es venia com a Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Die VTech Socrates ist eine 8-Bit-Videospielkonsole für den Heimgebrauch, die 1988 von VTech hergestellt und auf den Markt gebracht wurde. Die Konsole verfügt über einen Robotercharakter namens Socrates, benannt nach dem Philosophen. Der Charakter ähnelt optisch Johnny Five aus den Short Circuit-Filmen. Sie wurde Anfang der 1990er Jahre eingestellt. Das System verfügt über standardmäßige drahtlose Controller, die über Infrarotempfang kommunizieren. Yeno vertrieb das System in Europa. In Deutschland unter dem Namen Prof. Weiss-Alles, was übersetzt „Professor weiß alles“ bedeutet. Und in Frankreich als Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, wobei „Saitout“ vom französischen Ausdruck „Sais Tout“ stammt, was „weiß alles“ bedeutet. VTech vertrieb das System auch in Kanada, wo es als Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video verkauft wurde.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>La VTech Socrates es una consola de videojuegos educativa de 8 bits fabricada y lanzada en 1988 por VTech. La consola cuenta con un personaje robot llamado Sócrates, en honor al filósofo. El personaje es visualmente similar a Johnny Five de las películas Short Circuit. Se dejó de fabricar a principios de la década de 1990. El sistema cuenta con mandos inalámbricos estándar que se comunicaban mediante recepción por infrarrojos. Yeno distribuyó el sistema en Europa. En Alemania, bajo el nombre de Prof. Weiss-Alles, que se traduce como «Profesor Sabe-Todo». Y en Francia, como Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, donde «Saitout» proviene de la frase francesa «Sais Tout», que significa «Lo sabe todo». VTech también distribuyó el sistema en Canadá, donde se vendió como Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>La VTech Socrates est une console de jeux vidéo éducative 8 bits fabriquée et commercialisée en 1988 par VTech. La console met en scène un personnage robotique nommé Socrates, d'après le philosophe. Ce personnage ressemble visuellement à Johnny Five, le robot du film Short Circuit. La console a été retirée du marché au début des années 1990. Le système comprend des manettes sans fil standard qui communiquent par réception infrarouge. Yeno a distribué le système en Europe. En Allemagne, sous le nom de Prof. Weiss-Alles, qui signifie « Professeur sait-tout ». Et en France, sous le nom de Professeur Saitout ; Jeu Educatif Video, où « Saitout » vient de l'expression française « Sais Tout », qui signifie « sait tout ». VTech a également distribué le système au Canada, où il était vendu sous le nom de Socrates Saitout ; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>VTech Socrates je 8-bitna obrazovna kućna videoigračka konzola koju je proizveo i objavio VTech 1988. godine. Konzola ima robota po imenu Socrates, nazvanog po filozofu. Lik je vizualno sličan Johnnyju Fiveu iz filmova Short Circuit. Proizvodnja je prekinuta početkom 1990-ih. Sustav ima standardne bežične kontrolere koji su komunicirali putem infracrvenog prijema. Sustav je u Europi distribuirao Yeno. U Njemačkoj je sustav distribuiran pod nazivom Prof. Weiss-Alles, što se prevodi kao "Profesor Sve-Zna". A u Francuskoj kao Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, gdje "Saitout" potječe od francuske fraze "Sais Tout", što znači "Sve zna". VTech je sustav distribuirao i u Kanadi, gdje se prodavao pod nazivom Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Il VTech Socrates è una console per videogiochi educativi a 8 bit prodotta e lanciata nel 1988 da VTech. La console presenta un personaggio robotico chiamato Socrates, dal nome del filosofo. Il personaggio è visivamente simile a Johnny Five dei film Short Circuit. È stato ritirato dal mercato all'inizio degli anni '90. Il sistema è dotato di controller wireless standard che comunicano tramite ricezione a infrarossi. Yeno ha distribuito il sistema in Europa. In Germania, con il nome Prof. Weiss-Alles, che si traduce in "Professore Sa-Tutto". E in Francia, come Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, dove "Saitout" deriva dalla frase francese "Sais Tout", che significa "Sa Tutto". VTech ha distribuito il sistema anche in Canada, venduto come Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>VTechソクラテスは、VTechが1988年に製造・発売した8ビット教育用家庭用ビデオゲーム機である。このコンソールは哲学者ソクラテスに因んで名付けられたロボットキャラクター「ソクラテス」を特徴としている。そのキャラクターは映画『ショート・サーキット』のジョニー・ファイブに視覚的に類似している。1990年代初頭に生産中止となった。本システムは赤外線受信による通信を行う標準的なワイヤレスコントローラーを備えている。ヨーノ社が欧州での販売を担当した。 ドイツでは「Prof. Weiss-Alles」（「教授は全てを知る」の意）の名称で販売されました。フランスでは「Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video」として展開され、「Saitout」はフランス語の「Sais Tout」（「全てを知っている」の意）に由来します。VTechはカナダでも本システムを販売し、「Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video」として流通させました。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>VTech 소크라테스는 1988년 VTech에서 제조 및 출시한 8비트 교육용 가정용 비디오 게임 콘솔이다. 이 콘솔은 철학자의 이름을 딴 로봇 캐릭터 소크라테스를 특징으로 한다. 이 캐릭터는 영화 &lt;숏 서킷&gt; 시리즈의 조니 파이브와 시각적으로 유사하다. 1990년대 초에 단종되었다. 이 시스템은 적외선 수신을 통해 통신하는 표준 무선 컨트롤러를 특징으로 한다. Yeno가 유럽에서 이 시스템을 유통했다. 독일에서는 'Prof. Weiss-Alles'(모든 것을 아는 교수)라는 이름으로, 프랑스에서는 'Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video'(모든 것을 아는 교수; 교육용 비디오 게임)라는 이름으로 출시되었습니다. 여기서 'Saitout'은 프랑스어 'Sais Tout'(모든 것을 안다)에서 유래했습니다. VTech는 캐나다에서도 이 시스템을 'Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video'라는 이름으로 유통했습니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>De VTech Socrates is een 8-bit educatieve videogameconsole voor thuisgebruik, geproduceerd en uitgebracht in 1988 door VTech. De console heeft een robotpersonage genaamd Socrates, vernoemd naar de filosoof. Het personage lijkt visueel op Johnny Five uit de Short Circuit-films. Het werd begin jaren negentig uit de handel genomen. Het systeem heeft standaard draadloze controllers die communiceren via infraroodontvangst. Yeno distribueerde het systeem in Europa. In Duitsland onder de naam Prof. Weiss-Alles, wat zich laat vertalen als "Professor Weet-Alles". En in Frankrijk als Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, waarbij "Saitout" afkomstig is van de Franse uitdrukking "Sais Tout", wat "Weet Alles" betekent. VTech distribueerde het systeem ook in Canada, waar het werd verkocht als Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>VTech Socrates to 8-bitowa edukacyjna konsola do gier wideo wyprodukowana i wprowadzona na rynek w 1988 roku przez firmę VTech. Konsola zawiera postać robota o imieniu Socrates, nazwaną na cześć filozofa. Postać ta jest wizualnie podobna do Johnny'ego Five'a z filmów Short Circuit. Produkcja konsoli została wstrzymana na początku lat 90. System wyposażony jest w standardowe kontrolery bezprzewodowe, które komunikują się za pomocą odbiornika podczerwieni. Firma Yeno zajmowała się dystrybucją systemu w Europie. W Niemczech pod nazwą Prof. Weiss-Alles, co oznacza „profesor wie wszystko”. We Francji jako Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, gdzie „Saitout” pochodzi od francuskiego wyrażenia „Sais Tout”, oznaczającego „wie wszystko”. Firma VTech dystrybuowała również ten system w Kanadzie, gdzie był sprzedawany jako Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>O VTech Socrates é uma consola de videojogos educativa de 8 bits fabricada e lançada em 1988 pela VTech. A consola apresenta uma personagem robótica chamada Socrates, em homenagem ao filósofo. A personagem é visualmente semelhante ao Johnny Five dos filmes Short Circuit. Foi descontinuada no início da década de 1990. O sistema possui controladores sem fios padrão que comunicavam através de recepção por infravermelhos. A Yeno distribuiu o sistema na Europa. Na Alemanha, sob o nome Prof. Weiss-Alles, que se traduz como "Professor Sabe-Tudo". E na França, como Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, onde "Saitout" vem da frase francesa "Sais Tout", que significa "Sabe Tudo". A VTech também distribuiu o sistema no Canadá, sendo vendido como Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>VTech Socrates este o consolă de jocuri video educativă pe 8 biți, fabricată și lansată în 1988 de VTech. Consola are ca personaj principal un robot numit Socrates, după numele filosofului. Personajul este similar din punct de vedere vizual cu Johnny Five din filmele Short Circuit. A fost scoasă din producție la începutul anilor 1990. Sistemul are controlere wireless standard care comunicau prin recepție infraroșu. Yeno a distribuit sistemul în Europa. În Germania, sub numele Prof. Weiss-Alles, care se traduce prin „Profesorul știe totul”. Iar în Franța, sub numele Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, unde „Saitout” provine din expresia franceză „Sais Tout”, care înseamnă „Știe totul”. VTech a distribuit sistemul și în Canada, fiind vândut sub numele Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>VTech Socrates — 8-битная образовательная домашняя игровая консоль, произведенная и выпущенная в 1988 году компанией VTech. Консоль имеет персонажа-робота по имени Сократ, названного в честь философа. Персонаж визуально похож на Джонни Пятерых из фильмов «Короткое замыкание». Производство консоли было прекращено в начале 1990-х годов.

Система оснащена стандартными беспроводными контроллерами, которые связываются через инфракрасный приемник.

Yeno распространяла систему в Европе. В Германии она продавалась под названием Prof. Weiss-Alles, что переводится как «Профессор Знает-Все». А во Франции — как Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, где «Saitout» происходит от французского выражения «Sais Tout», означающего «Знает все».
VTech также распространяла систему в Канаде, где она продавалась под названием Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>VTech Socrates је 8-битна едукативна кућна видео-игра конзола коју је произвео и објавио VTech 1988. године. Конзола има робота по имену Сократ, названог по филозофу. Лик је визуелно сличан Џонију Фајву из филмова "Short Circuit". Производња је обустављена почетком 1990-их.

Систем има стандардне бежичне контролере који су комуницирали инфрацрвеним пријемом.

Систем је у Европи дистрибуирала компанија Yeno. У Немачкој је систем дистрибуиран под именом Prof. Weiss-Alles, што се преводи као "Професор Свезна". А у Француској, као Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, где "Saitout" потиче од француског израза "Sais Tout", што значи "Све зна".
VTech је такође дистрибуирао систем у Канади, где се продавао као Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>VTech Socrates är en 8-bitars pedagogisk hemvideospelkonsol som tillverkades och släpptes 1988 av VTech. Konsolen har en robotkaraktär vid namn Socrates, uppkallad efter filosofen. Karaktären liknar Johnny Five från Short Circuit-filmerna. Den togs ur produktion i början av 1990-talet.

Systemet har standardtrådlösa kontroller som kommunicerar via infraröd mottagning.

Yeno distribuerade systemet i Europa. I Tyskland under namnet Prof. Weiss-Alles, vilket översätts till ”Professor vet allt”. Och i Frankrike som Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video, där ’Saitout’ kommer från det franska uttrycket ”Sais Tout”, som betyder ”vet allt”.
VTech distribuerade också systemet i Kanada, där det såldes som Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>伟易达苏格拉底是一款由伟易达公司于1988年制造并发售的8位家用教育型电子游戏主机。该主机以哲学家苏格拉底命名，主机角色为机器人苏格拉底，其外观与电影《短路》中的机器人约翰尼五号相似。该产品于1990年代初停产。

该系统配备标准无线控制器，通过红外接收器进行通信。

Yeno公司在欧洲负责该系统的分销。在德国以“Prof. Weiss-Alles”（意为“全知教授”）命名销售；法国则称为“Professeur Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video”，其中“Saitout”源自法语“Sais Tout”（意为“无所不知”）。
伟易达亦在加拿大销售该系统，产品名为“Socrates Saitout; Jeu Educatif Video”。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
