<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Sonic 3 AIR</systemName>
    <systemDescription>Re-experience one of Sonic's greatest adventures in a whole new light with Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Released in 2019 by Eukaryot, Sonic 3 A.I.R., is a full PC port of the 1994 Sega Genesis classic (and Knuckles) that boasts widescreen and smooth scrolling. On top of this screen filters, graphical improvements, achievement support, most of the changes from Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, a Knuckles and Tails mode, Sonic Mania's drop dash and mod support have been added.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Eukaryot</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>2019</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-port}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>أعد اكتشاف أحد أعظم مغامرات Sonic في ضوء جديد تماماً مع Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

تم إصداره في عام 2019 بواسطة Eukaryot، Sonic 3 A.I.R. هو عبارة عن منفذ كامل لـ PC من كلاسيكية Sega Genesis لعام 1994 (و Knuckles) الذي يفتخر بالشاشات العريضة والتمرير السلس. علاوة على ذلك، تم إضافة مرشحات الشاشة والتحسينات الرسومية ودعم الإنجازات ومعظم التغييرات من Sonic 3 Complete و Time Trials وموضع Knuckles و Tails ودعم مود Sonic Mania's drop dash.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>Ponovno doživite jednu od najvećih Sonicovih avantura u potpuno novoj svjetlosti sa Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Izdano 2019. godine od strane Eukaryot, Sonic 3 A.I.R., je potpuni PC port klasičnog Sega Genesis iz 1994. (i Knuckles) koji ima široku ekrana i glatko klizanje. Osim toga, dodane su filtri ekrana, grafička poboljšanja, podrška za uspjehe, većina promjena iz Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, Knuckles i Tails moda, te podrška za Sonic Mania drop dash i modove.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>Torna a experimentar una de les majors aventures de Sonic en una llum completament nova amb Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Llançat el 2019 per Eukaryot, Sonic 3 A.I.R., és un port PC complet del clàssic de Sega Genesis de 1994 (i Knuckles) que té pantalla panoràmica i desplaçament suau. A més, s'han afegit filtres de pantalla, millores gràfiques, suport d'assoliment, la majoria dels canvis de Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, mode Knuckles i Tails, suport de Sonic Mania drop dash i mods.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Erleben Sie eines von Sonics größten Abenteuer neu im völlig neuen Licht mit Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Sonic 3 A.I.R., das 2019 von Eukaryot veröffentlicht wurde, ist ein vollständiger PC-Port des klassischen Sega Genesis von 1994 (und Knuckles), das Breitbildschirm und reibungslose Bildläufe bietet. Darüber hinaus wurden Bildschirmfilter, Grafikverbesserungen, Erfolgsunterstützung, die meisten Änderungen aus Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, Knuckles- und Tails-Modus, Sonic Mania's Drop-Dash- und Mod-Unterstützung hinzugefügt.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>Vuelve a experimentar una de las mayores aventuras de Sonic en una luz completamente nueva con Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Lanzado en 2019 por Eukaryot, Sonic 3 A.I.R., es un puerto de PC completo del clásico de Sega Genesis de 1994 (y Knuckles) que presume de pantalla ancha y desplazamiento suave. Además, se han añadido filtros de pantalla, mejoras gráficas, soporte de logros, la mayoría de los cambios de Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, modo Knuckles y Tails, soporte de Sonic Mania drop dash y mods.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>Revivez l'une des plus grandes aventures de Sonic sous une toute nouvelle lumière avec Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Lancé en 2019 par Eukaryot, Sonic 3 A.I.R., est un port PC complet du classique Sega Genesis de 1994 (et Knuckles) qui vante un écran large et un défilement fluide. De plus, les filtres d'écran, les améliorations graphiques, le support des réalisations, la plupart des modifications de Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, le mode Knuckles et Tails, le support du Sonic Mania drop dash et les mods ont été ajoutés.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>Ponovno doživite jednu od najvećih Sonicovih avantura u potpuno novoj svjetlosti sa Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Izdano 2019. godine od strane Eukaryot, Sonic 3 A.I.R., je potpuni PC port klasičnog Sega Genesis iz 1994. (i Knuckles) koji ima široku ekrana i glatko klizanje. Osim toga, dodane su filtri ekrana, grafička poboljšanja, podrška za uspjehe, većina promjena iz Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, Knuckles i Tails moda, te podrška za Sonic Mania drop dash i modove.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Rivisita una delle più grandi avventure di Sonic sotto una luce completamente nuova con Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Lancio nel 2019 da Eukaryot, Sonic 3 A.I.R., è un port PC completo del classico Sega Genesis del 1994 (e Knuckles) che vanta schermo panoramico e scorrimento fluido. Inoltre, sono stati aggiunti filtri dello schermo, miglioramenti grafici, supporto dei risultati, la maggior parte dei cambiamenti da Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, modalità Knuckles e Tails, supporto di Sonic Mania drop dash e mod.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited（A.I.R.）を使用して、Sonicの最大の冒険の1つをまったく新しい光で再体験してください。

2019年にEukaryotがリリースした、Sonic 3 A.I.R.は、1994年のSega Genesis古典（およびKnuckles）の完全なPCポートであり、ワイドスクリーンとスムーズなスクロールを備えています。さらに、スクリーンフィルター、グラフィック改善、達成サポート、Sonic 3 Completeからのほとんどのchangeschanges、Time Trials、KnucklesおよびTailsモード、Sonic Maniaドロップダッシュおよびmodサポートが追加されました。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.)를 사용하여 Sonic의 가장 위대한 모험 중 하나를 완전히 새로운 빛으로 다시 경험하세요.

Eukaryot가 2019년에 출시한 Sonic 3 A.I.R.는 1994년 Sega Genesis 클래식 (및 Knuckles)의 완전한 PC 포트로 와이드스크린과 부드러운 스크롤을 자랑합니다. 또한 화면 필터, 그래픽 개선 사항, 성취 지원, Sonic 3 Complete의 대부분의 변경 사항, Time Trials, Knuckles 및 Tails 모드, Sonic Mania drop dash 및 mod 지원이 추가되었습니다.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>Herbeleef een van Sonics grootste avonturen in een geheel nieuw licht met Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Sonic 3 A.I.R., uitgebracht in 2019 door Eukaryot, is een volledige PC-port van de klassieke Sega Genesis uit 1994 (en Knuckles) met breedbeeldscherm en soepel scrollen. Daarnaast zijn schermfilters, grafische verbeteringen, prestatie-ondersteuning, de meeste wijzigingen van Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, Knuckles- en Tails-modus, Sonic Mania drop dash- en mod-ondersteuning toegevoegd.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Przeżyj na nowo jedną z największych przygód Sonika w zupełnie nowym świetle dzięki Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Sonic 3 A.I.R., wydany w 2019 roku przez Eukaryot, jest pełnym portem PC klasycznego Sega Genesis z 1994 roku (i Knuckles) z szerokim ekranem i gładkim przewijaniem. Ponadto dodano filtry ekranu, ulepszenia grafiki, wsparcie dla osiągnięć, większość zmian z Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, tryb Knuckles i Tails, obsługę Sonic Mania drop dash i modów.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>Reviva uma das maiores aventuras de Sonic sob uma luz completamente nova com Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Lançado em 2019 por Eukaryot, Sonic 3 A.I.R. é uma porta PC completa do clássico Sega Genesis de 1994 (e Knuckles) que possui tela panorâmica e rolagem suave. Além disso, foram adicionados filtros de tela, melhorias gráficas, suporte de conquistas, a maioria das alterações de Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, modo Knuckles e Tails, suporte de Sonic Mania drop dash e mods.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Retrăiți una dintre cele mai mari aventuri ale Sonic-ului sub o lumină complet nouă cu Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Lansat în 2019 de Eukaryot, Sonic 3 A.I.R. este un port PC complet al clasicului Sega Genesis din 1994 (și Knuckles) care se mândrește cu ecran lat și derulare lin. În plus, au fost adăugate filtre de ecran, îmbunătățiri grafice, suport pentru realizări, cea mai mare parte din modificările din Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, modul Knuckles și Tails, suport pentru Sonic Mania drop dash și moduri.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Переживите одно из величайших приключений Sonic в совершенно новом свете с помощью Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Sonic 3 A.I.R., выпущенный в 2019 году компанией Eukaryot, представляет собой полный порт на ПК классического Sega Genesis 1994 года (и Knuckles), который имеет широкоэкранный дисплей и плавную прокрутку. Кроме того, были добавлены фильтры экрана, графические улучшения, поддержка достижений, большинство изменений из Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, режим Knuckles и Tails, поддержка Sonic Mania drop dash и модов.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>Поново доживите једну од највећих Соничиних авантура у потпуно новој светлости са Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Објављено 2019. године од стране Eukaryot-а, Sonic 3 A.I.R., је потпуни PC порт класичног Sega Genesis-а из 1994. (и Knuckles) који има широко екранску поддршку и глатко скроловање. Поред тога, додани су филтери екрана, графичка побољшања, подршка за достигнућа, већина промена из Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, Knuckles и Tails режима, подршка за Sonic Mania drop dash и модове.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>Gjenupplev ett av Sonics största äventyr i helt nytt ljus med Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited (A.I.R.).

Utgivet 2019 av Eukaryot, Sonic 3 A.I.R., är en fullständig PC-port av den klassiska Sega Genesis från 1994 (och Knuckles) med bredd skärm och smooth scrolling. Dessutom har skärmfilter, grafiska förbättringar, prestationsstöd, de flesta ändringar från Sonic 3 Complete, Time Trials, Knuckles och Tails-läge, stöd för Sonic Mania drop dash och mods lagts till.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>在Sonic 3 Angel Island Revisited（A.I.R.）的全新光芒中重新体验Sonic最伟大的冒险之一。

由Eukaryot在2019年发布，Sonic 3 A.I.R.是1994年Sega Genesis经典（和Knuckles）的完整PC端口，配备宽屏和流畅滚动。此外，还添加了屏幕过滤器、图形改进、成就支持、Sonic 3 Complete的大部分更改、Time Trials、Knuckles和Tails模式、Sonic Mania的Drop Dash和Mod支持。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
