<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Star Engine</systemName>
    <systemDescription>The Sonic Retro Engine (currently known as the Star Engine) is an engine created by "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). It is designed to deliver features from the 32-bit console era and below, and focuses on things like raster effects, palette manipulations, 'mode 7', and other features of retro games from back then, unlike modern engines today. The engine is multi-platform, and it fully supports modern essentials such as widescreen and online functionality. The Taxman and Stealth (Simon Thomley) remade and remastered Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) for Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS, and Android, Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) for iOS and Android, and Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) for iOS and Android using the Retro Engine. These new features for the games include upgraded graphics, widescreen display, 60 fps, remastered soundtracks, and many more features.

In January 2021, 3 games based on Retro Engine were reverse engineered. The user Rubberduckycooly released two projects on GitHub: one for Sonic 1 and 2, and the other for Sonic CD. Despite binaries being freely available, the player is still required to obtain a copy of the game's data through official sources such as Google Play, AppStore or Steam.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Christian Whitehead</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>2021</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-engine}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>محرك Sonic Retro (المعروف حالياً باسم Star Engine) هو محرك أنشأه "ذا تاكسمان" (Christian Whitehead). تم تصميمه لتقديم ميزات من عصر أجهزة الكونسول 32-بت والأقدم، ويركز على أمور مثل تأثيرات الراستر، ومعالجات لوحات الألوان، و"مود 7"، وميزات أخرى للألعاب الكلاسيكية من تلك الحقبة، بخلاف المحركات الحديثة اليوم. المحرك متعدد الأنظمة ويدعم أساسيات حديثة مثل العرض بعريض الشاشة والوظائف عبر الإنترنت. قام The Taxman وStealth (Simon Thomley) بإعادة صنع وإعادة تحسين Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) لـ Xbox Live Arcade وPlayStation Network وiOS وAndroid، وكذلك Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) وSonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) لإصدارات الهواتف باستخدام Retro Engine. تشمل الميزات الجديدة لهذه الإصدارات تحسين الرسومات، ودعم العرض بعريض الشاشة، وتشغيل بمعدل 60 إطارًا في الثانية، وإعادة مزج المسارات الصوتية، والعديد من الميزات الأخرى.

في يناير 2021، تم عكس هندسة 3 ألعاب مبنية على Retro Engine. نشر المستخدم Rubberduckycooly مشروعين على GitHub: أحدهما لسونيك 1 و2، والآخر لـ Sonic CD. على الرغم من توفر الثنائيات مجانًا، يظل مطلوبًا من اللاعب الحصول على نسخة من بيانات اللعبة من مصادر رسمية مثل Google Play أو AppStore أو Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>Sonic Retro Engine (trenutno poznat kao Star Engine) je engine kojeg je napravio "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). Dizajniran je da pruži mogućnosti iz ere 32-bitnih konzola i ranijih generacija, fokusirajući se na efekte poput raster efekata, manipulaciju paletama, 'mode 7' i druge karakteristike retro igara iz tog vremena, za razliku od modernih engine-a danas. Engine je multiplatformski i potpuno podržava moderne ključne funkcije poput widescreen prikaza i online mogućnosti. The Taxman i Stealth (Simon Thomley) su preradili i remasterirali Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) za Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS i Android, te Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) i Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) za iOS i Android koristeći Retro Engine. Nove funkcije uključuju unaprijeđenu grafiku, widescreen prikaz, 60 fps, remasterirane soundtrackove i mnoge druge.

U januaru 2021., tri igre bazirane na Retro Engineu su bile reverzno inženjerisane. Korisnik Rubberduckycooly je objavio dva projekta na GitHubu: jedan za Sonic 1 i 2, a drugi za Sonic CD. Iako su binarni fajlovi slobodno dostupni, igrač i dalje mora nabaviti kopiju podataka igre iz službenih izvora kao što su Google Play, AppStore ili Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>L'Enginy Sonic Retro (actualment conegut com a Star Engine) és un motor creat per "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). Està dissenyat per oferir característiques de l'època de les consoles de 32 bits i anteriors, i es centra en efectes com raster, manipulacions de paleta, 'mode 7' i altres característiques dels jocs retro d'aquella època, a diferència dels motors moderns d'avui. El motor és multiplataforma i dóna suport complet a essencials moderns com la pantalla panoràmica i la funcionalitat en línia. The Taxman i Stealth (Simon Thomley) van refer i remasteritzar Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) per a Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS i Android, Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) per a iOS i Android, i Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) per a iOS i Android utilitzant el Retro Engine. Aquestes noves característiques inclouen gràfics millorats, pantalla panoràmica, 60 ips, bandes sonores remasteritzades i moltes altres funcions.

Al gener de 2021, tres jocs basats en Retro Engine van ser enginyeria inversa. L'usuari Rubberduckycooly va publicar dos projectes a GitHub: un per a Sonic 1 i 2 i un altre per a Sonic CD. Tot i que els binaris estan disponibles lliurement, el jugador encara ha d'obtenir una còpia de les dades del joc a través de fonts oficials com Google Play, AppStore o Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Die Sonic Retro Engine (derzeit bekannt als Star Engine) ist eine Engine, erstellt von "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). Sie wurde entwickelt, um Funktionen aus der Ära der 32-Bit-Konsolen und älter bereitzustellen, und legt den Schwerpunkt auf Dinge wie Rastereffekte, Palette-Manipulationen, 'Mode 7' und andere Merkmale klassischer Spiele jener Zeit – im Gegensatz zu modernen Engines heute. Die Engine ist plattformübergreifend und unterstützt moderne Grundlagen wie Breitbildauflösung und Online-Funktionalität vollständig. The Taxman und Stealth (Simon Thomley) überarbeiteten und remasterten Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) für Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS und Android sowie Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) und Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) für iOS und Android mit der Retro Engine. Zu den neuen Features zählen verbesserte Grafik, Breitbilddarstellung, 60 fps, remasterte Soundtracks und viele weitere Funktionen.

Im Januar 2021 wurden drei auf der Retro Engine basierende Spiele reverse-engineered. Der Nutzer Rubberduckycooly veröffentlichte zwei Projekte auf GitHub: eines für Sonic 1 und 2 und ein anderes für Sonic CD. Obwohl die Binärdateien frei verfügbar sind, muss der Spieler dennoch eine Kopie der Spieldaten aus offiziellen Quellen wie Google Play, AppStore oder Steam beziehen.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>El Sonic Retro Engine (conocido actualmente como Star Engine) es un motor creado por "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). Está diseñado para ofrecer características de la era de las consolas de 32 bits y anteriores, y se enfoca en elementos como efectos raster, manipulaciones de paleta, 'mode 7' y otras características de los juegos retro de aquella época, a diferencia de los motores modernos actuales. El motor es multiplataforma y admite completamente funciones modernas esenciales como pantalla panorámica y funcionalidad en línea. The Taxman y Stealth (Simon Thomley) rehicieron y remasterizaron Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) para Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS y Android, Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) para iOS y Android, y Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) para iOS y Android usando el Retro Engine. Estas nuevas características incluyen gráficos mejorados, pantalla panorámica, 60 fps, bandas sonoras remasterizadas y muchas más.

En enero de 2021, 3 juegos basados en Retro Engine fueron sometidos a ingeniería inversa. El usuario Rubberduckycooly lanzó dos proyectos en GitHub: uno para Sonic 1 y 2 y otro para Sonic CD. A pesar de que los binarios están disponibles gratuitamente, el jugador aún debe obtener una copia de los datos del juego a través de fuentes oficiales como Google Play, AppStore o Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>Le Sonic Retro Engine (connu actuellement sous le nom de Star Engine) est un moteur créé par "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). Il est conçu pour fournir des fonctionnalités de l'ère des consoles 32 bits et antérieures, et se concentre sur des éléments tels que les effets raster, la manipulation des palettes, le « mode 7 » et d'autres caractéristiques des jeux rétro de cette époque, contrairement aux moteurs modernes actuels. Le moteur est multiplateforme et prend en charge les éléments essentiels modernes tels que l'écran large et les fonctionnalités en ligne. The Taxman et Stealth (Simon Thomley) ont refait et remasterisé Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) pour Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS et Android, ainsi que Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) et Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) pour iOS et Android en utilisant le Retro Engine. Ces nouvelles fonctionnalités incluent des graphismes améliorés, un affichage en grand format, 60 ips, des bandes-son remasterisées et bien d'autres.

En janvier 2021, trois jeux basés sur le Retro Engine ont été rétroconçus (reverse engineered). L'utilisateur Rubberduckycooly a publié deux projets sur GitHub : l'un pour Sonic 1 et 2, et l'autre pour Sonic CD. Bien que les binaires soient librement disponibles, le joueur doit toujours obtenir une copie des données du jeu via des sources officielles telles que Google Play, AppStore ou Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>Sonic Retro Engine (trenutno poznat kao Star Engine) engine je kojeg je stvorio "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). Dizajniran je da pruži značajke iz ere 32-bitnih konzola i ranijih generacija, fokusirajući se na raster efekte, manipulacije paletom, 'mode 7' i druge karakteristike retro igara iz tog vremena, za razliku od modernih engine-a danas. Engine je multiplatformski i u potpunosti podržava suvremene bitne funkcije poput widescreen prikaza i online mogućnosti. The Taxman i Stealth (Simon Thomley) preradili su i remasterirali Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) za Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS i Android, te Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) i Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) za iOS i Android koristeći Retro Engine. Nove značajke uključuju poboljšanu grafiku, widescreen prikaz, 60 fps, remasterirane soundtrackove i mnoge druge.

U siječnju 2021. tri igre temeljene na Retro Engineu su bile reverzno inženjerirane. Korisnik Rubberduckycooly objavio je dva projekta na GitHubu: jedan za Sonic 1 i 2, a drugi za Sonic CD. Iako su binarni fajlovi slobodno dostupni, igrač i dalje mora pribaviti kopiju podataka igre iz službenih izvora poput Google Play, AppStore ili Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Il Sonic Retro Engine (attualmente noto come Star Engine) è un motore creato da "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). È progettato per offrire funzionalità dell'era delle console a 32 bit e precedenti, e si concentra su elementi come effetti raster, manipolazione delle palette, 'mode 7' e altre caratteristiche dei giochi retrò di quel periodo, a differenza dei motori moderni odierni. Il motore è multipiattaforma e supporta pienamente le funzionalità moderne essenziali come il widescreen e il supporto online. The Taxman e Stealth (Simon Thomley) hanno rimasterizzato e rifatto Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) per Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS e Android, Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) per iOS e Android, e Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) per iOS e Android usando il Retro Engine. Tra le nuove funzionalità ci sono grafica migliorata, visualizzazione widescreen, 60 fps, colonne sonore rimasterizzate e molte altre funzioni.

A gennaio 2021, 3 giochi basati su Retro Engine sono stati reverse engineered. L'utente Rubberduckycooly ha rilasciato due progetti su GitHub: uno per Sonic 1 e 2, e un altro per Sonic CD. Nonostante i binari siano liberamente disponibili, il giocatore deve comunque procurarsi una copia dei dati del gioco da fonti ufficiali come Google Play, AppStore o Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>（通称 Star Engine）として現在知られている Sonic Retro Engine は、"The Taxman"（Christian Whitehead）によって作られたエンジンです。32ビットコンソール時代以前の表現を再現することを目的に設計されており、ラスター効果、パレット操作、"mode 7"、および当時のレトロゲームに見られるその他の特徴に重点を置いています。現代のエンジンとは異なるアプローチを取っています。エンジンはマルチプラットフォームで、ワイドスクリーン表示やオンライン機能などの現代的な必須機能を完全にサポートします。The Taxman と Stealth（Simon Thomley）は Retro Engine を使用して、Sonic the Hedgehog CD（2011）（Xbox Live Arcade、PlayStation Network、iOS、Android）や Sonic the Hedgehog（2013）（iOS、Android）、Sonic the Hedgehog 2（2013）（iOS、Android）をリメイク／リマスターしました。これらの新機能には、グラフィックの向上、ワイドスクリーン表示、60fps、リマスターされたサウンドトラックなど多くの改善が含まれます。

2021年1月、Retro Engine をベースにした3つのゲームがリバースエンジニアリングされました。ユーザー Rubberduckycooly は GitHub に2つのプロジェクトを公開しました：Sonic 1 と 2 用のプロジェクトと、Sonic CD 用のプロジェクトです。バイナリが自由に入手可能であっても、プレイヤーは公式の配信元（Google Play、AppStore、Steam など）からゲームデータのコピーを入手する必要があります。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>Sonic Retro Engine(현재 Star Engine으로 알려짐)는 "The Taxman"(Christian Whitehead)가 만든 엔진입니다. 이 엔진은 32비트 콘솔 시기 및 그 이전 시대의 기능을 재현하도록 설계되었으며, 래스터 효과, 팔레트 조작, 'mode 7' 등 당시 레트로 게임의 특징들에 중점을 둡니다. 현대 엔진과는 다른 접근을 취합니다. 이 엔진은 멀티플랫폼을 지원하며 와이드스크린 및 온라인 기능과 같은 현대적인 필수 기능을 완전히 지원합니다. The Taxman과 Stealth(Simon Thomley)는 Retro Engine을 사용해 Sonic the Hedgehog CD(2011)를 Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS 및 Android용으로 리메이크·리마스터했고, Sonic the Hedgehog(2013)와 Sonic the Hedgehog 2(2013)도 iOS 및 Android용으로 제작했습니다. 이러한 새 기능에는 향상된 그래픽, 와이드스크린 표시, 60fps, 리마스터된 사운드트랙 등 많은 개선사항이 포함됩니다。

2021년 1월, Retro Engine 기반의 3개 게임이 리버스 엔지니어링되었습니다. 사용자 Rubberduckycooly는 GitHub에 두 개의 프로젝트를 공개했는데, 하나는 Sonic 1과 2용, 다른 하나는 Sonic CD용입니다. 바이너리가 자유롭게 제공되더라도 플레이어는 Google Play, AppStore 또는 Steam과 같은 공식 소스에서 게임 데이터의 사본을 획득해야 합니다。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>De Sonic Retro Engine (nu bekend als Star Engine) is een engine gemaakt door "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). Hij is ontworpen om functies uit het tijdperk van 32-bit consoles en ouder te leveren, en richt zich op zaken als rastereffecten, paletmanipulatie, 'mode 7' en andere kenmerken van retrospellen uit die tijd, in tegenstelling tot moderne engines van vandaag. De engine is multiplatform en ondersteunt volledig moderne essentiële functies zoals widescreen en online functionaliteit. The Taxman en Stealth (Simon Thomley) hebben Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) voor Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS en Android, en Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) en Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) voor iOS en Android opnieuw gemaakt en geremasterd met de Retro Engine. Deze nieuwe functies omvatten verbeterde graphics, widescreen-weergave, 60 fps, geremasterde soundtracks en nog veel meer.

In januari 2021 zijn drie op de Retro Engine gebaseerde spellen gereverse-engineered. Gebruiker Rubberduckycooly publiceerde twee projecten op GitHub: één voor Sonic 1 en 2 en één voor Sonic CD. Hoewel de binaries vrij beschikbaar zijn, moet de speler nog steeds een kopie van de spelgegevens verkrijgen via officiële bronnen zoals Google Play, AppStore of Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Sonic Retro Engine (obecnie znany jako Star Engine) to silnik stworzony przez "The Taxman" (Christiana Whiteheada). Został zaprojektowany tak, aby odtwarzać cechy z ery konsol 32-bitowych i wcześniejszych, koncentrując się na efektach rastrowych, manipulacji paletami, 'mode 7' i innych cechach retro gier z tamtego okresu, w odróżnieniu od współczesnych silników. Silnik jest wieloplatformowy i w pełni obsługuje nowoczesne podstawowe funkcje, takie jak szerokoekranowy tryb i funkcjonalność online. The Taxman i Stealth (Simon Thomley) odtworzyli i zremasterowali Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) dla Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS i Android oraz Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) i Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) dla iOS i Android przy użyciu Retro Engine. Nowe funkcje obejmują ulepszoną grafikę, tryb szerokoekranowy, 60 fps, zremasterowane ścieżki dźwiękowe i wiele innych.

W styczniu 2021 roku trzy gry oparte na Retro Engine zostały poddane inżynierii wstecznej. Użytkownik Rubberduckycooly opublikował dwa projekty na GitHubie: jeden dla Sonic 1 i 2 oraz drugi dla Sonic CD. Pomimo że pliki binarne są ogólnie dostępne, gracz nadal musi uzyskać kopię danych gry z oficjalnych źródeł, takich jak Google Play, AppStore lub Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>O Sonic Retro Engine (actualmente conhecido como Star Engine) é um motor criado por "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). Foi concebido para oferecer funcionalidades da era das consolas de 32 bits e anteriores, e foca-se em elementos como efeitos raster, manipulação de paletas, 'mode 7' e outras características dos jogos retro dessa época, em contraste com os motores modernos atuais. O motor é multiplataforma e suporta integralmente funcionalidades modernas essenciais, como ecrã panorâmico e capacidades online. The Taxman e Stealth (Simon Thomley) refizeram e remasterizaram Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) para Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS e Android; e Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) e Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) para iOS e Android usando o Retro Engine. Estas novas funcionalidades incluem gráficos melhorados, suporte widescreen, 60 fps, bandas sonoras remasterizadas e muitas outras.

Em janeiro de 2021, 3 jogos baseados no Retro Engine foram alvo de engenharia reversa. O utilizador Rubberduckycooly lançou dois projectos no GitHub: um para Sonic 1 e 2 e outro para Sonic CD. Apesar de os binários estarem livremente disponíveis, o jogador ainda tem de obter uma cópia dos dados do jogo através de fontes oficiais como Google Play, AppStore ou Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Sonic Retro Engine (cunoscut în prezent ca Star Engine) este un motor creat de "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). A fost proiectat pentru a reproduce caracteristici din era consolelor pe 32 de biți și anterioare, concentrându-se pe efecte raster, manipulări de paletă, 'mode 7' și alte caracteristici ale jocurilor retro din acea perioadă, spre deosebire de motoarele moderne de azi. Motorul este multiplatformă și suportă pe deplin elementele moderne esențiale, cum ar fi afișajul widescreen și funcționalitatea online. The Taxman și Stealth (Simon Thomley) au refăcut și remasterizat Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) pentru Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS și Android, precum și Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) și Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) pentru iOS și Android folosind Retro Engine. Noile funcții includ grafică îmbunătățită, afișaj widescreen, 60 fps, coloane sonore remasterizate și multe altele.

În ianuarie 2021, trei jocuri bazate pe Retro Engine au fost revers-engineered. Utilizatorul Rubberduckycooly a publicat două proiecte pe GitHub: unul pentru Sonic 1 și 2 și altul pentru Sonic CD. Deși binarele sunt disponibile gratuit, jucătorul trebuie în continuare să obțină o copie a datelor jocului din surse oficiale precum Google Play, AppStore sau Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Движок Sonic Retro (в настоящее время известный как Star Engine) создан "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). Он разработан для воспроизведения возможностей эпохи 32-битных консолей и ранее, с акцентом на растровые эффекты, манипуляции палитрой, «mode 7» и другие особенности ретро-игр того времени, в отличие от современных движков. Движок кроссплатформенный и полностью поддерживает современные базовые функции, такие как широкоформатный режим и онлайн-функциональность. The Taxman и Stealth (Simon Thomley) переработали и ремастировали Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) для Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS и Android, а также Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) и Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) для iOS и Android с использованием Retro Engine. Эти новые функции включают улучшенную графику, поддержку широкоформатного отображения, 60 fps, ремастерованные саундтреки и многое другое.

В январе 2021 года три игры на базе Retro Engine были подвергнуты реверс-инжинирингу. Пользователь Rubberduckycooly выпустил два проекта на GitHub: один для Sonic 1 и 2, другой для Sonic CD. Несмотря на свободную доступность бинарных файлов, игрок все ещё обязан получить копию игровых данных из официальных источников, таких как Google Play, AppStore или Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>Соник Ретро Енгине (сада познат као Star Engine) је енџин који је направио "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). Дизајниран је да пружи могућности из ере 32-битних конзола и ранијих, фокусирајући се на растер ефекте, манипулације палетом, 'mode 7' и друге карактеристике ретро игара из тог доба, за разлику од модерних енџина данас. Енџин је мултиплатформски и у потпуности подржава модерне битне функције као што су widescreen приказ и онлајн функционалност. The Taxman и Stealth (Simon Thomley) су прерадили и ремастерирали Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) за Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS и Android, као и Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) и Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) за iOS и Android користећи Retro Engine. Нове функције укључују побољшану графику, widescreen приказ, 60 fps, ремастероване звучне записе и много више.

У јануару 2021. три игре засноване на Retro Engine-у су биле реверс инжењеринговане. Корисник Rubberduckycooly је објавио два пројекта на GitHub-у: један за Sonic 1 и 2 и други за Sonic CD. Иако су бинарни фајлови доступни бесплатно, играч ипак мора да набави копију података игре из званичних извора као што су Google Play, AppStore или Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>Sonic Retro Engine (numera känt som Star Engine) är en motor skapad av "The Taxman" (Christian Whitehead). Den är utformad för att återge funktioner från 32-bitarskonsolernas era och tidigare, och fokuserar på saker som rastereffekter, palettmanipulation, 'mode 7' och andra egenskaper hos retrospel från den tiden, till skillnad från moderna motorer idag. Motorn är plattformsoberoende och stöder fullt ut moderna nödvändigheter som widescreen och online-funktionalitet. The Taxman och Stealth (Simon Thomley) gjorde om och remastrade Sonic the Hedgehog CD (2011) för Xbox Live Arcade, PlayStation Network, iOS och Android, samt Sonic the Hedgehog (2013) och Sonic the Hedgehog 2 (2013) för iOS och Android med Retro Engine. Dessa nya funktioner inkluderar förbättrad grafik, widescreen-visning, 60 fps, remastrade ljudspår och mycket mer.

I januari 2021 blev tre spel baserade på Retro Engine reverse-engineered. Användaren Rubberduckycooly publicerade två projekt på GitHub: ett för Sonic 1 och 2 och ett annat för Sonic CD. Trots att binärfilerna finns fritt tillgängliga måste spelaren fortfarande skaffa en kopia av spelets data från officiella källor som Google Play, AppStore eller Steam.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>Sonic Retro 引擎（目前以 Star Engine 名义为人所知）是由 "The Taxman"（Christian Whitehead）创建的引擎。它旨在重现 32 位主机时代及更早期的特性，侧重于光栅效果、调色板操作、“mode 7”以及当时复古游戏的其他特征，这与现代引擎的设计不同。该引擎为跨平台，并完全支持如宽屏显示和在线功能等现代必需项。The Taxman 与 Stealth（Simon Thomley）使用 Retro Engine 对 Sonic the Hedgehog CD（2011）进行了重制与重混，面向 Xbox Live Arcade、PlayStation Network、iOS 与 Android；同时也以该引擎重制了 Sonic the Hedgehog（2013）和 Sonic the Hedgehog 2（2013）用于 iOS 与 Android。新特性包括升级后的图像、宽屏支持、60 fps、重制的原声带等许多改进。

2021 年 1 月，基于 Retro Engine 的 3 款游戏被反向工程化。用户 Rubberduckycooly 在 GitHub 上发布了两个项目：一个用于 Sonic 1 与 2，另一个用于 Sonic CD。尽管二进制文件可自由获取，玩家仍需通过官方来源（如 Google Play、AppStore 或 Steam）获取游戏数据的副本。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
