<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>System SP</systemName>
    <systemDescription>The Sega System SP, also known as the Aurora, is an arcade system board developed by Sega. It is essentially a “Dreamcast-on-a-chip,” featuring the same SH-4 CPU and PowerVR2 GPU as the Sega Dreamcast console. This system was designed to be versatile, supporting various arcade game formats and configurations.

It was used in a range of arcade games, including some that involved gambling, ticket redemption, and children’s attractions. The Sega System SP was manufactured until 2014 and is notable for its compact and efficient design.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Sega</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>2004</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-emulator}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>لوحة ألعاب الأركيد Sega System SP، المعروفة أيضًا باسم Aurora، هي لوحة أنظمة طورتها شركة Sega. هي أساسًا "دريمكاست على رقاقة"، وتضم نفس معالج SH-4 ووحدة رسومية PowerVR2 كما في جهاز Sega Dreamcast. صُممت هذه المنصة لتكون متعددة الاستخدامات، داعمة لأشكال وتكوينات الألعاب الأركيدية المتنوعة.

استُخدمت في مجموعة من ألعاب الأركيد، بما في ذلك بعضها الذي شمل المقامرة، واسترداد التذاكر، ومعارض للأطفال. تم تصنيع Sega System SP حتى عام 2014 وتُعرف بتصميمها المدمج والكفء.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>Sega System SP, također poznat kao Aurora, je arcade matična ploča razvijena od strane Sega-e. U suštini predstavlja "Dreamcast-on-a-chip", s istim SH-4 CPU-om i PowerVR2 GPU-om kao Sega Dreamcast konzola. Ovaj sistem je dizajniran da bude svestran, podržavajući razne formate i konfiguracije arkadnih igara.

Koristio se u nizu arkadnih igara, uključujući neke koje su uključivale kockanje, povrat bonova i atrakcije za djecu. Sega System SP je proizvođen do 2014. i poznat je po svom kompaktnom i efikasnom dizajnu.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>El Sega System SP, també conegut com a Aurora, és una placa de sistema d'arcade desenvolupada per Sega. És essencialment un "Dreamcast-en-un-xip", amb la mateixa CPU SH-4 i GPU PowerVR2 que la consola Sega Dreamcast. Aquest sistema va ser dissenyat per ser versàtil, admetent diversos formats i configuracions de jocs d'arcade.

Es va utilitzar en una sèrie de jocs d'arcade, inclosos alguns que implicaven jocs d'atzar, canvi de tiquets i atraccions infantils. Sega System SP es va fabricar fins al 2014 i destaca per disseny compacte i eficient.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Das Sega System SP, auch als Aurora bekannt, ist ein Arcade-Systemboard, das von Sega entwickelt wurde. Es ist im Wesentlichen ein "Dreamcast-on-a-chip" und verfügt über die gleiche SH-4-CPU und PowerVR2-GPU wie die Sega Dreamcast-Konsole. Dieses System wurde so konzipiert, dass es vielseitig ist und verschiedene Arcade-Spielformate und -konfigurationen unterstützt.

Es wurde in einer Reihe von Arcade-Spielen eingesetzt, darunter einige mit Glücksspiel, Ticket-Einlösung und Kinderattraktionen. Das Sega System SP wurde bis 2014 hergestellt und ist für sein kompaktes und effizientes Design bekannt.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>El Sega System SP, también conocido como Aurora, es una placa de sistema arcade desarrollada por Sega. Es esencialmente un "Dreamcast-en-un-chip", con la misma CPU SH-4 y GPU PowerVR2 que la consola Sega Dreamcast. Este sistema fue diseñado para ser versátil, soportando varios formatos y configuraciones de juegos arcade.

Se utilizó en una variedad de juegos arcade, incluyendo algunos que implicaban apuestas, canje de tickets y atracciones infantiles. El Sega System SP se fabricó hasta 2014 y es notable por su diseño compacto y eficiente.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>Le Sega System SP, également connu sous le nom d'Aurora, est une carte système d'arcade développée par Sega. C'est essentiellement un "Dreamcast-on-a-chip", disposant du même CPU SH-4 et du GPU PowerVR2 que la console Sega Dreamcast. Ce système a été conçu pour être polyvalent, prenant en charge divers formats et configurations de jeux d'arcade.

Il a été utilisé dans une gamme de jeux d'arcade, y compris certains impliquant des jeux d'argent, l'échange de tickets et des attractions pour enfants. Le Sega System SP a été fabriqué jusqu'en 2014 et est notable pour son design compact et efficace.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>Sega System SP, poznat i kao Aurora, je arcade matična ploča koju je razvila tvrtka Sega. U suštini je to "Dreamcast-on-a-chip", s istim SH-4 CPU-om i PowerVR2 GPU-om kao konzola Sega Dreamcast. Ovaj sustav je dizajniran da bude svestran, podržavajući razne arkadne formate i konfiguracije.

Koristio se u nizu arkadnih igara, uključujući neke koje su uključivale kockanje, otkup karata i dječje atrakcije. Sega System SP se proizvodio do 2014. i poznat je po kompaktnom i učinkovitom dizajnu.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Il Sega System SP, noto anche come Aurora, è una scheda di sistema arcade sviluppata da Sega. È fondamentalmente un "Dreamcast-on-a-chip", con la stessa CPU SH-4 e GPU PowerVR2 della console Sega Dreamcast. Questo sistema è stato progettato per essere versatile, supportando vari formati e configurazioni di giochi arcade.

È stato utilizzato in una serie di giochi arcade, inclusi alcuni che prevedevano giochi d'azzardo, riscossione di biglietti e attrazioni per bambini. Il Sega System SP è stato prodotto fino al 2014 ed è noto per il suo design compatto ed efficiente.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>Sega System SP（オーロラとも呼ばれる）は、Sega によって開発されたアーケード用システムボードです。基本的には「チップ上のドリームキャスト」であり、Sega Dreamcast 本体と同じ SH-4 CPU と PowerVR2 GPU を搭載しています。本システムは多用途に設計され、さまざまなアーケードゲームの形式や構成に対応します。

ギャンブル要素、チケット交換、子供向けアトラクションなどを含む幅広いアーケードゲームで使用されました。Sega System SP は 2014 年まで製造され、そのコンパクトで効率的な設計が特長です。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>Sega System SP(오로라라고도 알려짐)는 Sega에서 개발한 아케이드 시스템 보드입니다. 본질적으로 "칩 위의 드림캐스트"로, Sega Dreamcast 콘솔과 동일한 SH-4 CPU 및 PowerVR2 GPU를 탑재하고 있습니다. 이 시스템은 다양한 아케이드 게임 형식과 구성을 지원하도록 설계되어 다목적으로 사용될 수 있습니다.

도박, 티켓 교환, 어린이용 어트랙션 등이 포함된 다양한 아케이드 게임에서 사용되었습니다. Sega System SP는 2014년까지 제조되었으며 소형화되고 효율적인 설계로 유명합니다。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>De Sega System SP, ook bekend als Aurora, is een arcade-systeemkaart ontwikkeld door Sega. Het is in wezen een "Dreamcast-on-a-chip", met dezelfde SH-4 CPU en PowerVR2 GPU als de Sega Dreamcast-console. Dit systeem is ontworpen om veelzijdig te zijn en ondersteunt verschillende arcade-spelformaten en configuraties.

Het werd gebruikt in een reeks arcade-spellen, waaronder sommige met gokken, ticketinwisseling en kinderattracties. De Sega System SP werd geproduceerd tot 2014 en staat bekend om zijn compacte en efficiënte ontwerp.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Sega System SP, znany również jako Aurora, to płyta systemowa arcade opracowana przez firmę Sega. W istocie jest to „Dreamcast-on-a-chip”, wyposażony w ten sam procesor SH-4 i GPU PowerVR2 co konsola Sega Dreamcast. System ten został zaprojektowany jako wszechstronny, obsługujący różne formaty i konfiguracje gier arcade.

Był używany w szeregu gier arcade, w tym takich, które obejmowały hazard, wymianę biletów i atrakcje dla dzieci. Sega System SP był produkowany do 2014 roku i wyróżnia się kompaktowym i wydajnym projektem.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>O Sega System SP, também conhecido como Aurora, é uma placa de sistema arcade desenvolvida pela Sega. É, essencialmente, um "Dreamcast-on-a-chip", com a mesma CPU SH-4 e GPU PowerVR2 da consola Sega Dreamcast. Este sistema foi concebido para ser versátil, suportando vários formatos e configurações de jogos arcade.

Foi utilizado numa série de jogos arcade, incluindo alguns que envolviam apostas, troca de bilhetes e atrações infantis. O Sega System SP foi fabricado até 2014 e é notável pelo seu design compacto e eficiente.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Sega System SP, cunoscut și sub numele Aurora, este o placă de sistem arcade dezvoltată de Sega. Este, în esență, un „Dreamcast-on-a-chip”, având același CPU SH-4 și GPU PowerVR2 ca și consola Sega Dreamcast. Acest sistem a fost proiectat pentru a fi versatil, suportând diverse formate și configurații de jocuri arcade.

A fost folosit într-o gamă de jocuri arcade, inclusiv unele care implicau jocuri de noroc, schimbul de bilete și atracții pentru copii. Sega System SP a fost produs până în 2014 și este remarcabil pentru designul său compact și eficient.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Sega System SP, также известная как Aurora, — это плата аркадной системы, разработанная компанией Sega. По сути это «Dreamcast-on-a-chip», оснащённая тем же процессором SH-4 и GPU PowerVR2, что и консоль Sega Dreamcast. Система была разработана как универсальная, поддерживающая различные форматы и конфигурации аркадных игр.

Она использовалась в ряде аркадных игр, включая те, что связаны с азартными играми, обменом билетов и детскими аттракционами. Sega System SP производилась до 2014 года и примечательна компактным и эффективным дизайном.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>Sega System SP, познат и као Aurora, је аркадна матична плоча коју је развила компанија Sega. У суштини је то „Dreamcast-on-a-chip“, са истим SH-4 CPU и PowerVR2 GPU као и конзола Sega Dreamcast. Овај систем је дизајниран да буде свестран и подржава разне формате и конфигурације аркадних игара.

Користио се у низу аркадних игара, укључујући неке које укључују коцкање, обраду тикета и дечје атракције. Sega System SP се производио до 2014. и познат је по свом компактном и ефикасном дизајну.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>Sega System SP, även känd som Aurora, är ett arkadsystemkort utvecklat av Sega. Det är i huvudsak en "Dreamcast-on-a-chip" med samma SH-4-CPU och PowerVR2-GPU som Sega Dreamcast-konsolen. Systemet var utformat för att vara mångsidigt och stödja olika arkadspelsformat och konfigurationer.

Det användes i en rad arkadspel, inklusive vissa som involverade spel om pengar, biljettinlösen och barnattraktioner. Sega System SP tillverkades fram till 2014 och är känt för sin kompakta och effektiva design.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>Sega System SP，也称为 Aurora，是 Sega 开发的一款街机系统主板。本质上它是“芯片上的 Dreamcast”，采用与 Sega Dreamcast 主机相同的 SH-4 CPU 和 PowerVR2 GPU。该系统被设计为通用平台，支持各种街机游戏格式和配置。

它被用于多种街机游戏，包括一些涉及赌博、兑换奖券和儿童游乐设施的游戏。Sega System SP 生产至 2014 年，以其紧凑高效的设计而著称。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
