<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Tyrian</systemName>
    <systemDescription>Tyrian is a vertically scrolling shooter developed by Eclipse Software for MS-DOS and published in 1995 by Epic MegaGames. Tyrian was programmed by Jason Emery, illustrated by Daniel Cook, and its music composed by Alexander Brandon and Andras Molnar.

The game was re-released as freeware in 2004. A free and open-source port of the game started in April 2007.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Epic MegaGames</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1995</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-port}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian هي لعبة إطلاق نار رأسية (vertically scrolling shooter) طورتها شركة Eclipse Software لنظام MS-DOS ونشرتها عام 1995 شركة Epic MegaGames. تمت برمجة Tyrian بواسطة Jason Emery، ورسومها من Daniel Cook، وموسيقاها من تأليف Alexander Brandon وAndras Molnar.

أعيد إصدار اللعبة كبرنامج مجاني في عام 2004. وبدأ مشروع منفذ حر ومفتوح المصدر للعبة في أبريل 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian je vertikalni shoot 'em up koji je razvio Eclipse Software za MS-DOS, a 1995. ga je objavila tvrtka Epic MegaGames. Tyrian je programirao Jason Emery, ilustrirao Daniel Cook, a glazbu su skladao Alexander Brandon i Andras Molnar.

Igra je ponovno izdana kao freeware 2004. godine. Besplatan i open-source port igre započeo je u travnju 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian és un shooter de desplaçament vertical desenvolupat per Eclipse Software per a MS-DOS i publicat el 1995 per Epic MegaGames. Tyrian va ser programat per Jason Emery, il·lustrat per Daniel Cook i amb música composta per Alexander Brandon i Andras Molnar.

El joc es va reeditat com a freeware el 2004. Un port gratuït i de codi obert del joc va començar el abril de 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian ist ein vertikal scrollender Shooter, entwickelt von Eclipse Software für MS-DOS und 1995 von Epic MegaGames veröffentlicht. Tyrian wurde von Jason Emery programmiert, von Daniel Cook illustriert und die Musik stammt von Alexander Brandon und Andras Molnar.

Das Spiel wurde 2004 als Freeware neu veröffentlicht. Ein freier und Open-Source-Port des Spiels begann im April 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian es un shooter de desplazamiento vertical desarrollado por Eclipse Software para MS-DOS y publicado en 1995 por Epic MegaGames. Tyrian fue programado por Jason Emery, ilustrado por Daniel Cook y su música compuesta por Alexander Brandon y Andras Molnar.

El juego fue relanzado como freeware en 2004. Un puerto gratuito y de código abierto del juego comenzó en abril de 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian est un shoot 'em up à défilement vertical développé par Eclipse Software pour MS-DOS et publié en 1995 par Epic MegaGames. Tyrian a été programmé par Jason Emery, illustré par Daniel Cook, et sa musique composée par Alexander Brandon et Andras Molnar.

Le jeu a été réédité en freeware en 2004. Un port libre et open-source du jeu a commencé en avril 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian je vertikalni pucač razvijen od strane Eclipse Software za MS-DOS, a 1995. ga je objavila tvrtka Epic MegaGames. Tyrian je programirao Jason Emery, ilustrirao Daniel Cook, a glazbu su skladao Alexander Brandon i Andras Molnar.

Igra je ponovno objavljena kao freeware 2004. godine. Besplatan i otvoreni port igre započeo je u travnju 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian è uno sparatutto a scorrimento verticale sviluppato da Eclipse Software per MS-DOS e pubblicato nel 1995 da Epic MegaGames. Tyrian è stato programmato da Jason Emery, illustrato da Daniel Cook e la sua musica è stata composta da Alexander Brandon e Andras Molnar.

Il gioco è stato ripubblicato come freeware nel 2004. Un port gratuito e open-source del gioco è iniziato nell'aprile 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian は Eclipse Software によって MS-DOS 向けに開発された縦スクロールシューティングで、1995 年に Epic MegaGames によって発売されました。Tyrian は Jason Emery によってプログラムされ、Daniel Cook によってイラストが描かれ、音楽は Alexander Brandon と Andras Molnar によって作曲されました。

このゲームは 2004 年にフリーウェアとして再発売されました。ゲームのフリーかつオープンソースの移植プロジェクトは 2007 年 4 月に始まりました。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian은 Eclipse Software가 MS-DOS용으로 개발한 수직 스크롤 슈터로, 1995년 Epic MegaGames에서 출시했습니다. Tyrian은 Jason Emery가 프로그래밍했고, Daniel Cook이 일러스트를 담당했으며, 음악은 Alexander Brandon과 Andras Molnar가 작곡했습니다.

이 게임은 2004년에 프리웨어로 재출시되었습니다. 게임의 무료 오픈소스 포트는 2007년 4월에 시작되었습니다。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian is een verticaal scrollende shooter ontwikkeld door Eclipse Software voor MS-DOS en uitgebracht in 1995 door Epic MegaGames. Tyrian werd geprogrammeerd door Jason Emery, geïllustreerd door Daniel Cook en de muziek gecomponeerd door Alexander Brandon en Andras Molnar.

Het spel werd in 2004 opnieuw uitgebracht als freeware. Een gratis en open-source port van het spel begon in april 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian to pionowy shooter opracowany przez Eclipse Software na MS-DOS i wydany w 1995 roku przez Epic MegaGames. Tyrian został zaprogramowany przez Jasona Emery'ego, zilustrowany przez Daniela Cooka, a muzykę skomponowali Alexander Brandon i Andras Molnar.

Gra została ponownie wydana jako freeware w 2004 roku. Wolny i otwarty port gry rozpoczął się w kwietniu 2007 roku.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian é um shooter de scroll vertical desenvolvido pela Eclipse Software para MS-DOS e publicado em 1995 pela Epic MegaGames. Tyrian foi programado por Jason Emery, ilustrado por Daniel Cook e a sua música composta por Alexander Brandon e Andras Molnar.

O jogo foi relançado como freeware em 2004. Um port gratuito e open-source do jogo começou em abril de 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian este un shooter cu derulare verticală dezvoltat de Eclipse Software pentru MS-DOS și publicat în 1995 de Epic MegaGames. Tyrian a fost programat de Jason Emery, ilustrat de Daniel Cook, iar muzica a fost compusă de Alexander Brandon și Andras Molnar.

Jocul a fost relansat ca freeware în 2004. Un port gratuit și open-source al jocului a început în aprilie 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian — вертикальный скролл-шутер, разработанный Eclipse Software для MS-DOS и изданный в 1995 году компанией Epic MegaGames. Tyrian был запрограммирован Джейсоном Эмери, иллюстрации сделал Дэниел Кук, а музыку написали Александр Брэндон и Андраш Молнар.

Игра была переиздана как условно бесплатная (freeware) в 2004 году. Бесплатная и открытая портированная версия игры появилась в апреле 2007 года.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian је вертикални шутер развијен од стране Eclipse Software за MS-DOS, а објављен 1995. године од стране Epic MegaGames. Tyrian је програмирао Jason Emery, илустровао Daniel Cook, а музику су компоновали Alexander Brandon и Andras Molnar.

Игра је поново објављена као freeware 2004. године. Бесплатан и отворени порт игре започео је у априлу 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian är en vertikalt scrollande shooter utvecklad av Eclipse Software för MS-DOS och utgiven 1995 av Epic MegaGames. Tyrian programmerades av Jason Emery, illustrerades av Daniel Cook och musiken komponerades av Alexander Brandon och Andras Molnar.

Spelet återutgavs som freeware 2004. En gratis och öppen källkodsport av spelet påbörjades i april 2007.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>Tyrian 是一款纵向卷轴射击游戏，由 Eclipse Software 为 MS-DOS 开发，1995 年由 Epic MegaGames 发布。Tyrian 由 Jason Emery 编程，Daniel Cook 绘制插图，音乐由 Alexander Brandon 和 Andras Molnar 作曲。

该游戏在 2004 年作为免费软件重新发布。一个免费的开源移植项目于 2007 年 4 月启动。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
