<theme>
  <variables>
    <systemName>Video Information System</systemName>
    <systemDescription>The Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) is an interactive, multimedia CD-ROM player produced by the Tandy Corporation starting in 1992. It is similar in function to the Philips CD-i and Commodore CDTV systems (particularly the CDTV, since both the VIS and CDTV were adaptations of existing computer platforms and operating systems to the set-top-box design).

The VIS systems were sold only at Radio Shack, under the Memorex brand, both of which Tandy owned at the time.</systemDescription>
    <systemManufacturer>Tandy/Memorex</systemManufacturer>
    <systemReleaseYear>1992</systemReleaseYear>
    <systemHardwareType>${i18n.hardware-console}</systemHardwareType>
    <systemCoverSize>1-1</systemCoverSize>
    <systemCartSize>1-1</systemCartSize>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ar">
    <systemDescription>نظام Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) هو مشغل CD-ROM تفاعلي متعدد الوسائط أنتجته شركة Tandy بدءًا من عام 1992. يشبه في الوظيفة أنظمة Philips CD-i و Commodore CDTV (لا سيما CDTV، حيث كان كل من VIS وCDTV تكيفًا لمنصات حاسوبية قائمة ونظم تشغيل لتصميم أجهزة الاستقبال التلفزيوني).

بيعت أنظمة VIS حصريًا في متاجر Radio Shack تحت العلامة التجارية Memorex، والتي كانت Tandy تملكها في ذلك الوقت.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="bs">
    <systemDescription>Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) je interaktivni multimedijalni CD-ROM player kojeg je proizvodila tvrtka Tandy počevši od 1992. Sličan je po funkciji Philips CD-i i Commodore CDTV sustavima (posebice CDTV, budući da su i VIS i CDTV bili prilagodbe postojećih računalnih platformi i operativnih sustava za set-top-box dizajn).

VIS sustavi su se prodavali samo u Radio Shack trgovinama pod Memorex markom, koju je Tandy u to vrijeme posjedovao.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ca">
    <systemDescription>El Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) és un reproductor de CD-ROM interactiu i multimèdia produït per la companyia Tandy a partir de 1992. Té una funcionalitat similar als sistemes Philips CD-i i Commodore CDTV (particularment el CDTV, ja que tant el VIS com el CDTV eren adaptacions de plataformes informàtiques i sistemes operatius existents al disseny de set-top-box).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="de">
    <systemDescription>Das Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) ist ein interaktiver Multimedia-CD-ROM-Player, der ab 1992 von der Tandy Corporation produziert wurde. Es ist in seiner Funktion dem Philips CD-i und dem Commodore CDTV ähnlich (insbesondere dem CDTV, da sowohl VIS als auch CDTV Anpassungen bestehender Computerplattformen und Betriebssysteme zum Set-Top-Box-Design waren).

Die VIS-Systeme wurden ausschließlich bei Radio Shack unter der Marke Memorex verkauft, die zu der Zeit im Besitz von Tandy war.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="es">
    <systemDescription>El Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) es un reproductor de CD-ROM interactivo y multimedia producido por la compañía Tandy a partir de 1992. Es similar en función a los sistemas Philips CD-i y Commodore CDTV (en particular al CDTV, ya que tanto el VIS como el CDTV eran adaptaciones de plataformas informáticas y sistemas operativos existentes al diseño de set-top-box).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="fr">
    <systemDescription>Le Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) est un lecteur CD-ROM multimédia interactif produit par la société Tandy à partir de 1992. Il est similaire dans sa fonction aux systèmes Philips CD-i et Commodore CDTV (en particulier au CDTV, puisque le VIS et le CDTV étaient des adaptations de plateformes informatiques et de systèmes d'exploitation existants au design de set-top box).

Les systèmes VIS étaient vendus uniquement chez Radio Shack, sous la marque Memorex, que Tandy possédait à l'époque.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="hr">
    <systemDescription>Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) je interaktivni multimedijalni CD-ROM player koji je proizvodila tvrtka Tandy od 1992. godine. Slično je po funkciji sustavima Philips CD-i i Commodore CDTV (posebno CDTV, jer su i VIS i CDTV bile prilagodbe postojećih računalnih platformi i operativnih sustava za set-top-box dizajn).

VIS sustavi su se prodavali isključivo u Radio Shack trgovinama pod Memorex markom, koju je Tandy tada posjedovao.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="it">
    <systemDescription>Il Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) è un lettore CD-ROM multimediale interattivo prodotto dalla Tandy Corporation a partire dal 1992. È simile nella funzione ai sistemi Philips CD-i e Commodore CDTV (in particolare al CDTV, poiché sia il VIS che il CDTV erano adattamenti di piattaforme e sistemi operativi informatici esistenti al design set-top-box).

I sistemi VIS venivano venduti esclusivamente da Radio Shack, con il marchio Memorex, di proprietà di Tandy all'epoca.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ja">
    <systemDescription>Tandy Memorex Video Information System（VIS）は、1992年からTandy Corporationが製造したインタラクティブなマルチメディアCD-ROMプレーヤーです。機能的には Philips CD-i や Commodore CDTV に類似しており（特に CDTV、VIS と CDTV は既存のコンピュータプラットフォームと OS をセットトップボックス設計に適合させたものであるため）、類似点が多くあります。

VIS システムは、当時 Tandy が所有していた Memorex ブランドで Radio Shack のみで販売されていました。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ko">
    <systemDescription>Tandy Memorex Video Information System(VIS)는 1992년부터 Tandy Corporation이 제작한 상호작용형 멀티미디어 CD-ROM 플레이어입니다. 기능적으로 Philips CD-i 및 Commodore CDTV와 유사합니다(특히 VIS와 CDTV는 기존 컴퓨터 플랫폼 및 운영체제를 셋톱박스 설계로 전환한 사례입니다).

VIS 시스템은 당시 Tandy가 소유하던 Memorex 브랜드로 Radio Shack에서만 판매되었습니다。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="nl">
    <systemDescription>Het Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) is een interactieve multimedia CD-ROM speler geproduceerd door de Tandy Corporation vanaf 1992. Het is vergelijkbaar in functie met de Philips CD-i en Commodore CDTV systemen (in het bijzonder de CDTV, aangezien zowel VIS als CDTV aanpassingen waren van bestaande computerplatforms en besturingssystemen voor set-top-boxontwerpen).

De VIS-systemen werden uitsluitend verkocht bij Radio Shack onder het merk Memorex, dat destijds eigendom was van Tandy.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pl">
    <systemDescription>Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) to interaktywny odtwarzacz CD-ROM typu multimedia produkowany przez Tandy Corporation od 1992 roku. Jest podobny funkcjonalnie do systemów Philips CD-i i Commodore CDTV (szczególnie do CDTV, ponieważ zarówno VIS, jak i CDTV były adaptacjami istniejących platform komputerowych i systemów operacyjnych do projektu set-top-box).

Systemy VIS sprzedawane były wyłącznie w sklepach Radio Shack pod marką Memorex, której właścicielem była wówczas firma Tandy.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="pt">
    <systemDescription>O Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) é um leitor de CD-ROM multimédia interativo produzido pela Tandy Corporation a partir de 1992. É semelhante nas suas funcionalidades aos sistemas Philips CD-i e Commodore CDTV (particularmente o CDTV, uma vez que tanto o VIS como o CDTV eram adaptações de plataformas e sistemas operativos informáticos existentes para o design de set-top-box).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ro">
    <systemDescription>Sistemul Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) este un player CD-ROM multimedia interactiv produs de Tandy Corporation începând cu 1992. Este similar ca funcționalitate cu sistemele Philips CD-i și Commodore CDTV (în special CDTV, deoarece atât VIS, cât și CDTV erau adaptări ale platformelor și sistemelor de operare existente pentru designul set-top-box).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="ru">
    <systemDescription>Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) — интерактивный мультимедийный CD-ROM-плеер, выпускавшийся корпорацией Tandy с 1992 года. По функционалу он схож с системами Philips CD-i и Commodore CDTV (особенно с CDTV, поскольку и VIS, и CDTV были адаптациями существующих компьютерных платформ и ОС для конструкции set-top-box).

Системы VIS продавались исключительно в магазинах Radio Shack под брендом Memorex, который тогда принадлежал Tandy.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sr">
    <systemDescription>Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) је интерактивни мултимедијални CD-ROM плејер који је производила компанија Tandy почевши од 1992. године. Функционално је сличан системима Philips CD-i и Commodore CDTV (посебно CDTV, јер су и VIS и CDTV биле прилагођавања постојећих рачунарских платформи и оперативних система за дизајн set-top box-а).

VIS системи су се продавали искључиво у продавницама Radio Shack под брендом Memorex, који је у то време био у власништву компаније Tandy.</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="sv">
    <systemDescription>Tandy Memorex Video Information System (VIS) är en interaktiv multimediaplayer för CD-ROM som tillverkades av Tandy Corporation från 1992. Den liknar funktionellt systemen Philips CD-i och Commodore CDTV (särskilt CDTV, eftersom både VIS och CDTV var anpassningar av befintliga datorplattformar och operativsystem till set-top-box-design).</systemDescription>
  </variables>
  <variables lang="zh">
    <systemDescription>Tandy Memorex Video Information System（VIS）是由 Tandy Corporation 从 1992 年起生产的一款交互式多媒体 CD-ROM 播放器。其功能类似于 Philips CD-i 和 Commodore CDTV（尤其是 CDTV，因为 VIS 与 CDTV 都是将现有计算机平台和操作系统改造为机顶盒设计的产物）。

VIS 系统仅在 Radio Shack 销售，以 Memorex 品牌发售，当时该品牌归 Tandy 所有。</systemDescription>
  </variables>
</theme>
